{"question_ID":1,"question":"Which of the following are present in Nymphaea nouchali var. caerulea: apomorphine, aporphine, or neither?","context1":"Apomorphine is said to be main psychoactive compound present.","context2":"Like other species in the genus, Nymphaea nouchali var. caerulea contains the psychoactive alkaloid aporphine (not to be confused with apomorphine, a metabolic product of aporphine).","answer1":"Apomorphine","answer2":"Aporphine","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Apomorphine is said to be main psychoactive compound present.\nLike other species in the genus, Nymphaea nouchali var. caerulea contains the psychoactive alkaloid aporphine (not to be confused with apomorphine, a metabolic product of aporphine).","ref_answer":"Apomorphine|Aporphine","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Nymphaea nouchali var. caerulea","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Nymphaea_nouchali_var._caerulea"}
{"question_ID":2,"question":"Are there any other missiles besides the P-500 Bazalt that influenced the design of P-700 Granit missile?","context1":"The P-700 was derived from the P-500 Bazalt missile with a turbojet.","context2":"The missile was partially derived from the P-500 Bazalt.","answer1":"No.","answer2":"Yes.","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"The P-700 was derived from the P-500 Bazalt missile with a turbojet.\nThe missile was partially derived from the P-500 Bazalt.","ref_answer":"No.|Yes.","WikipediaArticleTitle":"P-700 Granit","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/P-700_Granit"}
{"question_ID":3,"question":"Did the formation of the grooves on Phobos occur as a single event?","context1":"The model designed in 2015 supported the discovery that some of the grooves are younger than others, implying that the process that produces the grooves is ongoing.","context2":"In November 2018, following further computational probability analysis, astronomers concluded that the many grooves on Phobos were caused by boulders, ejected from the asteroid impact that created Stickney crater. These boulders rolled in a predictable pattern on the surface of the moon.","answer1":"No.","answer2":"Yes.","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"The model designed in 2015 supported the discovery that some of the grooves are younger than others, implying that the process that produces the grooves is ongoing.\nIn November 2018, following further computational probability analysis, astronomers concluded that the many grooves on Phobos were caused by boulders, ejected from the asteroid impact that created Stickney crater. These boulders rolled in a predictable pattern on the surface of the moon.","ref_answer":"No.|Yes.","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Phobos (moon)","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Phobos_(moon)"}
{"question_ID":4,"question":"Did Bishop Heber meet D\u2019Oyly in the 1840s in Patna ?","context1":"Bishop Heber, who visited Patna in the 1840s, described Charles D'Oyly as the \u201cbest gentleman artist I ever met\u201d.","context2":"After working for the Company for forty years, Charles D'Oyly's failing health compelled him to retire and leave India in 1838","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Bishop Heber, who visited Patna in the 1840s, described Charles D'Oyly as the \u201cbest gentleman artist I ever met\u201d.\nAfter working for the Company for forty years, Charles D'Oyly's failing health compelled him to retire and leave India in 1838","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Charles D'Oyly","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Charles_D'Oyly"}
{"question_ID":5,"question":"What year did President Oler take the stand in court?","context1":"President Wesley M. Oler took the stand for the company in 1911 when detectives traveled to Rockland Lake to find the icehouses packed with ice but no workers to load the product onto barges to New York City. The lack of workers had to do with the two dollars they were getting paid when small, independent companies were paying double what bigger companies like Knickerbocker were paying their employees. Oler took to the stand to tell the court he was paying his workers properly and was even paying them extra for the work they did on Sundays, but the workers rebelled. When detectives dug deeper into the situation, they discovered Oler secretly made deals with other companies to purchase ice when they were suffering from deficiencies. Oler came up with numerous excuses why he was conducting the Knickerbocker Ice Company\u2019s business in such a way. Oler explained it was cheaper to transport ice in smaller quantities to meet the demands of clients than to purchase more rail cars and transport everything at once. Also, the 1890s was an exceptionally warm winter which was a major setback for the ice industry since there was not much ice to sell to consumers. Oler told the court he searched for skilled workers to harvest ice during the warm season but was unsuccessful, which is the why these complications occurred while he was president of the company.","context2":"President Wesley M. Oler took the stand for the company in 1911 when detectives traveled to Rockland Lake to find the icehouses packed with ice but no workers to load the product onto barges to New York City. The lack of workers had to do with the two dollars they were getting paid when small, independent companies were paying double what bigger companies like Knickerbocker were paying their employees. Oler took to the stand to tell the court he was paying his workers properly and was even paying them extra for the work they did on Sundays, but the workers rebelled. When detectives dug deeper into the situation, they discovered Oler secretly made deals with other companies to purchase ice when they were suffering from deficiencies. Oler came up with numerous excuses why he was conducting the Knickerbocker Ice Company\u2019s business in such a way. Oler explained it was cheaper to transport ice in smaller quantities to meet the demands of clients than to purchase more rail cars and transport everything at once. Also, the 1890s was an exceptionally warm winter which was a major setback for the ice industry since there was not much ice to sell to consumers. Oler told the court he searched for skilled workers to harvest ice during the warm season but was unsuccessful, which is the why these complications occurred while he was president of the company.","answer1":"President Oler took the stand in 1911","answer2":"President Oler appeard in court in the 1890s","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"President Wesley M. Oler took the stand for the company in 1911 when detectives traveled to Rockland Lake to find the icehouses packed with ice but no workers to load the product onto barges to New York City. The lack of workers had to do with the two dollars they were getting paid when small, independent companies were paying double what bigger companies like Knickerbocker were paying their employees. Oler took to the stand to tell the court he was paying his workers properly and was even paying them extra for the work they did on Sundays, but the workers rebelled. When detectives dug deeper into the situation, they discovered Oler secretly made deals with other companies to purchase ice when they were suffering from deficiencies. Oler came up with numerous excuses why he was conducting the Knickerbocker Ice Company\u2019s business in such a way. Oler explained it was cheaper to transport ice in smaller quantities to meet the demands of clients than to purchase more rail cars and transport everything at once. Also, the 1890s was an exceptionally warm winter which was a major setback for the ice industry since there was not much ice to sell to consumers. Oler told the court he searched for skilled workers to harvest ice during the warm season but was unsuccessful, which is the why these complications occurred while he was president of the company.","ref_answer":"President Oler took the stand in 1911|President Oler appeard in court in the 1890s","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Knickerbocker Ice Company","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Knickerbocker_Ice_Company"}
{"question_ID":6,"question":"What is the most common occupation for the residents of Kodimunai?","context1":"A significant number of the residents of Kodimunai do jobs related to fishing. These jobs includes deep sea fishing, shallow water fishing, fishing from the shore (known as karamadi in the local language), fishing with mechanized boats, exporting fish, etc.","context2":"Many of the residents of Kodimunai work in a number of other fields like IT, medicine, education, engineering, trading, cargo shipping, etc. However, there is no noticeable local industry except for fishing","answer1":"Fishing","answer2":"IT, medicine, engineering, trading","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"A significant number of the residents of Kodimunai do jobs related to fishing. These jobs includes deep sea fishing, shallow water fishing, fishing from the shore (known as karamadi in the local language), fishing with mechanized boats, exporting fish, etc.\nMany of the residents of Kodimunai work in a number of other fields like IT, medicine, education, engineering, trading, cargo shipping, etc. However, there is no noticeable local industry except for fishing","ref_answer":"Fishing|IT, medicine, engineering, trading","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Kodimunai","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Kodimunai"}
{"question_ID":7,"question":"What is the salinity of Lake Maracaibo?","context1":"Lake Maracaibo is deep in the south and shallow in the north. The northern half of Lake Maracaibo, which looks like a bottleneck, is 55 kilometers long. The southeastern edge of Lake Maracaibo basin with a flat bottom is steep and the northwestern edge is gentle. Lake Maracaibo is slightly salty due to the influence of tides, and the overall salinity of Lake Maracaibo is between 1.5 and 3.8%.","context2":"The Catatumbo River forms a bird-foot-shaped delta in the southwest of Lake Maracaibo basin, and the surface lake water in the delta has a salinity of only 0.13%. However, the intrusion of seawater from the mouth of Lake Maracaibo makes the salinity of the bottom lake water higher, reaching 0.2-0.3%.","answer1":"The salinity of Lake Maracaibo is between 1.5% and 3.8%","answer2":"The salinity of Lake Maracibo is between 0.2% and 0.3%","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Lake Maracaibo is deep in the south and shallow in the north. The northern half of Lake Maracaibo, which looks like a bottleneck, is 55 kilometers long. The southeastern edge of Lake Maracaibo basin with a flat bottom is steep and the northwestern edge is gentle. Lake Maracaibo is slightly salty due to the influence of tides, and the overall salinity of Lake Maracaibo is between 1.5 and 3.8%.\nThe Catatumbo River forms a bird-foot-shaped delta in the southwest of Lake Maracaibo basin, and the surface lake water in the delta has a salinity of only 0.13%. However, the intrusion of seawater from the mouth of Lake Maracaibo makes the salinity of the bottom lake water higher, reaching 0.2-0.3%.","ref_answer":"The salinity of Lake Maracaibo is between 1.5% and 3.8%|The salinity of Lake Maracibo is between 0.2% and 0.3%","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Lake Maracaibo","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Lake_Maracaibo"}
{"question_ID":8,"question":"What are examples of defunct newspapers in the United States?","context1":"This is a list of defunct newspapers of the United States. Only notable names among the thousands of such newspapers are listed, primarily major metropolitan dailies which published for ten years or more.","context2":"The Hoover Gazette was a weekly newspaper that served the city of Hoover, Alabama. The Hoover Gazette was owned by Eagle Publishing Company LLC. The Hoover Gazette was first published on June 5, 2006. The last edition of Hoover Gazette was on August 15, 2007. The newspaper Hoover Gazette was published each Wednesday.","answer1":"The Daily Worker","answer2":"The Hoover Gazette","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"This is a list of defunct newspapers of the United States. Only notable names among the thousands of such newspapers are listed, primarily major metropolitan dailies which published for ten years or more.\nThe Hoover Gazette was a weekly newspaper that served the city of Hoover, Alabama. The Hoover Gazette was owned by Eagle Publishing Company LLC. The Hoover Gazette was first published on June 5, 2006. The last edition of Hoover Gazette was on August 15, 2007. The newspaper Hoover Gazette was published each Wednesday.","ref_answer":"The Daily Worker|The Hoover Gazette","WikipediaArticleTitle":"List of defunct newspapers of the United States","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/List_of_defunct_newspapers_of_the_United_States"}
{"question_ID":9,"question":"When was Little America II base established?","context1":"Little America II was established in 1934, some thirty feet (ten meters) above the site of the original base Little America I, with some of the original base accessed via tunnel. The Little America II base was briefly set adrift in 1934, but the iceberg fused to the main glacier.","context2":"In a later expedition to Antarctica, Byrd's expedition spotted Little America's towers still standing, including the Jacobs Wind plant installed in 1933.","answer1":"1934","answer2":"1933","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Little America II was established in 1934, some thirty feet (ten meters) above the site of the original base Little America I, with some of the original base accessed via tunnel. The Little America II base was briefly set adrift in 1934, but the iceberg fused to the main glacier.\nIn a later expedition to Antarctica, Byrd's expedition spotted Little America's towers still standing, including the Jacobs Wind plant installed in 1933.","ref_answer":"1934|1933","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Little America (exploration base)","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Little_America_(exploration_base)"}
{"question_ID":10,"question":"Is Moxonidine selective or non-selective Agonist?","context1":"I1 receptors include Agonists such as AGN 192403, and Moxonidine","context2":"Nonselective ligands include Agonists such as Agmatine (putative endogenous ligand at I1; also interacts with NMDA, nicotinic, and \u03b12 adrenoceptors), Apraclonidine (\u03b12 adrenoceptor agonist), 2-BFI (I2 agonist, NMDA antagonist), Cimetidine (I1 agonist, H2 receptor antagonist), Clonidine (I1 agonist, \u03b12 adrenoceptor agonist), LNP-509, LNP-911, 7-Me-marsanidine, Dimethyltryptamine, mCPP, and Moxonidine","answer1":"selective","answer2":"non-selective","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"I1 receptors include Agonists such as AGN 192403, and Moxonidine\nNonselective ligands include Agonists such as Agmatine (putative endogenous ligand at I1; also interacts with NMDA, nicotinic, and \u03b12 adrenoceptors), Apraclonidine (\u03b12 adrenoceptor agonist), 2-BFI (I2 agonist, NMDA antagonist), Cimetidine (I1 agonist, H2 receptor antagonist), Clonidine (I1 agonist, \u03b12 adrenoceptor agonist), LNP-509, LNP-911, 7-Me-marsanidine, Dimethyltryptamine, mCPP, and Moxonidine","ref_answer":"selective|non-selective","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Imidazoline receptor","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Imidazoline_receptor"}
{"question_ID":11,"question":"What year did Paul Fraisse become a director of the Institute of Psychology of the University of Paris?","context1":"In 1965, Paul Fraisse becomes the Institute of Psychology of the University of Paris director","context2":"1952 : Paul Fraisse replaces Henri Pi\u00e9ron with a director board of the Institute of Psychology of the University of Paris including Daniel Lagache (Sorbonne, lettres), Jean Delay (Facult\u00e9 de m\u00e9decine), and Pierre-Paul Grass\u00e9 (Sorbonne, Sciences). 1960 : Daniel Lagache steps back from co-directorship. 1961 : Paul Fraisse becomes the only director of the Institute of Psychology of the University of Paris.","answer1":"1965","answer2":"1952","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"In 1965, Paul Fraisse becomes the Institute of Psychology of the University of Paris director\n1952 : Paul Fraisse replaces Henri Pi\u00e9ron with a director board of the Institute of Psychology of the University of Paris including Daniel Lagache (Sorbonne, lettres), Jean Delay (Facult\u00e9 de m\u00e9decine), and Pierre-Paul Grass\u00e9 (Sorbonne, Sciences). 1960 : Daniel Lagache steps back from co-directorship. 1961 : Paul Fraisse becomes the only director of the Institute of Psychology of the University of Paris.","ref_answer":"1965|1952","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Institute of Psychology of the University of Paris","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Institute_of_Psychology_of_the_University_of_Paris"}
{"question_ID":12,"question":"What date was Julian Lewis Jones born?","context1":"Julian Lewis Jones (born 21 August 1968","context2":"Julian Lewis Jones Born\t27 August 1968","answer1":"August 21st 1968","answer2":" 27 August 1968","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Julian Lewis Jones (born 21 August 1968\nJulian Lewis Jones Born\t27 August 1968","ref_answer":"August 21st 1968| 27 August 1968","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Julian Lewis Jones","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Julian_Lewis_Jones"}
{"question_ID":13,"question":"When did Liu Zhi die?","context1":"Liu Zhi first fled to British Hong Kong, and later on made a living in Indonesia as a Chinese language teacher. In 1953, he was ordered to return to Kuomingtang-controlled Taiwan as a political adviser to Chiang Kai-shek. He was decorated with the Order of Blue Sky and White Sun. He died in Taiwan in 1972.","context2":"Liu Zhi died on the 15 January 1971 (aged 78) in Taichung, Taiwan","answer1":"Liu Zhi died in 1972.","answer2":"Liu Zhi died on the 15 January 1971.","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Liu Zhi first fled to British Hong Kong, and later on made a living in Indonesia as a Chinese language teacher. In 1953, he was ordered to return to Kuomingtang-controlled Taiwan as a political adviser to Chiang Kai-shek. He was decorated with the Order of Blue Sky and White Sun. He died in Taiwan in 1972.\nLiu Zhi died on the 15 January 1971 (aged 78) in Taichung, Taiwan","ref_answer":"Liu Zhi died in 1972.|Liu Zhi died on the 15 January 1971.","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Liu Zhi (ROC)","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Liu_Zhi_(ROC)"}
{"question_ID":14,"question":"How is the Loretto Chapel staircase held together?","context1":"The Loretto Chapel staircase lacks the newel or central pole usually used to support and stabilize a spiral staircase, and therefore the means of supporting the weight is not obvious. However, the staircase is supported by its stringers just like a conventional (straight) staircase, although in this case each stringer is twisted into a helix. Observers have also noted that the inside stringer has such a tight radius that it is able to function similarly to a straight center support. According to an analysis by a professional carpenter in Mysterious New Mexico, the assembly of the stringers from overlapping segments joined by wood glue  creates a laminate that is actually stronger than the wood alone. Additionally, the use of wooden pegs rather than nails prevents degradation of the joints due to compression set as the wood swells against the nails due to changes in humidity or temperature","context2":"Loretto Chapel is best known for its helix-shaped staircase (nicknamed \"Miraculous Stair\"), which rises 20 feet (6.1 m) to the choir loft while making two full turns, all without the support of a newel or central pole. The staircase is built mostly out of wood and is held together by wooden pegs, with no glue, nails or other hardware used. The inner stringer consists of seven wooden segments joined together with pegs, while the longer outer stringer has nine segments. The exact wood used to build the staircase has been confirmed to be a type of spruce which is not native to New Mexico and scientifically not identified anywhere else in the world.","answer1":"It is held together by overlapping segments joined by wood glue.","answer2":"It is held together by wooden pegs, with no glue.","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"The Loretto Chapel staircase lacks the newel or central pole usually used to support and stabilize a spiral staircase, and therefore the means of supporting the weight is not obvious. However, the staircase is supported by its stringers just like a conventional (straight) staircase, although in this case each stringer is twisted into a helix. Observers have also noted that the inside stringer has such a tight radius that it is able to function similarly to a straight center support. According to an analysis by a professional carpenter in Mysterious New Mexico, the assembly of the stringers from overlapping segments joined by wood glue  creates a laminate that is actually stronger than the wood alone. Additionally, the use of wooden pegs rather than nails prevents degradation of the joints due to compression set as the wood swells against the nails due to changes in humidity or temperature\nLoretto Chapel is best known for its helix-shaped staircase (nicknamed \"Miraculous Stair\"), which rises 20 feet (6.1 m) to the choir loft while making two full turns, all without the support of a newel or central pole. The staircase is built mostly out of wood and is held together by wooden pegs, with no glue, nails or other hardware used. The inner stringer consists of seven wooden segments joined together with pegs, while the longer outer stringer has nine segments. The exact wood used to build the staircase has been confirmed to be a type of spruce which is not native to New Mexico and scientifically not identified anywhere else in the world.","ref_answer":"It is held together by overlapping segments joined by wood glue.|It is held together by wooden pegs, with no glue.","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Loretto Chapel","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Loretto_Chapel"}
{"question_ID":15,"question":"How many people were survivors of the P\u00e1nfilo de Narv\u00e1ez expedition?","context1":"In the spring of 1528, during the P\u00e1nfilo de Narv\u00e1ez's 1527 expedition, thirteen of the fifteen survivors decided to leave the Galveston island, abandoning Cabeza de Vaca (because he was sick and unable to travel) and two other members of the expedition. In April 1529, this group, led by Dorantes and Castillo, reached the coast and landed at Matagorda Bay. However, most of the members of this expedition were killed by Native Americans. Only three survived: Dorantes de Carranza, Castillo and Estevanico.","context2":"Alonso del Castillo Maldonado (died after 1547) was an early Spanish explorer in the Americas. He was one of the last four survivors of the P\u00e1nfilo de Narv\u00e1ez expedition, along with \u00c1lvar N\u00fa\u00f1ez Cabeza de Vaca, Andr\u00e9s Dorantes de Carranza and his African slave Estevanico. ","answer1":"Three survived.","answer2":"Four survived.","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"In the spring of 1528, during the P\u00e1nfilo de Narv\u00e1ez's 1527 expedition, thirteen of the fifteen survivors decided to leave the Galveston island, abandoning Cabeza de Vaca (because he was sick and unable to travel) and two other members of the expedition. In April 1529, this group, led by Dorantes and Castillo, reached the coast and landed at Matagorda Bay. However, most of the members of this expedition were killed by Native Americans. Only three survived: Dorantes de Carranza, Castillo and Estevanico.\nAlonso del Castillo Maldonado (died after 1547) was an early Spanish explorer in the Americas. He was one of the last four survivors of the P\u00e1nfilo de Narv\u00e1ez expedition, along with \u00c1lvar N\u00fa\u00f1ez Cabeza de Vaca, Andr\u00e9s Dorantes de Carranza and his African slave Estevanico. ","ref_answer":"Three survived.|Four survived.","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Alonso del Castillo Maldonado","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Alonso_del_Castillo_Maldonado"}
{"question_ID":16,"question":"How tall is Tyler Mane?","context1":"In 2007, Tayler Mane played Michael Myers in Rob Zombie's remake of Halloween. After winning the role, he noted that he consecutively watched seven of the eight Halloween films (excluding the third because Michael Myers does not appear apart from in an ad for the first movie) to better understand his character. He is the tallest actor (6' 8\") to portray the character","context2":"Tayler Mane height is 6 ft 9 in (2.06 m).","answer1":"6 ft 8 in","answer2":"6 ft 9 in","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"In 2007, Tayler Mane played Michael Myers in Rob Zombie's remake of Halloween. After winning the role, he noted that he consecutively watched seven of the eight Halloween films (excluding the third because Michael Myers does not appear apart from in an ad for the first movie) to better understand his character. He is the tallest actor (6' 8\") to portray the character\nTayler Mane height is 6 ft 9 in (2.06 m).","ref_answer":"6 ft 8 in|6 ft 9 in","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Tyler Mane","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Tyler_Mane"}
{"question_ID":17,"question":"What is Heinrich Mark birth name?","context1":"Heinrich Marx (born Herschel HaLevi, Yiddish: \u05d4\u05d9\u05e8\u05e9\u05dc \u05d4\u05dc\u05d5\u05d9; 15 April 1777 \u2013 10 May 1838) was a German lawyer who fathered the communist philosopher Karl Marx, as well as seven other children, including Louise Juta.","context2":"Heinrich Marx was born in Saarlouis into an Ashkenazi Jewish family with the name Herschel Levi, the son of Rabbi Marx Levi Mordechai ben Samuel HaLevi von R\u00f6delheim (1743\u20131804) and Eva Lwow (1753\u20131823)","answer1":"Herschel HaLevi","answer2":"Herschel Levi","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Heinrich Marx (born Herschel HaLevi, Yiddish: \u05d4\u05d9\u05e8\u05e9\u05dc \u05d4\u05dc\u05d5\u05d9; 15 April 1777 \u2013 10 May 1838) was a German lawyer who fathered the communist philosopher Karl Marx, as well as seven other children, including Louise Juta.\nHeinrich Marx was born in Saarlouis into an Ashkenazi Jewish family with the name Herschel Levi, the son of Rabbi Marx Levi Mordechai ben Samuel HaLevi von R\u00f6delheim (1743\u20131804) and Eva Lwow (1753\u20131823)","ref_answer":"Herschel HaLevi|Herschel Levi","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Heinrich Marx","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Heinrich_Marx"}
{"question_ID":18,"question":"Is sleep is essential for all complex animals?","context1":"Sleep in fish is the subject of ongoing scientific research.Typically fish exhibit periods of inactivity but show no significant reactions to deprivation of this condition.","context2":"If sleep were not essential in animals, one would expect to find  - Animal species that do not sleep at all - Animals that do not need recovery sleep after staying awake longer than usual - Animals that suffer no serious consequences as a result of lack of sleep. Hence sleep is essential for all complex animals.","answer1":"Not for all types of complex animals, typically fish exhibit periods of inactivity but show no significant reactions to deprivation of this condition.","answer2":"Yes as if sleep were not essential in animals, one would expect to find  - Animal species that do not sleep at all - Animals that do not need recovery sleep after staying awake longer than usual - Animals that suffer no serious consequences as a result of lack of sleep. Hence sleep is essential for all complex animals.","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Sleep in fish is the subject of ongoing scientific research.Typically fish exhibit periods of inactivity but show no significant reactions to deprivation of this condition.\nIf sleep were not essential in animals, one would expect to find  - Animal species that do not sleep at all - Animals that do not need recovery sleep after staying awake longer than usual - Animals that suffer no serious consequences as a result of lack of sleep. Hence sleep is essential for all complex animals.","ref_answer":"Not for all types of complex animals, typically fish exhibit periods of inactivity but show no significant reactions to deprivation of this condition.|Yes as if sleep were not essential in animals, one would expect to find  - Animal species that do not sleep at all - Animals that do not need recovery sleep after staying awake longer than usual - Animals that suffer no serious consequences as a result of lack of sleep. Hence sleep is essential for all complex animals.","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Sleep in animals","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Sleep_in_animals"}
{"question_ID":19,"question":"Who was the manager of St Eunan's GAA in 2017?","context1":"The manager of St Eunan's GAA in the period c2014-c.2018 was Maxi Curran.","context2":"The managers of St Eunan's GAA in 2017 were Barry Meehan and Eddie Brennan.","answer1":"The manager of St Eunan's GAA in 2017 was Maxi Curran.","answer2":"The managers of St Eunan's GAA in 2017 were Barry Meehan and Eddie Brennan.","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"The manager of St Eunan's GAA in the period c2014-c.2018 was Maxi Curran.\nThe managers of St Eunan's GAA in 2017 were Barry Meehan and Eddie Brennan.","ref_answer":"The manager of St Eunan's GAA in 2017 was Maxi Curran.|The managers of St Eunan's GAA in 2017 were Barry Meehan and Eddie Brennan.","WikipediaArticleTitle":"St Eunan's GAA","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/St_Eunan's_GAA"}
{"question_ID":20,"question":"Was Maria Stevens executed for witchcraft?","context1":"Maria Stevens (died after 1707) was an English woman who was executed for witchcraft.","context2":"Maria Stevens was accused of having bewitched an acquaintance, Dorothy Reeves. The trial was held at Taunton Castle. Stevens was acquitted and released after judge and jury failed to believe the evidence given against her.","answer1":"Maria Stevens was an English woman who was executed for witchcraft.","answer2":"Maria Stevens was acquitted and released after judge and jury failed to believe the evidence given against her.","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Maria Stevens (died after 1707) was an English woman who was executed for witchcraft.\nMaria Stevens was accused of having bewitched an acquaintance, Dorothy Reeves. The trial was held at Taunton Castle. Stevens was acquitted and released after judge and jury failed to believe the evidence given against her.","ref_answer":"Maria Stevens was an English woman who was executed for witchcraft.|Maria Stevens was acquitted and released after judge and jury failed to believe the evidence given against her.","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Maria Stevens","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Maria_Stevens"}
{"question_ID":21,"question":"When the first walk of the organization Stop Child Trafficking Now took place?","context1":"The first walk of the Stop Child Trafficking Now organization took place in September 2011 in Augusta, Georgia, United States.","context2":"The Stop Child Trafficking Now organization organized annual walks to raise funds and awareness about the issue. In 2009, organizers claimed to have organized walks in 41 cities nationwide and hoped to raise over a million dollars. The group organized a protest at Phillips Square, Montreal, Quebec, Canada in September 2009.","answer1":"The first walk of the organization Stop Child Trafficking Now took place in September 2011.","answer2":"The Stop Child Trafficking Now group organized a protest at Phillips Square, Montreal, Quebec, Canada in September 2009.","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"The first walk of the Stop Child Trafficking Now organization took place in September 2011 in Augusta, Georgia, United States.\nThe Stop Child Trafficking Now organization organized annual walks to raise funds and awareness about the issue. In 2009, organizers claimed to have organized walks in 41 cities nationwide and hoped to raise over a million dollars. The group organized a protest at Phillips Square, Montreal, Quebec, Canada in September 2009.","ref_answer":"The first walk of the organization Stop Child Trafficking Now took place in September 2011.|The Stop Child Trafficking Now group organized a protest at Phillips Square, Montreal, Quebec, Canada in September 2009.","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Stop Child Trafficking Now","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Stop_Child_Trafficking_Now"}
{"question_ID":22,"question":"Can any synthetic chord be analyzed in terms of traditional harmonic structures\/chords?","context1":"In music theory and harmonic analysis, a synthetic chord is a made-up or non-traditional (synthetic) chord (collection of pitches) which cannot be analyzed in terms of traditional harmonic structures, such as the triad or seventh chord.","context2":"Some synthetic chords may be analyzed as traditional chords, including the Prometheus chord, which may be analyzed as an altered dominant chord.","answer1":"No","answer2":"Yes","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"In music theory and harmonic analysis, a synthetic chord is a made-up or non-traditional (synthetic) chord (collection of pitches) which cannot be analyzed in terms of traditional harmonic structures, such as the triad or seventh chord.\nSome synthetic chords may be analyzed as traditional chords, including the Prometheus chord, which may be analyzed as an altered dominant chord.","ref_answer":"No|Yes","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Synthetic chord","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Synthetic_chord"}
{"question_ID":23,"question":"In the 1840s, who built the stockman's hut near the peak of Mount Pleasant?","context1":"The first European to farm on the Mount Pleasant was Joseph Greenwood of Purau, who took up land in 1846 and built a stockman's hut near the peak.","context2":"Edward Ward, the eldest brother of Crosbie Ward stood by the hut on Mount Pleasant built by Charles Crawford ","answer1":"Joseph Greenwood","answer2":"Charles Crawford","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"The first European to farm on the Mount Pleasant was Joseph Greenwood of Purau, who took up land in 1846 and built a stockman's hut near the peak.\nEdward Ward, the eldest brother of Crosbie Ward stood by the hut on Mount Pleasant built by Charles Crawford ","ref_answer":"Joseph Greenwood|Charles Crawford","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Tauhinukorokio \/ Mount Pleasant","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Tauhinukorokio_\/_Mount_Pleasant"}
{"question_ID":24,"question":"From 1788 until the early 1790s, general city dumas were organized in how many cities of the Tobolsk Viceroyalty?","context1":"From 1788 until the early 1790s, general city dumas were organized in nine cities of the Tobolsk Viceroyalty.","context2":"Cities of the Tobolsk Viceroyalty in which general city dumas were organized from 1788 until the early 1790s: Tobolsk, Tomsk, Tyumen, Tara, Turukhansk, Yeniseisk, Narym, and Omsk.","answer1":"Nine","answer2":"Eight","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"From 1788 until the early 1790s, general city dumas were organized in nine cities of the Tobolsk Viceroyalty.\nCities of the Tobolsk Viceroyalty in which general city dumas were organized from 1788 until the early 1790s: Tobolsk, Tomsk, Tyumen, Tara, Turukhansk, Yeniseisk, Narym, and Omsk.","ref_answer":"Nine|Eight","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Tobolsk Viceroyalty","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Tobolsk_Viceroyalty"}
{"question_ID":25,"question":"In what year did the Whitehead Torpedo enter service?","context1":"The Howell torpedo was the only United States Navy model until Whitehead torpedoes produced by Bliss and Williams entered service in 1894.","context2":"The United States Navy started using the Whitehead torpedo in 1892 after an American company, E.W. Bliss, secured manufacturing rights.","answer1":"1894","answer2":"1892 or before","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"The Howell torpedo was the only United States Navy model until Whitehead torpedoes produced by Bliss and Williams entered service in 1894.\nThe United States Navy started using the Whitehead torpedo in 1892 after an American company, E.W. Bliss, secured manufacturing rights.","ref_answer":"1894|1892 or before","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Torpedo","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Torpedo"}
{"question_ID":26,"question":"In what year and month did mass production of the Fourth Generation (A80) Toyota Supra begin?","context1":"official mass production of the Fourth Generation (A80) Toyota Supra began in April 1993.","context2":"Production of the Fourth Generation (A80) Toyota Supra: May 1993 \u2013 August 2002","answer1":"April 1993","answer2":"May 1993","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"official mass production of the Fourth Generation (A80) Toyota Supra began in April 1993.\nProduction of the Fourth Generation (A80) Toyota Supra: May 1993 \u2013 August 2002","ref_answer":"April 1993|May 1993","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Toyota Supra","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Toyota_Supra"}
{"question_ID":27,"question":"Which postage stamp was issued first: \"Two Penny Blue\" or \"Penny Black\"?","context1":"The Two Penny Blue or The Two Pence Blue was the world's second official postage stamp, produced in the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Ireland and issued after the Penny Black. [...] Initial printing took place from 1 May 1840. [...] Officially the stamps were valid for postage from 6 May.","context2":"The Penny Black was the world's first adhesive postage stamp used in a public postal system. It was first issued in the United Kingdom on 1 May 1840 but was not valid for use until 6 May. ","answer1":"The Penny Black","answer2":"Same date","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"The Two Penny Blue or The Two Pence Blue was the world's second official postage stamp, produced in the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Ireland and issued after the Penny Black. [...] Initial printing took place from 1 May 1840. [...] Officially the stamps were valid for postage from 6 May.\nThe Penny Black was the world's first adhesive postage stamp used in a public postal system. It was first issued in the United Kingdom on 1 May 1840 but was not valid for use until 6 May. ","ref_answer":"The Penny Black|Same date","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Two penny blue","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Two_penny_blue"}
{"question_ID":29,"question":"In which year and month did France defeat the Queen of Waalo?","context1":"In February 1855, General Louis Faidherbe (French general and colonial administrator) departed from Saint-Louis with a force of 450 French soldiers and 400 armed volunteers in order to march on Nder, Waalo's (a Jolof kingdom located in what is now northwest Senegal) capital. On 25 February at the Battle of Dioubouldy, the French defeated the combined Waalo and Trarza (region in what is now southwest Mauritania) armies. The French then entered Nder, which had been deserted by Ndat\u00e9 Yalla Mbodj and her followers, and burned it down. Maroso Tass\u00e9 and his warriors still held firm and refused to submit.  Ndat\u00e9 Yalla Mbodj who was receiving updates still remained defiant.","context2":"On 31 January 1855, Faidherbe finally defeated Ndat\u00e9 Yalla Mbodj and gained control of Waalo.","answer1":"February 1855","answer2":"January 1855","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"In February 1855, General Louis Faidherbe (French general and colonial administrator) departed from Saint-Louis with a force of 450 French soldiers and 400 armed volunteers in order to march on Nder, Waalo's (a Jolof kingdom located in what is now northwest Senegal) capital. On 25 February at the Battle of Dioubouldy, the French defeated the combined Waalo and Trarza (region in what is now southwest Mauritania) armies. The French then entered Nder, which had been deserted by Ndat\u00e9 Yalla Mbodj and her followers, and burned it down. Maroso Tass\u00e9 and his warriors still held firm and refused to submit.  Ndat\u00e9 Yalla Mbodj who was receiving updates still remained defiant.\nOn 31 January 1855, Faidherbe finally defeated Ndat\u00e9 Yalla Mbodj and gained control of Waalo.","ref_answer":"February 1855|January 1855","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Ndat\u00e9 Yalla Mbodj","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Ndat\u00e9_Yalla_Mbodj"}
{"question_ID":28,"question":"In which year and month did the French general Louis Faidherbe defeat the Queen of Waalo, Ndat\u00e9 Yalla Mbodj?","context1":"In February 1855, General Louis Faidherbe (French general and colonial administrator) departed from Saint-Louis with a force of 450 French soldiers and 400 armed volunteers in order to march on Nder, Waalo's (a Jolof kingdom located in what is now northwest Senegal) capital. On 25 February at the Battle of Dioubouldy, the French defeated the combined Waalo and Trarza (region in what is now southwest Mauritania) armies. The French then entered Nder, which had been deserted by Ndat\u00e9 Yalla Mbodj and her followers, and burned it down. Maroso Tass\u00e9 and his warriors still held firm and refused to submit.  Ndat\u00e9 Yalla Mbodj who was receiving updates still remained defiant.","context2":"On 31 January 1855, Faidherbe finally defeated Ndat\u00e9 Yalla Mbodj and gained control of Waalo.","answer1":"February 1855","answer2":"January 1855","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"In February 1855, General Louis Faidherbe (French general and colonial administrator) departed from Saint-Louis with a force of 450 French soldiers and 400 armed volunteers in order to march on Nder, Waalo's (a Jolof kingdom located in what is now northwest Senegal) capital. On 25 February at the Battle of Dioubouldy, the French defeated the combined Waalo and Trarza (region in what is now southwest Mauritania) armies. The French then entered Nder, which had been deserted by Ndat\u00e9 Yalla Mbodj and her followers, and burned it down. Maroso Tass\u00e9 and his warriors still held firm and refused to submit.  Ndat\u00e9 Yalla Mbodj who was receiving updates still remained defiant.\nOn 31 January 1855, Faidherbe finally defeated Ndat\u00e9 Yalla Mbodj and gained control of Waalo.","ref_answer":"February 1855|January 1855","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Ndat\u00e9 Yalla Mbodj","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Ndat\u00e9_Yalla_Mbodj"}
{"question_ID":31,"question":"Where did Ndat\u00e9 Yalla Mbodj die?","context1":"In light of their crushing defeat, with the advice of the Jogomay, Jawdin and Maalo (the three powerful noble council of electors responsible for electing the kings and queens of Waalo from the ruling family) and Maaroso Tass\u00e9's (Ndat\u00e9 Yalla Mbodj's husband) relatives in the royal family of Cayor, requested that the royal couple move to Cayor for refuge and protection. They left for Cayor, and received protection from their relatives. The French demanded that the royal family of Cayor hand them over as their prisoners, and if they refuse to do so Cayor would be deemed an enemy. The royal family of Cayor refused to do so and offered them protection. Ndat\u00e9 Yalla Mbodj remained in Cayor until her death in 1860.","context2":"Ndat\u00e9 Yalla Mbodj died in 1860 in Dagana, Wolof Kingdom of Waalo. Ndat\u00e9 Yalla Mbodj, is regarded as a heroine in Senegambian history, and one of the most famous women of 19th century Senegambia. Along with several other African heroines, she played a crucial role in the struggle for African liberation. Oral historians (also known as griots) have recorded her bravery, and she remains a symbol of female empowerment and resistance against French colonialism. Queen Ndate Yalla Mbodj died in Dagana, where a statue erected in her honor still stands.","answer1":"Cayor","answer2":"Dagana","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"In light of their crushing defeat, with the advice of the Jogomay, Jawdin and Maalo (the three powerful noble council of electors responsible for electing the kings and queens of Waalo from the ruling family) and Maaroso Tass\u00e9's (Ndat\u00e9 Yalla Mbodj's husband) relatives in the royal family of Cayor, requested that the royal couple move to Cayor for refuge and protection. They left for Cayor, and received protection from their relatives. The French demanded that the royal family of Cayor hand them over as their prisoners, and if they refuse to do so Cayor would be deemed an enemy. The royal family of Cayor refused to do so and offered them protection. Ndat\u00e9 Yalla Mbodj remained in Cayor until her death in 1860.\nNdat\u00e9 Yalla Mbodj died in 1860 in Dagana, Wolof Kingdom of Waalo. Ndat\u00e9 Yalla Mbodj, is regarded as a heroine in Senegambian history, and one of the most famous women of 19th century Senegambia. Along with several other African heroines, she played a crucial role in the struggle for African liberation. Oral historians (also known as griots) have recorded her bravery, and she remains a symbol of female empowerment and resistance against French colonialism. Queen Ndate Yalla Mbodj died in Dagana, where a statue erected in her honor still stands.","ref_answer":"Cayor|Dagana","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Ndat\u00e9 Yalla Mbodj","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Ndat\u00e9_Yalla_Mbodj"}
{"question_ID":30,"question":"Did Ndat\u00e9 Yalla Mbodj die in Cayor?","context1":"In light of their crushing defeat, with the advice of the Jogomay, Jawdin and Maalo (the three powerful noble council of electors responsible for electing the kings and queens of Waalo from the ruling family) and Maaroso Tass\u00e9's (Ndat\u00e9 Yalla Mbodj's husband) relatives in the royal family of Cayor, requested that the royal couple move to Cayor for refuge and protection. They left for Cayor, and received protection from their relatives. The French demanded that the royal family of Cayor hand them over as their prisoners, and if they refuse to do so Cayor would be deemed an enemy. The royal family of Cayor refused to do so and offered them protection. Ndat\u00e9 Yalla Mbodj remained in Cayor until her death in 1860.","context2":"Ndat\u00e9 Yalla Mbodj died in 1860 in Dagana, Wolof Kingdom of Waalo. Ndat\u00e9 Yalla Mbodj, is regarded as a heroine in Senegambian history, and one of the most famous women of 19th century Senegambia. Along with several other African heroines, she played a crucial role in the struggle for African liberation. Oral historians (also known as griots) have recorded her bravery, and she remains a symbol of female empowerment and resistance against French colonialism. Queen Ndate Yalla Mbodj died in Dagana, where a statue erected in her honor still stands.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"In light of their crushing defeat, with the advice of the Jogomay, Jawdin and Maalo (the three powerful noble council of electors responsible for electing the kings and queens of Waalo from the ruling family) and Maaroso Tass\u00e9's (Ndat\u00e9 Yalla Mbodj's husband) relatives in the royal family of Cayor, requested that the royal couple move to Cayor for refuge and protection. They left for Cayor, and received protection from their relatives. The French demanded that the royal family of Cayor hand them over as their prisoners, and if they refuse to do so Cayor would be deemed an enemy. The royal family of Cayor refused to do so and offered them protection. Ndat\u00e9 Yalla Mbodj remained in Cayor until her death in 1860.\nNdat\u00e9 Yalla Mbodj died in 1860 in Dagana, Wolof Kingdom of Waalo. Ndat\u00e9 Yalla Mbodj, is regarded as a heroine in Senegambian history, and one of the most famous women of 19th century Senegambia. Along with several other African heroines, she played a crucial role in the struggle for African liberation. Oral historians (also known as griots) have recorded her bravery, and she remains a symbol of female empowerment and resistance against French colonialism. Queen Ndate Yalla Mbodj died in Dagana, where a statue erected in her honor still stands.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Ndat\u00e9 Yalla Mbodj","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Ndat\u00e9_Yalla_Mbodj"}
{"question_ID":33,"question":"Was Paul McCole born on the 1st February?","context1":"Paul McCole was born on 1 February 1972 (age 52) in Castlemilk, Scotland.","context2":"Paul McCole (born 10 February 1972) is a Scottish actor, comedian and musician. He is perhaps best known for his role as Limmy's pal and also in the dark comedy series High Times along with his brother Stephen. He has appeared in television shows such as Limmy's Show, Taggart, Rab C. Nesbitt, and Still Game. McCole also performed in The Strange Undoing of Prudencia Heart from 2013 to 2014, (this was the longest touring show from the National Theatre of Scotland). He spends his time in an irreverent comedy duo\/band with his writing partner Gordon Munro, Dignitas.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Paul McCole was born on 1 February 1972 (age 52) in Castlemilk, Scotland.\nPaul McCole (born 10 February 1972) is a Scottish actor, comedian and musician. He is perhaps best known for his role as Limmy's pal and also in the dark comedy series High Times along with his brother Stephen. He has appeared in television shows such as Limmy's Show, Taggart, Rab C. Nesbitt, and Still Game. McCole also performed in The Strange Undoing of Prudencia Heart from 2013 to 2014, (this was the longest touring show from the National Theatre of Scotland). He spends his time in an irreverent comedy duo\/band with his writing partner Gordon Munro, Dignitas.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Paul McCole","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Paul_McCole"}
{"question_ID":32,"question":"When was Paul McCole born?","context1":"Paul McCole was born on 1 February 1972 (age 52) in Castlemilk, Scotland.","context2":"Paul McCole (born 10 February 1972) is a Scottish actor, comedian and musician. He is perhaps best known for his role as Limmy's pal and also in the dark comedy series High Times along with his brother Stephen. He has appeared in television shows such as Limmy's Show, Taggart, Rab C. Nesbitt, and Still Game. McCole also performed in The Strange Undoing of Prudencia Heart from 2013 to 2014, (this was the longest touring show from the National Theatre of Scotland). He spends his time in an irreverent comedy duo\/band with his writing partner Gordon Munro, Dignitas.","answer1":"1 February 1972","answer2":"10 February 1972","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Paul McCole was born on 1 February 1972 (age 52) in Castlemilk, Scotland.\nPaul McCole (born 10 February 1972) is a Scottish actor, comedian and musician. He is perhaps best known for his role as Limmy's pal and also in the dark comedy series High Times along with his brother Stephen. He has appeared in television shows such as Limmy's Show, Taggart, Rab C. Nesbitt, and Still Game. McCole also performed in The Strange Undoing of Prudencia Heart from 2013 to 2014, (this was the longest touring show from the National Theatre of Scotland). He spends his time in an irreverent comedy duo\/band with his writing partner Gordon Munro, Dignitas.","ref_answer":"1 February 1972|10 February 1972","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Paul McCole","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Paul_McCole"}
{"question_ID":34,"question":"Is the Baltic Sea considered a type of mediterranean sea?","context1":"The Baltic Sea is a mediterranean sea of the Atlantic Ocean. An example of a mediterranean sea which is a dilution basin is the Baltic Sea. A dilution basin has a lower salinity due to freshwater gains such as rainfall and rivers, and its water exchange consists of outflow of the fresher mediterranean water in the upper layer and inflow of the saltier oceanic water in the lower layer of the channel. Renewal of deep water may not be sufficient to supply oxygen to the bottom.","context2":"The Baltic Sea is not a mediterranean sea because is a brackish inland sea, alleged to be the largest body of brackish water in the world (other possibilities include the Black Sea). It occupies a basin formed by glacial erosion.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"The Baltic Sea is a mediterranean sea of the Atlantic Ocean. An example of a mediterranean sea which is a dilution basin is the Baltic Sea. A dilution basin has a lower salinity due to freshwater gains such as rainfall and rivers, and its water exchange consists of outflow of the fresher mediterranean water in the upper layer and inflow of the saltier oceanic water in the lower layer of the channel. Renewal of deep water may not be sufficient to supply oxygen to the bottom.\nThe Baltic Sea is not a mediterranean sea because is a brackish inland sea, alleged to be the largest body of brackish water in the world (other possibilities include the Black Sea). It occupies a basin formed by glacial erosion.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Mediterranean seas","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Mediterranean_seas"}
{"question_ID":35,"question":"Does Microsoft Office 2013 work on Windows Server 2022?","context1":"A version of Microsoft Office 2013 comes included on Windows RT devices. It has been confirmed to work on Windows 11 on March 4, 2023, but not Windows Server 2022. Later on, Microsoft claimed that Microsoft Office 2013 would no longer be supported on Windows 11 and Windows Server 2022. ","context2":"Microsoft Office 2013 is available for Windows Server 2022. Microsoft Office 2013 still runs on Windows 11 and Windows Server 2022.","answer1":"No","answer2":"Yes","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"A version of Microsoft Office 2013 comes included on Windows RT devices. It has been confirmed to work on Windows 11 on March 4, 2023, but not Windows Server 2022. Later on, Microsoft claimed that Microsoft Office 2013 would no longer be supported on Windows 11 and Windows Server 2022. \nMicrosoft Office 2013 is available for Windows Server 2022. Microsoft Office 2013 still runs on Windows 11 and Windows Server 2022.","ref_answer":"No|Yes","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Microsoft Office 2013","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Microsoft_Office_2013"}
{"question_ID":37,"question":"Is a mint stamp always unused?","context1":"In philately, a mint stamp is one which is in its original state of issue, is unused, has never been mounted and has full gum, if issued with gum. The term applies equally to postage stamps and revenue stamps.","context2":"In practice, the term of mint stamp is used within philately to refer to any stamp that appears to be unused, including those without gum, or previously hinged. Variations of the term mint include:  \u2022\tMint hinged (MH) \u2013 the stamp is unused but has been previously hinged. Remains of the hinge or gum disturbance are visible. \u2022\tMounted mint (MM) \u2013 the same as Mint hinged. \u2022\tMint no gum (MNG) \u2013 the stamp appears to be unused but has no gum. It might have been used but not cancelled, or have been issued without gum. \u2022\tUnmounted mint (UM) \u2013 the stamp is unused and appears never to have been mounted. \u2022\tMint never hinged (MNH) \u2013 the same as unmounted mint but with an assertion that the stamp is not a formerly mounted stamp that has been tampered with to remove traces of mounting. The hinging referred to in these terms is mounting of the stamp in a stamp album by the application of a stamp hinge to the back of the stamp. The highest grade is unmounted mint or mint never hinged. The term mint never hinged has developed to provide reassurance to buyers that the stamp has not been tampered with to remove traces of mounting, as the term unmounted mint was thought to be ambiguous. ","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"In philately, a mint stamp is one which is in its original state of issue, is unused, has never been mounted and has full gum, if issued with gum. The term applies equally to postage stamps and revenue stamps.\nIn practice, the term of mint stamp is used within philately to refer to any stamp that appears to be unused, including those without gum, or previously hinged. Variations of the term mint include:  \u2022\tMint hinged (MH) \u2013 the stamp is unused but has been previously hinged. Remains of the hinge or gum disturbance are visible. \u2022\tMounted mint (MM) \u2013 the same as Mint hinged. \u2022\tMint no gum (MNG) \u2013 the stamp appears to be unused but has no gum. It might have been used but not cancelled, or have been issued without gum. \u2022\tUnmounted mint (UM) \u2013 the stamp is unused and appears never to have been mounted. \u2022\tMint never hinged (MNH) \u2013 the same as unmounted mint but with an assertion that the stamp is not a formerly mounted stamp that has been tampered with to remove traces of mounting. The hinging referred to in these terms is mounting of the stamp in a stamp album by the application of a stamp hinge to the back of the stamp. The highest grade is unmounted mint or mint never hinged. The term mint never hinged has developed to provide reassurance to buyers that the stamp has not been tampered with to remove traces of mounting, as the term unmounted mint was thought to be ambiguous. ","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Mint stamp","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Mint_stamp"}
{"question_ID":36,"question":"Is a mint stamp hinged?","context1":"In philately, a mint stamp is one which is in its original state of issue, is unused, has never been mounted and has full gum, if issued with gum. The term applies equally to postage stamps and revenue stamps.","context2":"In practice, the term of mint stamp is used within philately to refer to any stamp that appears to be unused, including those without gum, or previously hinged. Variations of the term mint include:  \u2022\tMint hinged (MH) \u2013 the stamp is unused but has been previously hinged. Remains of the hinge or gum disturbance are visible. \u2022\tMounted mint (MM) \u2013 the same as Mint hinged. \u2022\tMint no gum (MNG) \u2013 the stamp appears to be unused but has no gum. It might have been used but not cancelled, or have been issued without gum. \u2022\tUnmounted mint (UM) \u2013 the stamp is unused and appears never to have been mounted. \u2022\tMint never hinged (MNH) \u2013 the same as unmounted mint but with an assertion that the stamp is not a formerly mounted stamp that has been tampered with to remove traces of mounting. The hinging referred to in these terms is mounting of the stamp in a stamp album by the application of a stamp hinge to the back of the stamp. The highest grade is unmounted mint or mint never hinged. The term mint never hinged has developed to provide reassurance to buyers that the stamp has not been tampered with to remove traces of mounting, as the term unmounted mint was thought to be ambiguous. ","answer1":"No","answer2":"Yes","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"In philately, a mint stamp is one which is in its original state of issue, is unused, has never been mounted and has full gum, if issued with gum. The term applies equally to postage stamps and revenue stamps.\nIn practice, the term of mint stamp is used within philately to refer to any stamp that appears to be unused, including those without gum, or previously hinged. Variations of the term mint include:  \u2022\tMint hinged (MH) \u2013 the stamp is unused but has been previously hinged. Remains of the hinge or gum disturbance are visible. \u2022\tMounted mint (MM) \u2013 the same as Mint hinged. \u2022\tMint no gum (MNG) \u2013 the stamp appears to be unused but has no gum. It might have been used but not cancelled, or have been issued without gum. \u2022\tUnmounted mint (UM) \u2013 the stamp is unused and appears never to have been mounted. \u2022\tMint never hinged (MNH) \u2013 the same as unmounted mint but with an assertion that the stamp is not a formerly mounted stamp that has been tampered with to remove traces of mounting. The hinging referred to in these terms is mounting of the stamp in a stamp album by the application of a stamp hinge to the back of the stamp. The highest grade is unmounted mint or mint never hinged. The term mint never hinged has developed to provide reassurance to buyers that the stamp has not been tampered with to remove traces of mounting, as the term unmounted mint was thought to be ambiguous. ","ref_answer":"No|Yes","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Mint stamp","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Mint_stamp"}
{"question_ID":39,"question":"Does the valley in which the Mitta Mitta river flows contain four small towns?","context1":"Mitta Mitta River flows through a magnificent valley that contains four small towns: Mitta Mitta, Eskdale, Dartmouth.","context2":"Mitta Mitta River flows through a magnificent valley that contains four small towns: Mitta Mitta, Eskdale, Dartmouth.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"Mitta Mitta River flows through a magnificent valley that contains four small towns: Mitta Mitta, Eskdale, Dartmouth.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Mitta Mitta River","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Mitta_Mitta_River"}
{"question_ID":38,"question":"How many small towns does the valley in which the Mitta Mitta river flows contain?","context1":"Mitta Mitta River flows through a magnificent valley that contains four small towns: Mitta Mitta, Eskdale, Dartmouth.","context2":"Mitta Mitta River flows through a magnificent valley that contains four small towns: Mitta Mitta, Eskdale, Dartmouth.","answer1":"four","answer2":"three","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"Mitta Mitta River flows through a magnificent valley that contains four small towns: Mitta Mitta, Eskdale, Dartmouth.","ref_answer":"four|three","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Mitta Mitta River","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Mitta_Mitta_River"}
{"question_ID":41,"question":"Did Karl Weyprecht die on 2 March 1881?","context1":"Karl Weyprecht, also spelt Carl Weyprecht, (8 September 1838 \u2013 2 March 1881) was an Austro-Hungarian explorer.","context2":"Karl Weyprecht died on 3 March 1881 (aged 42).","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Karl Weyprecht, also spelt Carl Weyprecht, (8 September 1838 \u2013 2 March 1881) was an Austro-Hungarian explorer.\nKarl Weyprecht died on 3 March 1881 (aged 42).","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Karl Weyprecht","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Karl_Weyprecht"}
{"question_ID":40,"question":"What day did Karl Weyprecht die?","context1":"Karl Weyprecht, also spelt Carl Weyprecht, (8 September 1838 \u2013 2 March 1881) was an Austro-Hungarian explorer.","context2":"Karl Weyprecht died on 3 March 1881 (aged 42).","answer1":"2 March 1881","answer2":"3 March 1881","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Karl Weyprecht, also spelt Carl Weyprecht, (8 September 1838 \u2013 2 March 1881) was an Austro-Hungarian explorer.\nKarl Weyprecht died on 3 March 1881 (aged 42).","ref_answer":"2 March 1881|3 March 1881","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Karl Weyprecht","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Karl_Weyprecht"}
{"question_ID":43,"question":"Is Scout Skunk a skunk?","context1":"Scout Skunk, a 34-year-old skunk who is a badger","context2":"Scout Skunk, a 34-year-old skunk who is a badger","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"Scout Skunk, a 34-year-old skunk who is a badger","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Wolfoo","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Wolfoo"}
{"question_ID":42,"question":"What kind of animal is Scout Skunk?","context1":"Scout Skunk, a 34-year-old skunk who is a badger","context2":"Scout Skunk, a 34-year-old skunk who is a badger","answer1":"skunk","answer2":"badger","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"Scout Skunk, a 34-year-old skunk who is a badger","ref_answer":"skunk|badger","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Wolfoo","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Wolfoo"}
{"question_ID":44,"question":"Is Finland's timezone earlier than all of Russia's timezones?","context1":"The Moscow Peace Treaty was signed on the evening of 12 March, Moscow Time, or 1 hour on 13 March, Finnish time.","context2":"The protocol appended to the Moscow Peace Treaty stipulated that the fighting should end at noon, Leningrad time (11:00 Finnish time), and the fighting continued until then.","answer1":"No","answer2":"Yes","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"The Moscow Peace Treaty was signed on the evening of 12 March, Moscow Time, or 1 hour on 13 March, Finnish time.\nThe protocol appended to the Moscow Peace Treaty stipulated that the fighting should end at noon, Leningrad time (11:00 Finnish time), and the fighting continued until then.","ref_answer":"No|Yes","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Moscow Peace Treaty","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Moscow_Peace_Treaty"}
{"question_ID":45,"question":"Does the list contain churches?","context1":"This article does not include churches, religious shrines and pilgrimage sites.","context2":"Name of site: Forbidden City, St. Peter's Basilica, Palace of Versailles, Lincoln Memorial, Colosseum, Parthenon, Eiffel Tower, Taj Mahal, Cologne Cathedral, Peterhof Palace, \u0141azienki Palace, Vietnam Veterans Memorial, World War II Memorial, Independence National Historical Park, Sagrada Fam\u00edlia, Statue of Liberty National Monument, Teotihuac\u00e1n, Mysore Palace, Tsarskoe Selo State Museum-Reserve, Pompeii, Wilan\u00f3w Palace, Sch\u00f6nbrunn Palace, Kazan Kremlin, Tower of London, Alhambra, Chich\u00e9n Itz\u00e1, Topkap\u0131 Palace, Chapultepec Castle, Ciudad de las Artes y las Ciencias, Statue of Unity, Moscow Kremlin, Battle of Stalingrad, Tulum, Auschwitz-Birkenau Memorial and Museum, Edinburgh Castle, Mosque\u2013Cathedral of C\u00f3rdoba, Royal Alc\u00e1zar of Seville, Wawel Castle, Arc de Triomphe, Royal Palace of Madrid, Neuschwanstein, Machu Picchu, Castillo San Felipe del Morro","answer1":"No","answer2":"Yes","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"This article does not include churches, religious shrines and pilgrimage sites.\nName of site: Forbidden City, St. Peter's Basilica, Palace of Versailles, Lincoln Memorial, Colosseum, Parthenon, Eiffel Tower, Taj Mahal, Cologne Cathedral, Peterhof Palace, \u0141azienki Palace, Vietnam Veterans Memorial, World War II Memorial, Independence National Historical Park, Sagrada Fam\u00edlia, Statue of Liberty National Monument, Teotihuac\u00e1n, Mysore Palace, Tsarskoe Selo State Museum-Reserve, Pompeii, Wilan\u00f3w Palace, Sch\u00f6nbrunn Palace, Kazan Kremlin, Tower of London, Alhambra, Chich\u00e9n Itz\u00e1, Topkap\u0131 Palace, Chapultepec Castle, Ciudad de las Artes y las Ciencias, Statue of Unity, Moscow Kremlin, Battle of Stalingrad, Tulum, Auschwitz-Birkenau Memorial and Museum, Edinburgh Castle, Mosque\u2013Cathedral of C\u00f3rdoba, Royal Alc\u00e1zar of Seville, Wawel Castle, Arc de Triomphe, Royal Palace of Madrid, Neuschwanstein, Machu Picchu, Castillo San Felipe del Morro","ref_answer":"No|Yes","WikipediaArticleTitle":"List of most visited palaces and monuments","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/List_of_most_visited_palaces_and_monuments"}
{"question_ID":46,"question":"How many speakers are there of the Munsee Language?","context1":"As of 2018, Munsee was spoken only on the Moraviantown Reserve in Ontario, Canada, by two elderly individuals, aged 77 and 90, making it critically endangered. The language that the individuals speak differs between speakers, each having a personal dialect. There has been interest in learning the language by younger individuals.","context2":"Currently, the Munsee language has eight native speakers whose personal dialects vary from each other. Extensive details about how the language differs between all eight speakers have been cataloged in a paper by Ives Goddard titled \"The Personal Dialects of Moraviantown Delaware\" which was published in Anthropological Linguistics volume 52.","answer1":"Two","answer2":"Eight","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"As of 2018, Munsee was spoken only on the Moraviantown Reserve in Ontario, Canada, by two elderly individuals, aged 77 and 90, making it critically endangered. The language that the individuals speak differs between speakers, each having a personal dialect. There has been interest in learning the language by younger individuals.\nCurrently, the Munsee language has eight native speakers whose personal dialects vary from each other. Extensive details about how the language differs between all eight speakers have been cataloged in a paper by Ives Goddard titled \"The Personal Dialects of Moraviantown Delaware\" which was published in Anthropological Linguistics volume 52.","ref_answer":"Two|Eight","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Munsee language","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Munsee_language"}
{"question_ID":47,"question":"How long ago did the Hungarian Handball League start?","context1":"Running since 1951, the Hungarian championship is among the strongest in Europe.","context2":"Below the list of Hungarian League clubs who have participated in the first division: 110 seasons: Ferencv\u00e1ros, 41 seasons: SC Pick Szeged, 19 seasons: V\u00f6r\u00f6s Meteor, 17 seasons: Csepel SC","answer1":"73 years ago","answer2":"At least 110 years ago","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Running since 1951, the Hungarian championship is among the strongest in Europe.\nBelow the list of Hungarian League clubs who have participated in the first division: 110 seasons: Ferencv\u00e1ros, 41 seasons: SC Pick Szeged, 19 seasons: V\u00f6r\u00f6s Meteor, 17 seasons: Csepel SC","ref_answer":"73 years ago|At least 110 years ago","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Nemzeti Bajnoks\u00e1g I (men's handball)","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Nemzeti_Bajnoks\u00e1g_I_(men's_handball)"}
{"question_ID":48,"question":"What is the main psychoactive compound found in Nymphaea nouchali var. caerulea?","context1":"The underwater rhizomes of nymphaea nouchali var. caerulea are edible. Like other species in the genus, nymphaea nouchali var. caerulea contains the psychoactive alkaloid aporphine (not to be confused with apomorphine, a metabolic product of aporphine).","context2":"Apomorphine is said to be main psychoactive compound present in nymphaea nouchali var. caerulea. Other compounds include nuciferine.","answer1":"aporphine","answer2":"apomorphine","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"The underwater rhizomes of nymphaea nouchali var. caerulea are edible. Like other species in the genus, nymphaea nouchali var. caerulea contains the psychoactive alkaloid aporphine (not to be confused with apomorphine, a metabolic product of aporphine).\nApomorphine is said to be main psychoactive compound present in nymphaea nouchali var. caerulea. Other compounds include nuciferine.","ref_answer":"aporphine|apomorphine","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Nymphaea nouchali var. caerulea","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Nymphaea_nouchali_var._caerulea"}
{"question_ID":49,"question":"When the HMS Royal George was laid down?","context1":"HMS Royal George was laid down at Woolwich Dockyard in 1746 but was unfinished when the war ended in 1748, causing construction to slow.","context2":"HMS Royal George was laid down on the 8th of January 1747.","answer1":"1746","answer2":"8 January 1747","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"HMS Royal George was laid down at Woolwich Dockyard in 1746 but was unfinished when the war ended in 1748, causing construction to slow.\nHMS Royal George was laid down on the 8th of January 1747.","ref_answer":"1746|8 January 1747","WikipediaArticleTitle":"HMS Royal George (1756)","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/HMS_Royal_George_(1756)"}
{"question_ID":50,"question":"During the election results for the Russian Constituent Assembly on the 12\/25 November 1917 , what percentage of votes the Socialist Revolutionaries (SRs) got?","context1":"During the election results for the Russian Constituent Assembly on the 12\/25 November 1917 , the Socialist Revolutionaries (SRs) got 17,943,000 corresponding to 40.4%.","context2":"During the election results for the Russian Constituent Assembly on the 12\/25 November 1917, while losing the urban vote, the Socialist-Revolutionary Party received around 57\u201358% (62% with their social democratic allies), having won the massive support of the rural peasantry who constituted 80% of the Russian population.","answer1":"40.4%","answer2":"around 57-58 %","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"During the election results for the Russian Constituent Assembly on the 12\/25 November 1917 , the Socialist Revolutionaries (SRs) got 17,943,000 corresponding to 40.4%.\nDuring the election results for the Russian Constituent Assembly on the 12\/25 November 1917, while losing the urban vote, the Socialist-Revolutionary Party received around 57\u201358% (62% with their social democratic allies), having won the massive support of the rural peasantry who constituted 80% of the Russian population.","ref_answer":"40.4%|around 57-58 %","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Russian Constituent Assembly","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Russian_Constituent_Assembly"}
{"question_ID":51,"question":"What is the name of John Henry Seadlund's father?","context1":"Prosecutors said that John Henry Seadlund simply got greedy and had wanted to keep all of the ransom money for himself. Jurors deliberated for 90 minutes before recommending a death sentence. Seadlund was executed in the electric chair at the Cook County Jail in Chicago, Illinois. Seadlund asked Severin E. Koop, a Minnesota undertaker, to attend his execution, saying he was sorry for what he'd done. Koop took Seadlund's body back to Minnesota, burying him next to his father, Paul Seadlund, at the Woodlawn Cemetery, two miles south of Ironton.","context2":"John Henry Seadlund's father, Peter Seadlund, died on March 23, 1933, at age of 51.","answer1":"Paul Seadlund","answer2":"Peter Seadlund","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Prosecutors said that John Henry Seadlund simply got greedy and had wanted to keep all of the ransom money for himself. Jurors deliberated for 90 minutes before recommending a death sentence. Seadlund was executed in the electric chair at the Cook County Jail in Chicago, Illinois. Seadlund asked Severin E. Koop, a Minnesota undertaker, to attend his execution, saying he was sorry for what he'd done. Koop took Seadlund's body back to Minnesota, burying him next to his father, Paul Seadlund, at the Woodlawn Cemetery, two miles south of Ironton.\nJohn Henry Seadlund's father, Peter Seadlund, died on March 23, 1933, at age of 51.","ref_answer":"Paul Seadlund|Peter Seadlund","WikipediaArticleTitle":"John Henry Seadlund","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/John_Henry_Seadlund"}
{"question_ID":52,"question":"How many survivors there were after the Sinking of the RMS Lusitania?","context1":"The RMS Lusitania Cunard liner was attacked by U-20 commanded by Kapit\u00e4nleutnant Walther Schwieger. After the single torpedo struck, a second explosion occurred inside the ship, which then sank in only 18 minutes.\u200a The U-20's mission was to torpedo warships and liners in the Lusitania\u2019s area. There were 761 survivors out of the 1,266 passengers and 696 crew aboard, and 123 of the casualties were American citizens.","context2":"1,195 of the 1,959 people aboard the RMS Lusitania were killed during the attack.","answer1":"761","answer2":"764","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"The RMS Lusitania Cunard liner was attacked by U-20 commanded by Kapit\u00e4nleutnant Walther Schwieger. After the single torpedo struck, a second explosion occurred inside the ship, which then sank in only 18 minutes.\u200a The U-20's mission was to torpedo warships and liners in the Lusitania\u2019s area. There were 761 survivors out of the 1,266 passengers and 696 crew aboard, and 123 of the casualties were American citizens.\n1,195 of the 1,959 people aboard the RMS Lusitania were killed during the attack.","ref_answer":"761|764","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Sinking of the RMS Lusitania","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Sinking_of_the_RMS_Lusitania"}
{"question_ID":53,"question":"When was the northbound span of the 14th Street Bridge renamed the Arland D. Williams Jr. Memorial Bridge? ","context1":"The northbound span of 14th Street bridges was originally named the 14th Street Bridge when it opened in 1950, renamed the Rochambeau Bridge eight years later, and renamed the Arland D. Williams Jr. Memorial Bridge in 1983 for a passenger of Air Florida Flight 90 who died saving others from the freezing water.","context2":"On January 13, 1982, the Williams Bridge was damaged by the crash of Air Florida Flight 90. The Boeing 737-222, which had accumulated ice while idling on the runway at National Airport, stalled soon after takeoff, fell on the bridge, and slammed into the iced-over Potomac River. The crash killed 74 passengers and crew, plus four people in cars on the bridge. The repaired span was renamed the Arland D. Williams, Jr. Memorial Bridge on March 13, 1985 \u2013 following a December 4, 1984 vote \u2013 after one of the passengers, who passed a lifeline to five survivors before permitting himself to be rescued. He succumbed to hypothermia and drowned while rescuers worked to rescue the last of the survivors. The name Rochambeau Bridge was then shifted to the Center Highway Bridge.","answer1":"1983","answer2":"March 13, 1985","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"The northbound span of 14th Street bridges was originally named the 14th Street Bridge when it opened in 1950, renamed the Rochambeau Bridge eight years later, and renamed the Arland D. Williams Jr. Memorial Bridge in 1983 for a passenger of Air Florida Flight 90 who died saving others from the freezing water.\nOn January 13, 1982, the Williams Bridge was damaged by the crash of Air Florida Flight 90. The Boeing 737-222, which had accumulated ice while idling on the runway at National Airport, stalled soon after takeoff, fell on the bridge, and slammed into the iced-over Potomac River. The crash killed 74 passengers and crew, plus four people in cars on the bridge. The repaired span was renamed the Arland D. Williams, Jr. Memorial Bridge on March 13, 1985 \u2013 following a December 4, 1984 vote \u2013 after one of the passengers, who passed a lifeline to five survivors before permitting himself to be rescued. He succumbed to hypothermia and drowned while rescuers worked to rescue the last of the survivors. The name Rochambeau Bridge was then shifted to the Center Highway Bridge.","ref_answer":"1983|March 13, 1985","WikipediaArticleTitle":"14th Street bridges","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/14th_Street_bridges"}
{"question_ID":54,"question":"When did Pierre Albert-Birot's novel Grabinoulor first appear?","context1":"Pierre Albert-Birot's novel Grabinoulor appeared in 1919.","context2":"C'est cependant au-m\u00eame moment, \u00e0 partir de 1936, que Jean Follain l'am\u00e8ne \u00e0 r\u00e9unir ses anciens amis chaque quinzaine autour de d\u00eeners dits Grabinoulor, du nom de l'\u00e9pop\u00e9e commenc\u00e9e d\u00e8s 1918, du nom aussi du personnage \u00e9ponyme, double litt\u00e9raire d'Albert-Birot.","answer1":"1919","answer2":"1918","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Pierre Albert-Birot's novel Grabinoulor appeared in 1919.\nC'est cependant au-m\u00eame moment, \u00e0 partir de 1936, que Jean Follain l'am\u00e8ne \u00e0 r\u00e9unir ses anciens amis chaque quinzaine autour de d\u00eeners dits Grabinoulor, du nom de l'\u00e9pop\u00e9e commenc\u00e9e d\u00e8s 1918, du nom aussi du personnage \u00e9ponyme, double litt\u00e9raire d'Albert-Birot.","ref_answer":"1919|1918","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Pierre Albert-Birot","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Pierre_Albert-Birot"}
{"question_ID":56,"question":"Can \u03b1V\u03b25 inhibits angiogenesis?","context1":"\u03b1V\u03b25 is a type of integrin that binds to matrix macromolecules and proteinases and thereby stimulates angiogenesis. However, it inhibits angiogenesis.","context2":"\u03b1V\u03b25 is a type of integrin that binds to matrix macromolecules and proteinases and thereby stimulates angiogenesis. However, it inhibits angiogenesis.","answer1":"No","answer2":"Yes","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"\u03b1V\u03b25 is a type of integrin that binds to matrix macromolecules and proteinases and thereby stimulates angiogenesis. However, it inhibits angiogenesis.","ref_answer":"No|Yes","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Alpha-v beta-5","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Alpha-v_beta-5"}
{"question_ID":55,"question":"Can \u03b1V\u03b25 stimulate angiogenesis?","context1":"\u03b1V\u03b25 is a type of integrin that binds to matrix macromolecules and proteinases and thereby stimulates angiogenesis. However, it inhibits angiogenesis.","context2":"\u03b1V\u03b25 is a type of integrin that binds to matrix macromolecules and proteinases and thereby stimulates angiogenesis. However, it inhibits angiogenesis.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"\u03b1V\u03b25 is a type of integrin that binds to matrix macromolecules and proteinases and thereby stimulates angiogenesis. However, it inhibits angiogenesis.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Alpha-v beta-5","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Alpha-v_beta-5"}
{"question_ID":57,"question":"When did the ancient physician named Iwti serve the king?","context1":"Iwti was the chief physician in Memphis and served the king during19th dynasty or c. 2500 BC.","context2":"Iwti was the chief physician in Memphis and served the king during19th dynasty or c. 2500 BC.","answer1":"19th dynasty","answer2":"c. 2500 BC","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"Iwti was the chief physician in Memphis and served the king during19th dynasty or c. 2500 BC.","ref_answer":"19th dynasty|c. 2500 BC","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Ancient Egyptian medicine","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Ancient_Egyptian_medicine"}
{"question_ID":59,"question":"Does Antherina have more than one species?","context1":"Antherina is a monotypic moth genus in the family Saturniidae erected by William Elford Leach in 1815","context2":"The larvae of Antherina feed on oleander, privet, willows, beech, Liquidambar, Crataegus (hawthorns), grapevine, lilac, cherry, laurel, Forsythia, Rhus, Pistacia, apple, pear, plum and peach leaves, but foodplants differ from species to species.","answer1":"No","answer2":"Yes","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Antherina is a monotypic moth genus in the family Saturniidae erected by William Elford Leach in 1815\nThe larvae of Antherina feed on oleander, privet, willows, beech, Liquidambar, Crataegus (hawthorns), grapevine, lilac, cherry, laurel, Forsythia, Rhus, Pistacia, apple, pear, plum and peach leaves, but foodplants differ from species to species.","ref_answer":"No|Yes","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Antherina","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Antherina"}
{"question_ID":58,"question":"How many specials does Antherina have?","context1":"Antherina is a monotypic moth genus in the family Saturniidae erected by William Elford Leach in 1815","context2":"The larvae of Antherina feed on oleander, privet, willows, beech, Liquidambar, Crataegus (hawthorns), grapevine, lilac, cherry, laurel, Forsythia, Rhus, Pistacia, apple, pear, plum and peach leaves, but foodplants differ from species to species.","answer1":"One","answer2":"More than one","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Antherina is a monotypic moth genus in the family Saturniidae erected by William Elford Leach in 1815\nThe larvae of Antherina feed on oleander, privet, willows, beech, Liquidambar, Crataegus (hawthorns), grapevine, lilac, cherry, laurel, Forsythia, Rhus, Pistacia, apple, pear, plum and peach leaves, but foodplants differ from species to species.","ref_answer":"One|More than one","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Antherina","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Antherina"}
{"question_ID":61,"question":"Michael J. Murray (a.k.a. Valgard Murray) of Arizona, a former vice-president of Else Christensen's Odinist Fellowship. Did Valgard Murray make contact with Else Christensen in 1969 or before 1969?","context1":"In 1969, Valgard Murray worked with Else Christensen to found the Odinist Fellowship, and served as vice president.","context2":"In the early 1970s Valgard Murray and Elton Hall formed a kindred and made contact with Else Christensen.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"In 1969, Valgard Murray worked with Else Christensen to found the Odinist Fellowship, and served as vice president.\nIn the early 1970s Valgard Murray and Elton Hall formed a kindred and made contact with Else Christensen.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"\u00c1satr\u00fa Alliance","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/\u00c1satr\u00fa_Alliance"}
{"question_ID":60,"question":"Michael J. Murray (a.k.a. Valgard Murray) of Arizona, a former vice-president of Else Christensen's Odinist Fellowship. When did Valgard Murray make contact with Else Christensen?","context1":"In 1969, Valgard Murray worked with Else Christensen to found the Odinist Fellowship, and served as vice president.","context2":"In the early 1970s Valgard Murray and Elton Hall formed a kindred and made contact with Else Christensen.","answer1":"1969 or before 1969","answer2":"In the early 1970s","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"In 1969, Valgard Murray worked with Else Christensen to found the Odinist Fellowship, and served as vice president.\nIn the early 1970s Valgard Murray and Elton Hall formed a kindred and made contact with Else Christensen.","ref_answer":"1969 or before 1969|In the early 1970s","WikipediaArticleTitle":"\u00c1satr\u00fa Alliance","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/\u00c1satr\u00fa_Alliance"}
{"question_ID":63,"question":"Did Birmingham have more than 40,000 back-to-back houses in 1959?","context1":"By 1959, Leeds and Birmingham each had 60,000 back-to-back houses, and Members of Parliament were calling for the demolition to be accelerated.","context2":"Following the Second World War and the Blitz aerial bombing of industrial cities, Britain was ready for a new wave of slum demolition and construction of more suitable housing. For example, Birmingham had about 40,000 back-to-backs in 1931 but only 29,182 by September 1946.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"By 1959, Leeds and Birmingham each had 60,000 back-to-back houses, and Members of Parliament were calling for the demolition to be accelerated.\nFollowing the Second World War and the Blitz aerial bombing of industrial cities, Britain was ready for a new wave of slum demolition and construction of more suitable housing. For example, Birmingham had about 40,000 back-to-backs in 1931 but only 29,182 by September 1946.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Back-to-back house","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Back-to-back_house"}
{"question_ID":62,"question":"Did Birmingham have more than 29,182 back-to-back houses in 1959?","context1":"By 1959, Leeds and Birmingham each had 60,000 back-to-back houses, and Members of Parliament were calling for the demolition to be accelerated.","context2":"Following the Second World War and the Blitz aerial bombing of industrial cities, Britain was ready for a new wave of slum demolition and construction of more suitable housing. For example, Birmingham had about 40,000 back-to-backs in 1931 but only 29,182 by September 1946.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"By 1959, Leeds and Birmingham each had 60,000 back-to-back houses, and Members of Parliament were calling for the demolition to be accelerated.\nFollowing the Second World War and the Blitz aerial bombing of industrial cities, Britain was ready for a new wave of slum demolition and construction of more suitable housing. For example, Birmingham had about 40,000 back-to-backs in 1931 but only 29,182 by September 1946.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Back-to-back house","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Back-to-back_house"}
{"question_ID":65,"question":"Marina Augusta Pepper also called Marina Baker is an English Liberal Democrat local politician, journalist. Was Marina Baker born on 8 December 1967?","context1":"Marina Baker was born on 8 December 1967.","context2":"Marina Augusta Baker was born on 12 August 1967 (age 56).","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Marina Baker was born on 8 December 1967.\nMarina Augusta Baker was born on 12 August 1967 (age 56).","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Marina Baker","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Marina_Baker"}
{"question_ID":64,"question":"Marina Augusta Pepper also called Marina Baker is an English Liberal Democrat local politician, journalist. When was Marina Baker born?","context1":"Marina Baker was born on 8 December 1967.","context2":"Marina Augusta Baker was born on 12 August 1967 (age 56).","answer1":"8 December 1967","answer2":"12 August 1967","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Marina Baker was born on 8 December 1967.\nMarina Augusta Baker was born on 12 August 1967 (age 56).","ref_answer":"8 December 1967|12 August 1967","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Marina Baker","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Marina_Baker"}
{"question_ID":67,"question":"When did Adolph James Rode change his name to Cesar Francesco Barone? ","context1":"In 1980, now under the name Cesar Francesco Barone, Adolph James Rode was sentenced again for several burglaries and imprisoned.","context2":"Released in 1987 after seven years in detention, Adolph James Rode moved to Washington state with his girlfriend Kathi Scarbrough, whom he met in prison. Shortly after, Adolph James Rode decided to rename himself Cesar Francesco Barone.","answer1":"1980 or before 1980","answer2":"1987 or after 1987","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"In 1980, now under the name Cesar Francesco Barone, Adolph James Rode was sentenced again for several burglaries and imprisoned.\nReleased in 1987 after seven years in detention, Adolph James Rode moved to Washington state with his girlfriend Kathi Scarbrough, whom he met in prison. Shortly after, Adolph James Rode decided to rename himself Cesar Francesco Barone.","ref_answer":"1980 or before 1980|1987 or after 1987","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Cesar Barone","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Cesar_Barone"}
{"question_ID":66,"question":"When Adolph James Rode was sentenced again for several burglaries and imprisoned in 1980, was he under the name Cesar Francesco Barone?","context1":"In 1980, now under the name Cesar Francesco Barone, Adolph James Rode was sentenced again for several burglaries and imprisoned.","context2":"Released in 1987 after seven years in detention, Adolph James Rode moved to Washington state with his girlfriend Kathi Scarbrough, whom he met in prison. Shortly after, Adolph James Rode decided to rename himself Cesar Francesco Barone.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"In 1980, now under the name Cesar Francesco Barone, Adolph James Rode was sentenced again for several burglaries and imprisoned.\nReleased in 1987 after seven years in detention, Adolph James Rode moved to Washington state with his girlfriend Kathi Scarbrough, whom he met in prison. Shortly after, Adolph James Rode decided to rename himself Cesar Francesco Barone.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Cesar Barone","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Cesar_Barone"}
{"question_ID":69,"question":"Did the formation of the Belogradchik Rocks start about 230 million years ago? ","context1":"The formation of the Belogradchik Rocks started during the Permian period, about 230 million years ago, when the tectonic cycle was folding to create the Balkan Mountains and elevating the region of Belogradchik.","context2":"The formation of the Belogradchik Rocks started during the Permian period, about 230 million years ago, when the tectonic cycle was folding to create the Balkan Mountains and elevating the region of Belogradchik.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"The formation of the Belogradchik Rocks started during the Permian period, about 230 million years ago, when the tectonic cycle was folding to create the Balkan Mountains and elevating the region of Belogradchik.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Belogradchik Rocks","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Belogradchik_Rocks"}
{"question_ID":68,"question":"Did the formation of the Belogradchik Rocks start during the Permian period?","context1":"The formation of the Belogradchik Rocks started during the Permian period, about 230 million years ago, when the tectonic cycle was folding to create the Balkan Mountains and elevating the region of Belogradchik.","context2":"The formation of the Belogradchik Rocks started during the Permian period, about 230 million years ago, when the tectonic cycle was folding to create the Balkan Mountains and elevating the region of Belogradchik.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"The formation of the Belogradchik Rocks started during the Permian period, about 230 million years ago, when the tectonic cycle was folding to create the Balkan Mountains and elevating the region of Belogradchik.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Belogradchik Rocks","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Belogradchik_Rocks"}
{"question_ID":71,"question":"Is the maximum firing range of the Blaster (flamethrower) more than 2 meters (6 ft 7 in)?","context1":"The Blaster was a liquefied petroleum gas flamethrower installed along the sides of the vehicle under the doors. Should a group of carjackers suddenly attack the vehicle while it is stopped in traffic (the typical scenario), the occupant could flip a switch and direct 5-metre (16 ft) plumes of flame upward into the facial area of anyone trying to enter the vehicle through the doors or windows.","context2":"The maximum firing range of the Blaster (flamethrower) is 2 meters (6 ft 7 in) flame.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"The Blaster was a liquefied petroleum gas flamethrower installed along the sides of the vehicle under the doors. Should a group of carjackers suddenly attack the vehicle while it is stopped in traffic (the typical scenario), the occupant could flip a switch and direct 5-metre (16 ft) plumes of flame upward into the facial area of anyone trying to enter the vehicle through the doors or windows.\nThe maximum firing range of the Blaster (flamethrower) is 2 meters (6 ft 7 in) flame.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Blaster (flamethrower)","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Blaster_(flamethrower)"}
{"question_ID":70,"question":"What is the maximum firing range of the Blaster (flamethrower)?","context1":"The Blaster was a liquefied petroleum gas flamethrower installed along the sides of the vehicle under the doors. Should a group of carjackers suddenly attack the vehicle while it is stopped in traffic (the typical scenario), the occupant could flip a switch and direct 5-metre (16 ft) plumes of flame upward into the facial area of anyone trying to enter the vehicle through the doors or windows.","context2":"The maximum firing range of the Blaster (flamethrower) is 2 meters (6 ft 7 in) flame.","answer1":"5-metre (16 ft)","answer2":"2 meters (6 ft 7 in)","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"The Blaster was a liquefied petroleum gas flamethrower installed along the sides of the vehicle under the doors. Should a group of carjackers suddenly attack the vehicle while it is stopped in traffic (the typical scenario), the occupant could flip a switch and direct 5-metre (16 ft) plumes of flame upward into the facial area of anyone trying to enter the vehicle through the doors or windows.\nThe maximum firing range of the Blaster (flamethrower) is 2 meters (6 ft 7 in) flame.","ref_answer":"5-metre (16 ft)|2 meters (6 ft 7 in)","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Blaster (flamethrower)","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Blaster_(flamethrower)"}
{"question_ID":73,"question":"When was the first production of Boeing-Saab T-7 rolled out?","context1":"On 18 May 2023 the Government Accountability Office released a report on the Boeing-Saab T-7 program detailing problems with the software and safety systems and other delays that saw the USAF delay a production decision to February 2025","context2":"The first production of Boeing-Saab T-7 was rolled out on 28 April 2022.","answer1":"The production decision will be made on February 2025","answer2":"28 April 2022","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"On 18 May 2023 the Government Accountability Office released a report on the Boeing-Saab T-7 program detailing problems with the software and safety systems and other delays that saw the USAF delay a production decision to February 2025\nThe first production of Boeing-Saab T-7 was rolled out on 28 April 2022.","ref_answer":"The production decision will be made on February 2025|28 April 2022","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Boeing\u2013Saab T-7 Red Hawk","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Boeing\u2013Saab_T-7_Red_Hawk"}
{"question_ID":72,"question":"Was the first production of Boeing-Saab T-7 rolled out before February 2025?","context1":"On 18 May 2023 the Government Accountability Office released a report on the Boeing-Saab T-7 program detailing problems with the software and safety systems and other delays that saw the USAF delay a production decision to February 2025","context2":"The first production of Boeing-Saab T-7 was rolled out on 28 April 2022.","answer1":"No","answer2":"Yes","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"On 18 May 2023 the Government Accountability Office released a report on the Boeing-Saab T-7 program detailing problems with the software and safety systems and other delays that saw the USAF delay a production decision to February 2025\nThe first production of Boeing-Saab T-7 was rolled out on 28 April 2022.","ref_answer":"No|Yes","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Boeing\u2013Saab T-7 Red Hawk","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Boeing\u2013Saab_T-7_Red_Hawk"}
{"question_ID":74,"question":"David Brady, an Irish former Gaelic footballer who played for the Mayo county team in midfield in the 1990s and 2000s. What was his job in 2020?","context1":"David Brady, an Irish former Gaelic footballer who played for the Mayo county team in midfield in the 1990s and 2000s, works as a medical sales rep in 2020.","context2":"David Brady (born 1974) is an Irish former Gaelic footballer who played for the Mayo county team in midfield in the 1990s and 2000s. As of 2020, he works as a journalist.","answer1":"medical sales rep","answer2":"journalist","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"David Brady, an Irish former Gaelic footballer who played for the Mayo county team in midfield in the 1990s and 2000s, works as a medical sales rep in 2020.\nDavid Brady (born 1974) is an Irish former Gaelic footballer who played for the Mayo county team in midfield in the 1990s and 2000s. As of 2020, he works as a journalist.","ref_answer":"medical sales rep|journalist","WikipediaArticleTitle":"David Brady","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/David_Brady"}
{"question_ID":76,"question":"Is Tregaron estate bigger than 20 acres?","context1":"Joseph E. Davies and his wife bought the Tregaron estate in 1940. After Davies's death in 1958, the Washington International School purchased 6 acres (24,000 m2) of the 20 acres (81,000 m2), and the Tregaron Limited Partnership, an Israeli corporation, purchased the remaining 14 acres (57,000 m2).","context2":"The Tregaron estate covers 20.5 acres (83,000 m2).","answer1":"No","answer2":"Yes","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Joseph E. Davies and his wife bought the Tregaron estate in 1940. After Davies's death in 1958, the Washington International School purchased 6 acres (24,000 m2) of the 20 acres (81,000 m2), and the Tregaron Limited Partnership, an Israeli corporation, purchased the remaining 14 acres (57,000 m2).\nThe Tregaron estate covers 20.5 acres (83,000 m2).","ref_answer":"No|Yes","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Tregaron Estate","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Tregaron_Estate"}
{"question_ID":75,"question":"How large is the Tregaron estate in both acres and square meters?","context1":"Joseph E. Davies and his wife bought the Tregaron estate in 1940. After Davies's death in 1958, the Washington International School purchased 6 acres (24,000 m2) of the 20 acres (81,000 m2), and the Tregaron Limited Partnership, an Israeli corporation, purchased the remaining 14 acres (57,000 m2).","context2":"The Tregaron estate covers 20.5 acres (83,000 m2).","answer1":"20 acres (81,000 m2)","answer2":"20.5 acres (83,000 m2)","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Joseph E. Davies and his wife bought the Tregaron estate in 1940. After Davies's death in 1958, the Washington International School purchased 6 acres (24,000 m2) of the 20 acres (81,000 m2), and the Tregaron Limited Partnership, an Israeli corporation, purchased the remaining 14 acres (57,000 m2).\nThe Tregaron estate covers 20.5 acres (83,000 m2).","ref_answer":"20 acres (81,000 m2)|20.5 acres (83,000 m2)","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Tregaron Estate","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Tregaron_Estate"}
{"question_ID":77,"question":"Is CD19 expressed in human plasma cells?","context1":"CD19 is expressed on all normal, mitogen-stimulated, and malignant B cells, excluding plasma cells.","context2":"Contrary to some early doubts, human plasma cells do express CD19, as confirmed by others.","answer1":"No","answer2":"Yes","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"CD19 is expressed on all normal, mitogen-stimulated, and malignant B cells, excluding plasma cells.\nContrary to some early doubts, human plasma cells do express CD19, as confirmed by others.","ref_answer":"No|Yes","WikipediaArticleTitle":"CD19","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/CD19"}
{"question_ID":79,"question":"Does more than two monks know the secret recipe of Chartreuse?","context1":"The exact recipes for all forms of Chartreuse remain trade secrets and are known at any given time only to the three monks who prepare the herbal mixture. ","context2":"Today, the Chartreuse liqueurs are produced using the herbal mixture prepared by two monks at Grande Chartreuse. They are the only ones to know the secret recipe.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"The exact recipes for all forms of Chartreuse remain trade secrets and are known at any given time only to the three monks who prepare the herbal mixture. \nToday, the Chartreuse liqueurs are produced using the herbal mixture prepared by two monks at Grande Chartreuse. They are the only ones to know the secret recipe.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Chartreuse (liqueur)","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Chartreuse_(liqueur)"}
{"question_ID":78,"question":"How many monks know the secret recipe of Chartreuse?","context1":"The exact recipes for all forms of Chartreuse remain trade secrets and are known at any given time only to the three monks who prepare the herbal mixture. ","context2":"Today, the Chartreuse liqueurs are produced using the herbal mixture prepared by two monks at Grande Chartreuse. They are the only ones to know the secret recipe.","answer1":"Three","answer2":"Two","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"The exact recipes for all forms of Chartreuse remain trade secrets and are known at any given time only to the three monks who prepare the herbal mixture. \nToday, the Chartreuse liqueurs are produced using the herbal mixture prepared by two monks at Grande Chartreuse. They are the only ones to know the secret recipe.","ref_answer":"Three|Two","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Chartreuse (liqueur)","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Chartreuse_(liqueur)"}
{"question_ID":81,"question":"As of 2011, are more than 47, 195 convenience stores located at fuel stations in US?","context1":"In 2011, of the 150,000 convenience stores in US, 120,000 of them are located at fuel stations, which sell approximately 80 percent of the fuels purchased in the country.","context2":"In 2011, there were approximately 47,195 gas stations in US with convenience stores that generated $326 billion in revenue.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"In 2011, of the 150,000 convenience stores in US, 120,000 of them are located at fuel stations, which sell approximately 80 percent of the fuels purchased in the country.\nIn 2011, there were approximately 47,195 gas stations in US with convenience stores that generated $326 billion in revenue.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Convenience store","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Convenience_store"}
{"question_ID":80,"question":"In 2011, how many convenience stores are located at fuel stations in US?","context1":"In 2011, of the 150,000 convenience stores in US, 120,000 of them are located at fuel stations, which sell approximately 80 percent of the fuels purchased in the country.","context2":"In 2011, there were approximately 47,195 gas stations in US with convenience stores that generated $326 billion in revenue.","answer1":"120,000","answer2":"47,195","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"In 2011, of the 150,000 convenience stores in US, 120,000 of them are located at fuel stations, which sell approximately 80 percent of the fuels purchased in the country.\nIn 2011, there were approximately 47,195 gas stations in US with convenience stores that generated $326 billion in revenue.","ref_answer":"120,000|47,195","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Convenience store","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Convenience_store"}
{"question_ID":83,"question":"Dilnigar Ilhamjan, also known as Dinigeer Yilamujiang, is a Chinese cross-country skier of Uyghur ethnicity, born in Altay, Xinjiang. Did Dinigeer Yilamujiang started learn to ski before 2013?","context1":"Originally competing as a track and field athlete, Dinigeer Yilamujiang started learning to ski when she was 12. She primarily pursued cross-country skiing initially as a hobby before transforming herself into an elite-level competitor. She took part in local events in 2012 and later engaged in competitive skiing events.","context2":"Dinigeer Yilamujiang was born on May 3, 2001. Originally competing as a track and field athlete, she started learning to ski when she was 12.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Originally competing as a track and field athlete, Dinigeer Yilamujiang started learning to ski when she was 12. She primarily pursued cross-country skiing initially as a hobby before transforming herself into an elite-level competitor. She took part in local events in 2012 and later engaged in competitive skiing events.\nDinigeer Yilamujiang was born on May 3, 2001. Originally competing as a track and field athlete, she started learning to ski when she was 12.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Dinigeer Yilamujiang","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Dinigeer_Yilamujiang"}
{"question_ID":82,"question":"Dilnigar Ilhamjan, also known as Dinigeer Yilamujiang, is a Chinese cross-country skier of Uyghur ethnicity, born in Altay, Xinjiang. When did Dinigeer Yilamujiang start to learn to ski?","context1":"Originally competing as a track and field athlete, Dinigeer Yilamujiang started learning to ski when she was 12. She primarily pursued cross-country skiing initially as a hobby before transforming herself into an elite-level competitor. She took part in local events in 2012 and later engaged in competitive skiing events.","context2":"Dinigeer Yilamujiang was born on May 3, 2001. Originally competing as a track and field athlete, she started learning to ski when she was 12.","answer1":"before 2012 or 2012","answer2":"2013","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Originally competing as a track and field athlete, Dinigeer Yilamujiang started learning to ski when she was 12. She primarily pursued cross-country skiing initially as a hobby before transforming herself into an elite-level competitor. She took part in local events in 2012 and later engaged in competitive skiing events.\nDinigeer Yilamujiang was born on May 3, 2001. Originally competing as a track and field athlete, she started learning to ski when she was 12.","ref_answer":"before 2012 or 2012|2013","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Dinigeer Yilamujiang","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Dinigeer_Yilamujiang"}
{"question_ID":85,"question":"Sir Charles D'Oyly, 7th Baronet (1781\u20131845), was a British public official and painter from Dacca (now Dhaka). When was Charles D'Oyly married?","context1":"Charles D'Oyly sketched incessantly and took an active interest in the arts generally, finding these leisure pursuits to be an agreeable way to relieve the boredom associated with colonial life. He produced landscapes, scenes of Indian life, portraits, and caricatures, primarily in watercolour, and also wrote satirical verse. His work was influenced by his friend, the painter, George Chinnery, who stayed with D\u2019Oyly and his wife in Dacca in 1802\u201303.","context2":"Charles D'Oyly went to England with the family in 1785 and received his first formal education there. In 1798 he returned to India as Assistant to the Registrar in the Court of Appeal in Calcutta. In 1803 he was appointed Keeper of the Records in the Governor General's office, and in 1805, he married his cousin, Marian Greer, daughter of William Greer.","answer1":"Before 1802 or 1802","answer2":"1805","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Charles D'Oyly sketched incessantly and took an active interest in the arts generally, finding these leisure pursuits to be an agreeable way to relieve the boredom associated with colonial life. He produced landscapes, scenes of Indian life, portraits, and caricatures, primarily in watercolour, and also wrote satirical verse. His work was influenced by his friend, the painter, George Chinnery, who stayed with D\u2019Oyly and his wife in Dacca in 1802\u201303.\nCharles D'Oyly went to England with the family in 1785 and received his first formal education there. In 1798 he returned to India as Assistant to the Registrar in the Court of Appeal in Calcutta. In 1803 he was appointed Keeper of the Records in the Governor General's office, and in 1805, he married his cousin, Marian Greer, daughter of William Greer.","ref_answer":"Before 1802 or 1802|1805","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Charles D'Oyly","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Charles_D'Oyly"}
{"question_ID":84,"question":"Sir Charles D'Oyly, 7th Baronet (1781\u20131845), was a British public official and painter from Dacca (now Dhaka). Was Charles D'Oyly married in 1803?","context1":"Charles D'Oyly sketched incessantly and took an active interest in the arts generally, finding these leisure pursuits to be an agreeable way to relieve the boredom associated with colonial life. He produced landscapes, scenes of Indian life, portraits, and caricatures, primarily in watercolour, and also wrote satirical verse. His work was influenced by his friend, the painter, George Chinnery, who stayed with D\u2019Oyly and his wife in Dacca in 1802\u201303.","context2":"Charles D'Oyly went to England with the family in 1785 and received his first formal education there. In 1798 he returned to India as Assistant to the Registrar in the Court of Appeal in Calcutta. In 1803 he was appointed Keeper of the Records in the Governor General's office, and in 1805, he married his cousin, Marian Greer, daughter of William Greer.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Charles D'Oyly sketched incessantly and took an active interest in the arts generally, finding these leisure pursuits to be an agreeable way to relieve the boredom associated with colonial life. He produced landscapes, scenes of Indian life, portraits, and caricatures, primarily in watercolour, and also wrote satirical verse. His work was influenced by his friend, the painter, George Chinnery, who stayed with D\u2019Oyly and his wife in Dacca in 1802\u201303.\nCharles D'Oyly went to England with the family in 1785 and received his first formal education there. In 1798 he returned to India as Assistant to the Registrar in the Court of Appeal in Calcutta. In 1803 he was appointed Keeper of the Records in the Governor General's office, and in 1805, he married his cousin, Marian Greer, daughter of William Greer.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Charles D'Oyly","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Charles_D'Oyly"}
{"question_ID":87,"question":"As of 2023, has Emperor released more than one live albums? ","context1":"Emperor has released four studio albums, two live albums, six EPs, two DVDs and three compilation albums.","context2":"Live albums\t1; Live albums - Emperial Live Ceremony, Live at Wacken Open Air 2006, Live Inferno","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Emperor has released four studio albums, two live albums, six EPs, two DVDs and three compilation albums.\nLive albums\t1; Live albums - Emperial Live Ceremony, Live at Wacken Open Air 2006, Live Inferno","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Emperor discography","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Emperor_discography"}
{"question_ID":86,"question":"As of 2023, how many live albums has Emperor released?","context1":"Emperor has released four studio albums, two live albums, six EPs, two DVDs and three compilation albums.","context2":"Live albums\t1; Live albums - Emperial Live Ceremony, Live at Wacken Open Air 2006, Live Inferno","answer1":"two","answer2":"One","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Emperor has released four studio albums, two live albums, six EPs, two DVDs and three compilation albums.\nLive albums\t1; Live albums - Emperial Live Ceremony, Live at Wacken Open Air 2006, Live Inferno","ref_answer":"two|One","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Emperor discography","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Emperor_discography"}
{"question_ID":89,"question":"Did Mari Fitzduff found Mediation Northern Ireland in 1988?","context1":"Mari Fitzduff began professional peacebuilding work in 1986. Living in Northern Ireland during the conflict in 1969-1998, she set up the first courses in conflict resolution and mediation in both Queen's University Belfast and Ulster University. She went on to found Mediation Northern Ireland in 1988, an organisation which trained and supplied mediators for community and political mediations throughout Northern Ireland in the context of the conflict.","context2":"Mari Christine Fitzduff (born March 15, 1947 in Dublin) is an Irish policy maker, writer and academic. She began her work in peacebuilding and mediation working with universities during the Northern Ireland conflict before setting up a mediation organisation in 1989.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Mari Fitzduff began professional peacebuilding work in 1986. Living in Northern Ireland during the conflict in 1969-1998, she set up the first courses in conflict resolution and mediation in both Queen's University Belfast and Ulster University. She went on to found Mediation Northern Ireland in 1988, an organisation which trained and supplied mediators for community and political mediations throughout Northern Ireland in the context of the conflict.\nMari Christine Fitzduff (born March 15, 1947 in Dublin) is an Irish policy maker, writer and academic. She began her work in peacebuilding and mediation working with universities during the Northern Ireland conflict before setting up a mediation organisation in 1989.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Mari Fitzduff","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Mari_Fitzduff"}
{"question_ID":88,"question":"When did Mari Fitzduff found Mediation Northern Ireland?","context1":"Mari Fitzduff began professional peacebuilding work in 1986. Living in Northern Ireland during the conflict in 1969-1998, she set up the first courses in conflict resolution and mediation in both Queen's University Belfast and Ulster University. She went on to found Mediation Northern Ireland in 1988, an organisation which trained and supplied mediators for community and political mediations throughout Northern Ireland in the context of the conflict.","context2":"Mari Christine Fitzduff (born March 15, 1947 in Dublin) is an Irish policy maker, writer and academic. She began her work in peacebuilding and mediation working with universities during the Northern Ireland conflict before setting up a mediation organisation in 1989.","answer1":"1988","answer2":"1989","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Mari Fitzduff began professional peacebuilding work in 1986. Living in Northern Ireland during the conflict in 1969-1998, she set up the first courses in conflict resolution and mediation in both Queen's University Belfast and Ulster University. She went on to found Mediation Northern Ireland in 1988, an organisation which trained and supplied mediators for community and political mediations throughout Northern Ireland in the context of the conflict.\nMari Christine Fitzduff (born March 15, 1947 in Dublin) is an Irish policy maker, writer and academic. She began her work in peacebuilding and mediation working with universities during the Northern Ireland conflict before setting up a mediation organisation in 1989.","ref_answer":"1988|1989","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Mari Fitzduff","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Mari_Fitzduff"}
{"question_ID":91,"question":"Is the bore of the pistols that are typically used in the Second World War longer than one inch?","context1":"The Very pistol, typical of the type used in the Second World War, are of one inch bore (26.5mm), now known as \"Calibre 4\" for signal pistols. ","context2":"The Very pistol, typical of the type used in the Second World War, are of one inch bore (26.5mm), now known as \"Calibre 4\" for signal pistols. ","answer1":"No","answer2":"Yes","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"The Very pistol, typical of the type used in the Second World War, are of one inch bore (26.5mm), now known as \"Calibre 4\" for signal pistols. ","ref_answer":"No|Yes","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Flare gun","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Flare_gun"}
{"question_ID":90,"question":"How long is the bore of the pistols that are typically used in the Second World War?","context1":"The Very pistol, typical of the type used in the Second World War, are of one inch bore (26.5mm), now known as \"Calibre 4\" for signal pistols. ","context2":"The Very pistol, typical of the type used in the Second World War, are of one inch bore (26.5mm), now known as \"Calibre 4\" for signal pistols. ","answer1":"One inch","answer2":"26.5 mm","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"The Very pistol, typical of the type used in the Second World War, are of one inch bore (26.5mm), now known as \"Calibre 4\" for signal pistols. ","ref_answer":"One inch|26.5 mm","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Flare gun","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Flare_gun"}
{"question_ID":93,"question":"During the Battle of Fort \u00c9ben-\u00c9mael, how many troops were deployed by the German army using the gliders in the attack?","context1":" During the battle of Fort \u00c9ben-\u00c9mael, for reasons of security, Sturmabteilung Walter Koch was dispersed around several locations in the Rhineland until it received orders for the operation against Fort \u00c9ben-\u00c9mael and the three bridges to begin. Preliminary orders were received on 9 May, ordering the separated detachments to move to a pre-arranged concentration area, and shortly afterwards a second order arrived, informing the assault force that Fall Gelb was to begin at 05:25 on 10 May. The Fallschirmj\u00e4ger filed onto a non-illuminated tarmac at 03:00, as the loudspeakers played Richard Wagner's \"Ride of the Valkyries\". At 04:30, forty-two gliders carrying the 493 airborne troops that formed the assault force were lifted off from two airfields in Cologne, the armada of gliders and transport aircraft turning south towards their objectives.","context2":"To prepare for the battle of Fort \u00c9ben-\u00c9mael, Hauptmann Walter Koch divided his force into four assault groups. Group Granite, under Oberleutnant Rudolf Witzig, composed of eighty-five men in eleven gliders whose task would be to assault and capture Fort \u00c9ben-\u00c9mael; Group Steel, commanded by Oberleutnant Gustav Altmann, and formed of ninety-two men and nine gliders, would capture the Veldwezelt bridge; Group Concrete, commanded by Leutnant Gerhard Schacht and composed of ninety-six men in eleven gliders, would capture the Vroenhoven bridge; and Group Iron, under Leutnant Martin Sch\u00e4chter, composed of ninety men in ten gliders, who would capture the Kanne bridge.","answer1":"493","answer2":"363","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":" During the battle of Fort \u00c9ben-\u00c9mael, for reasons of security, Sturmabteilung Walter Koch was dispersed around several locations in the Rhineland until it received orders for the operation against Fort \u00c9ben-\u00c9mael and the three bridges to begin. Preliminary orders were received on 9 May, ordering the separated detachments to move to a pre-arranged concentration area, and shortly afterwards a second order arrived, informing the assault force that Fall Gelb was to begin at 05:25 on 10 May. The Fallschirmj\u00e4ger filed onto a non-illuminated tarmac at 03:00, as the loudspeakers played Richard Wagner's \"Ride of the Valkyries\". At 04:30, forty-two gliders carrying the 493 airborne troops that formed the assault force were lifted off from two airfields in Cologne, the armada of gliders and transport aircraft turning south towards their objectives.\nTo prepare for the battle of Fort \u00c9ben-\u00c9mael, Hauptmann Walter Koch divided his force into four assault groups. Group Granite, under Oberleutnant Rudolf Witzig, composed of eighty-five men in eleven gliders whose task would be to assault and capture Fort \u00c9ben-\u00c9mael; Group Steel, commanded by Oberleutnant Gustav Altmann, and formed of ninety-two men and nine gliders, would capture the Veldwezelt bridge; Group Concrete, commanded by Leutnant Gerhard Schacht and composed of ninety-six men in eleven gliders, would capture the Vroenhoven bridge; and Group Iron, under Leutnant Martin Sch\u00e4chter, composed of ninety men in ten gliders, who would capture the Kanne bridge.","ref_answer":"493|363","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Battle of Fort \u00c9ben-\u00c9mael","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Battle_of_Fort_\u00c9ben-\u00c9mael"}
{"question_ID":92,"question":"During the Battle of Fort \u00c9ben-\u00c9mael, how many gliders were used by the German army in the attack?","context1":" During the battle of Fort \u00c9ben-\u00c9mael, for reasons of security, Sturmabteilung Walter Koch was dispersed around several locations in the Rhineland until it received orders for the operation against Fort \u00c9ben-\u00c9mael and the three bridges to begin. Preliminary orders were received on 9 May, ordering the separated detachments to move to a pre-arranged concentration area, and shortly afterwards a second order arrived, informing the assault force that Fall Gelb was to begin at 05:25 on 10 May. The Fallschirmj\u00e4ger filed onto a non-illuminated tarmac at 03:00, as the loudspeakers played Richard Wagner's \"Ride of the Valkyries\". At 04:30, forty-two gliders carrying the 493 airborne troops that formed the assault force were lifted off from two airfields in Cologne, the armada of gliders and transport aircraft turning south towards their objectives.","context2":"To prepare for the battle of Fort \u00c9ben-\u00c9mael, Hauptmann Walter Koch divided his force into four assault groups. Group Granite, under Oberleutnant Rudolf Witzig, composed of eighty-five men in eleven gliders whose task would be to assault and capture Fort \u00c9ben-\u00c9mael; Group Steel, commanded by Oberleutnant Gustav Altmann, and formed of ninety-two men and nine gliders, would capture the Veldwezelt bridge; Group Concrete, commanded by Leutnant Gerhard Schacht and composed of ninety-six men in eleven gliders, would capture the Vroenhoven bridge; and Group Iron, under Leutnant Martin Sch\u00e4chter, composed of ninety men in ten gliders, who would capture the Kanne bridge.","answer1":"42","answer2":"41","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":" During the battle of Fort \u00c9ben-\u00c9mael, for reasons of security, Sturmabteilung Walter Koch was dispersed around several locations in the Rhineland until it received orders for the operation against Fort \u00c9ben-\u00c9mael and the three bridges to begin. Preliminary orders were received on 9 May, ordering the separated detachments to move to a pre-arranged concentration area, and shortly afterwards a second order arrived, informing the assault force that Fall Gelb was to begin at 05:25 on 10 May. The Fallschirmj\u00e4ger filed onto a non-illuminated tarmac at 03:00, as the loudspeakers played Richard Wagner's \"Ride of the Valkyries\". At 04:30, forty-two gliders carrying the 493 airborne troops that formed the assault force were lifted off from two airfields in Cologne, the armada of gliders and transport aircraft turning south towards their objectives.\nTo prepare for the battle of Fort \u00c9ben-\u00c9mael, Hauptmann Walter Koch divided his force into four assault groups. Group Granite, under Oberleutnant Rudolf Witzig, composed of eighty-five men in eleven gliders whose task would be to assault and capture Fort \u00c9ben-\u00c9mael; Group Steel, commanded by Oberleutnant Gustav Altmann, and formed of ninety-two men and nine gliders, would capture the Veldwezelt bridge; Group Concrete, commanded by Leutnant Gerhard Schacht and composed of ninety-six men in eleven gliders, would capture the Vroenhoven bridge; and Group Iron, under Leutnant Martin Sch\u00e4chter, composed of ninety men in ten gliders, who would capture the Kanne bridge.","ref_answer":"42|41","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Battle of Fort \u00c9ben-\u00c9mael","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Battle_of_Fort_\u00c9ben-\u00c9mael"}
{"question_ID":95,"question":"Does Government College University in Lahore have more than five chairs?","context1":"In Government College University in Lahore, the following six chairs have been established at the respective departments: Allama Iqbal Chair in Philosophy, Gottlieb Wilhelm Leitner Chair in History, Syed Ali Hujwiri Chair in Persian, Ashfaq Ahmed Chair in Urdu, Sultan Ahmed Chair in Biological Sciences","context2":"In Government College University in Lahore, the following six chairs have been established at the respective departments: Allama Iqbal Chair in Philosophy, Gottlieb Wilhelm Leitner Chair in History, Syed Ali Hujwiri Chair in Persian, Ashfaq Ahmed Chair in Urdu, Sultan Ahmed Chair in Biological Sciences","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"In Government College University in Lahore, the following six chairs have been established at the respective departments: Allama Iqbal Chair in Philosophy, Gottlieb Wilhelm Leitner Chair in History, Syed Ali Hujwiri Chair in Persian, Ashfaq Ahmed Chair in Urdu, Sultan Ahmed Chair in Biological Sciences","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Government College University, Lahore","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Government_College_University,_Lahore"}
{"question_ID":94,"question":"How many chairs are established in Government College University in Lahore?","context1":"In Government College University in Lahore, the following six chairs have been established at the respective departments: Allama Iqbal Chair in Philosophy, Gottlieb Wilhelm Leitner Chair in History, Syed Ali Hujwiri Chair in Persian, Ashfaq Ahmed Chair in Urdu, Sultan Ahmed Chair in Biological Sciences","context2":"In Government College University in Lahore, the following six chairs have been established at the respective departments: Allama Iqbal Chair in Philosophy, Gottlieb Wilhelm Leitner Chair in History, Syed Ali Hujwiri Chair in Persian, Ashfaq Ahmed Chair in Urdu, Sultan Ahmed Chair in Biological Sciences","answer1":"Six","answer2":"Five","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"In Government College University in Lahore, the following six chairs have been established at the respective departments: Allama Iqbal Chair in Philosophy, Gottlieb Wilhelm Leitner Chair in History, Syed Ali Hujwiri Chair in Persian, Ashfaq Ahmed Chair in Urdu, Sultan Ahmed Chair in Biological Sciences","ref_answer":"Six|Five","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Government College University, Lahore","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Government_College_University,_Lahore"}
{"question_ID":97,"question":"Is Acid Cryptofiler a cryptographic software program?","context1":"Acid Cryptofiler is a cryptographic software program designed by the department for \"control of information\" (Centre d'Electronique de l'Armement) of the French General Directorate of Armament (Direction g\u00e9n\u00e9rale de l'armement). It is an online storage service. The software is now manufactured by ACID Technologies (France).","context2":"Acid Cryptofiler is a cryptographic software program designed by the department for \"control of information\" (Centre d'Electronique de l'Armement) of the French General Directorate of Armament (Direction g\u00e9n\u00e9rale de l'armement). It is an online storage service. The software is now manufactured by ACID Technologies (France).","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"Acid Cryptofiler is a cryptographic software program designed by the department for \"control of information\" (Centre d'Electronique de l'Armement) of the French General Directorate of Armament (Direction g\u00e9n\u00e9rale de l'armement). It is an online storage service. The software is now manufactured by ACID Technologies (France).","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Acid Cryptofiler","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Acid_Cryptofiler"}
{"question_ID":96,"question":"What is Acid Cryptofiler?","context1":"Acid Cryptofiler is a cryptographic software program designed by the department for \"control of information\" (Centre d'Electronique de l'Armement) of the French General Directorate of Armament (Direction g\u00e9n\u00e9rale de l'armement). It is an online storage service. The software is now manufactured by ACID Technologies (France).","context2":"Acid Cryptofiler is a cryptographic software program designed by the department for \"control of information\" (Centre d'Electronique de l'Armement) of the French General Directorate of Armament (Direction g\u00e9n\u00e9rale de l'armement). It is an online storage service. The software is now manufactured by ACID Technologies (France).","answer1":"Acid Cryptofiler is a cryptographic software program designed by the department for \"control of information\" (Centre d'Electronique de l'Armement) of the French General Directorate of Armament (Direction g\u00e9n\u00e9rale de l'armement)","answer2":"Acid Cryptofiler is an online storage service","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"Acid Cryptofiler is a cryptographic software program designed by the department for \"control of information\" (Centre d'Electronique de l'Armement) of the French General Directorate of Armament (Direction g\u00e9n\u00e9rale de l'armement). It is an online storage service. The software is now manufactured by ACID Technologies (France).","ref_answer":"Acid Cryptofiler is a cryptographic software program designed by the department for \"control of information\" (Centre d'Electronique de l'Armement) of the French General Directorate of Armament (Direction g\u00e9n\u00e9rale de l'armement)|Acid Cryptofiler is an online storage service","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Acid Cryptofiler","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Acid_Cryptofiler"}
{"question_ID":99,"question":"Is Azelaic acid a worse treatment for acne when compared to benzoyl peroxide?","context1":"Azelaic acid is effective for mild to moderate acne when applied topically at a 15\u201320% concentration. Treatment twice daily for six months is necessary, and is as effective as topical benzoyl peroxide 5%, isotretinoin 0.05%, and erythromycin 2%.","context2":"Azelaic acid also led to worse acne treatment response when compared to benzoyl peroxide. When compared to tretinoin, azelaic acid makes little or no treatment response.","answer1":"No","answer2":"Yes","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Azelaic acid is effective for mild to moderate acne when applied topically at a 15\u201320% concentration. Treatment twice daily for six months is necessary, and is as effective as topical benzoyl peroxide 5%, isotretinoin 0.05%, and erythromycin 2%.\nAzelaic acid also led to worse acne treatment response when compared to benzoyl peroxide. When compared to tretinoin, azelaic acid makes little or no treatment response.","ref_answer":"No|Yes","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Acne","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Acne"}
{"question_ID":98,"question":"Is Azelaic acid as effective as benzoyl peroxide when used to treat acne?","context1":"Azelaic acid is effective for mild to moderate acne when applied topically at a 15\u201320% concentration. Treatment twice daily for six months is necessary, and is as effective as topical benzoyl peroxide 5%, isotretinoin 0.05%, and erythromycin 2%.","context2":"Azelaic acid also led to worse acne treatment response when compared to benzoyl peroxide. When compared to tretinoin, azelaic acid makes little or no treatment response.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Azelaic acid is effective for mild to moderate acne when applied topically at a 15\u201320% concentration. Treatment twice daily for six months is necessary, and is as effective as topical benzoyl peroxide 5%, isotretinoin 0.05%, and erythromycin 2%.\nAzelaic acid also led to worse acne treatment response when compared to benzoyl peroxide. When compared to tretinoin, azelaic acid makes little or no treatment response.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Acne","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Acne"}
{"question_ID":101,"question":"Are stagnant pools of water the only breeding sites of Aedes albopictus?","context1":"Flowing water will not be a breeding spot for Aedes albopictus, and water that contains minnows is not usually a problem, because the fish eat the mosquito larvae.","context2":"The Aedes albopictus female lays her eggs near water, not directly into it as other mosquitoes do, but typically near a stagnant pool. However, any open container containing water will suffice for larvae development, even with less than one US fl oz (30 ml) of water. It can also breed in running water, so stagnant pools of water are not its only breeding sites. It is more likely to lay eggs in water sources near flowers than in water sources without flowers. It has a short flight range (less than 200 m (220 yd)), so breeding sites are likely to be close to where this mosquito is found.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Flowing water will not be a breeding spot for Aedes albopictus, and water that contains minnows is not usually a problem, because the fish eat the mosquito larvae.\nThe Aedes albopictus female lays her eggs near water, not directly into it as other mosquitoes do, but typically near a stagnant pool. However, any open container containing water will suffice for larvae development, even with less than one US fl oz (30 ml) of water. It can also breed in running water, so stagnant pools of water are not its only breeding sites. It is more likely to lay eggs in water sources near flowers than in water sources without flowers. It has a short flight range (less than 200 m (220 yd)), so breeding sites are likely to be close to where this mosquito is found.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Aedes albopictus","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Aedes_albopictus"}
{"question_ID":100,"question":"Can Aedes albopictus breed in running water?","context1":"Flowing water will not be a breeding spot for Aedes albopictus, and water that contains minnows is not usually a problem, because the fish eat the mosquito larvae.","context2":"The Aedes albopictus female lays her eggs near water, not directly into it as other mosquitoes do, but typically near a stagnant pool. However, any open container containing water will suffice for larvae development, even with less than one US fl oz (30 ml) of water. It can also breed in running water, so stagnant pools of water are not its only breeding sites. It is more likely to lay eggs in water sources near flowers than in water sources without flowers. It has a short flight range (less than 200 m (220 yd)), so breeding sites are likely to be close to where this mosquito is found.","answer1":"No","answer2":"Yes","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Flowing water will not be a breeding spot for Aedes albopictus, and water that contains minnows is not usually a problem, because the fish eat the mosquito larvae.\nThe Aedes albopictus female lays her eggs near water, not directly into it as other mosquitoes do, but typically near a stagnant pool. However, any open container containing water will suffice for larvae development, even with less than one US fl oz (30 ml) of water. It can also breed in running water, so stagnant pools of water are not its only breeding sites. It is more likely to lay eggs in water sources near flowers than in water sources without flowers. It has a short flight range (less than 200 m (220 yd)), so breeding sites are likely to be close to where this mosquito is found.","ref_answer":"No|Yes","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Aedes albopictus","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Aedes_albopictus"}
{"question_ID":103,"question":"Was Muhammad III of Alamut born in 1213?","context1":"Alauddin Muhammad, also known as Muhammad III of Alamut, was born in 1213.","context2":"\u02bfAl\u0101\u02be ad-D\u012bn Mu\u1e25ammad III (\u0639\u0644\u0627\u0621\u0627\u0644\u062f\u06cc\u0646 \u0645\u062d\u0645\u062f; 1211\u20131255), more commonly known as \u02bfAl\u0101\u02be ad-D\u012bn (\u0639\u0644\u0627\u0621\u0627\u0644\u062f\u06cc\u0646), son of Jal\u0101l al-D\u012bn \u1e24asan III, was the 26th Niz\u0101ri Isma'ilism Im\u0101m. ","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Alauddin Muhammad, also known as Muhammad III of Alamut, was born in 1213.\n\u02bfAl\u0101\u02be ad-D\u012bn Mu\u1e25ammad III (\u0639\u0644\u0627\u0621\u0627\u0644\u062f\u06cc\u0646 \u0645\u062d\u0645\u062f; 1211\u20131255), more commonly known as \u02bfAl\u0101\u02be ad-D\u012bn (\u0639\u0644\u0627\u0621\u0627\u0644\u062f\u06cc\u0646), son of Jal\u0101l al-D\u012bn \u1e24asan III, was the 26th Niz\u0101ri Isma'ilism Im\u0101m. ","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Muhammad III of Alamut","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Muhammad_III_of_Alamut"}
{"question_ID":102,"question":"When Muhammad III of Alamut was born?","context1":"Alauddin Muhammad, also known as Muhammad III of Alamut, was born in 1213.","context2":"\u02bfAl\u0101\u02be ad-D\u012bn Mu\u1e25ammad III (\u0639\u0644\u0627\u0621\u0627\u0644\u062f\u06cc\u0646 \u0645\u062d\u0645\u062f; 1211\u20131255), more commonly known as \u02bfAl\u0101\u02be ad-D\u012bn (\u0639\u0644\u0627\u0621\u0627\u0644\u062f\u06cc\u0646), son of Jal\u0101l al-D\u012bn \u1e24asan III, was the 26th Niz\u0101ri Isma'ilism Im\u0101m. ","answer1":"1213","answer2":"1211","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Alauddin Muhammad, also known as Muhammad III of Alamut, was born in 1213.\n\u02bfAl\u0101\u02be ad-D\u012bn Mu\u1e25ammad III (\u0639\u0644\u0627\u0621\u0627\u0644\u062f\u06cc\u0646 \u0645\u062d\u0645\u062f; 1211\u20131255), more commonly known as \u02bfAl\u0101\u02be ad-D\u012bn (\u0639\u0644\u0627\u0621\u0627\u0644\u062f\u06cc\u0646), son of Jal\u0101l al-D\u012bn \u1e24asan III, was the 26th Niz\u0101ri Isma'ilism Im\u0101m. ","ref_answer":"1213|1211","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Muhammad III of Alamut","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Muhammad_III_of_Alamut"}
{"question_ID":105,"question":"Is the operating speed of Lucknow\u2013Bandra Terminus Weekly Express 65 km\/h?","context1":"20921 Bandra Terminus\u2013Lucknow Weekly Express covers the distance of 1687 kilometres in 26 hours 5 mins (65 km\/h) and 1687 kilometres in 27 hours 5 mins (62 km\/h) as 20922 Lucknow\u2013Bandra Terminus Weekly Express. ","context2":"The operating speed of Bandra Terminus\u2013Lucknow Weekly Superfast Express is 65 km\/h (40 mph).","answer1":"No","answer2":"Yes","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"20921 Bandra Terminus\u2013Lucknow Weekly Express covers the distance of 1687 kilometres in 26 hours 5 mins (65 km\/h) and 1687 kilometres in 27 hours 5 mins (62 km\/h) as 20922 Lucknow\u2013Bandra Terminus Weekly Express. \nThe operating speed of Bandra Terminus\u2013Lucknow Weekly Superfast Express is 65 km\/h (40 mph).","ref_answer":"No|Yes","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Bandra Terminus\u2013Lucknow Weekly Superfast Express","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Bandra_Terminus\u2013Lucknow_Weekly_Superfast_Express"}
{"question_ID":104,"question":"What is the operating speed of Lucknow\u2013Bandra Terminus Weekly Express?","context1":"20921 Bandra Terminus\u2013Lucknow Weekly Express covers the distance of 1687 kilometres in 26 hours 5 mins (65 km\/h) and 1687 kilometres in 27 hours 5 mins (62 km\/h) as 20922 Lucknow\u2013Bandra Terminus Weekly Express. ","context2":"The operating speed of Bandra Terminus\u2013Lucknow Weekly Superfast Express is 65 km\/h (40 mph).","answer1":"62 km\/h","answer2":"65 km\/h (40 mph)","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"20921 Bandra Terminus\u2013Lucknow Weekly Express covers the distance of 1687 kilometres in 26 hours 5 mins (65 km\/h) and 1687 kilometres in 27 hours 5 mins (62 km\/h) as 20922 Lucknow\u2013Bandra Terminus Weekly Express. \nThe operating speed of Bandra Terminus\u2013Lucknow Weekly Superfast Express is 65 km\/h (40 mph).","ref_answer":"62 km\/h|65 km\/h (40 mph)","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Bandra Terminus\u2013Lucknow Weekly Superfast Express","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Bandra_Terminus\u2013Lucknow_Weekly_Superfast_Express"}
{"question_ID":107,"question":"Was Batman Province inhabited from the Paleolithic period?","context1":"Batman Province was inhabited from prehistoric times, likely from the Neolithic (Paleolithic) period, according to archeological evidence. ","context2":"Batman Province was inhabited from prehistoric times, likely from the Neolithic (Paleolithic) period, according to archeological evidence.","answer1":"No","answer2":"Yes","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"Batman Province was inhabited from prehistoric times, likely from the Neolithic (Paleolithic) period, according to archeological evidence. ","ref_answer":"No|Yes","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Batman, Turkey","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Batman,_Turkey"}
{"question_ID":106,"question":"Was Batman Province inhabited from the Neolithic period?","context1":"Batman Province was inhabited from prehistoric times, likely from the Neolithic (Paleolithic) period, according to archeological evidence. ","context2":"Batman Province was inhabited from prehistoric times, likely from the Neolithic (Paleolithic) period, according to archeological evidence.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"Batman Province was inhabited from prehistoric times, likely from the Neolithic (Paleolithic) period, according to archeological evidence. ","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Batman, Turkey","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Batman,_Turkey"}
{"question_ID":109,"question":"Did the Spanish Empire had 59 dead, 50 prisoners and 64 wounded in the Battle of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda?","context1":"In the first and bloodiest day (10th March 1814) of the Combate of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda, Jacinto de Romarate (frigate captain of Spanish royalist forces) successfully repelled the enemy's (forces of the United Provinces of the R\u00edo de la Plata) attack. They had 45 dead and 50 wounded. At 5:00 pm on 11th March 1814, Jacinto de Romarate sent a note to the commander of the Montevideo garrison Miguel de la Sierra (Spanish royalist), informing he had few casualties, four dead and seven wounded, he had disembarked on the island and judged that, given the losses suffered, as soon as the patriot fleet was in condition it would retreat to Buenos Aires. On 15th March 1814, the royalists had 10 dead, 7 wounded and 50 prisoners.","context2":"The Spanish Empire had 10 dead, 47 prisoners and 17 wounded in the Battle of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"In the first and bloodiest day (10th March 1814) of the Combate of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda, Jacinto de Romarate (frigate captain of Spanish royalist forces) successfully repelled the enemy's (forces of the United Provinces of the R\u00edo de la Plata) attack. They had 45 dead and 50 wounded. At 5:00 pm on 11th March 1814, Jacinto de Romarate sent a note to the commander of the Montevideo garrison Miguel de la Sierra (Spanish royalist), informing he had few casualties, four dead and seven wounded, he had disembarked on the island and judged that, given the losses suffered, as soon as the patriot fleet was in condition it would retreat to Buenos Aires. On 15th March 1814, the royalists had 10 dead, 7 wounded and 50 prisoners.\nThe Spanish Empire had 10 dead, 47 prisoners and 17 wounded in the Battle of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Battle of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Battle_of_Mart\u00edn_Garc\u00eda"}
{"question_ID":108,"question":"How many dead, prisoners and wounded did the Spanish Empire had in the Battle of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda?","context1":"In the first and bloodiest day (10th March 1814) of the Combate of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda, Jacinto de Romarate (frigate captain of Spanish royalist forces) successfully repelled the enemy's (forces of the United Provinces of the R\u00edo de la Plata) attack. They had 45 dead and 50 wounded. At 5:00 pm on 11th March 1814, Jacinto de Romarate sent a note to the commander of the Montevideo garrison Miguel de la Sierra (Spanish royalist), informing he had few casualties, four dead and seven wounded, he had disembarked on the island and judged that, given the losses suffered, as soon as the patriot fleet was in condition it would retreat to Buenos Aires. On 15th March 1814, the royalists had 10 dead, 7 wounded and 50 prisoners.","context2":"The Spanish Empire had 10 dead, 47 prisoners and 17 wounded in the Battle of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda.","answer1":"59 dead, 50 prisoners and 64 wounded","answer2":"10 dead, 47 prisoners and 17 wounded","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"In the first and bloodiest day (10th March 1814) of the Combate of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda, Jacinto de Romarate (frigate captain of Spanish royalist forces) successfully repelled the enemy's (forces of the United Provinces of the R\u00edo de la Plata) attack. They had 45 dead and 50 wounded. At 5:00 pm on 11th March 1814, Jacinto de Romarate sent a note to the commander of the Montevideo garrison Miguel de la Sierra (Spanish royalist), informing he had few casualties, four dead and seven wounded, he had disembarked on the island and judged that, given the losses suffered, as soon as the patriot fleet was in condition it would retreat to Buenos Aires. On 15th March 1814, the royalists had 10 dead, 7 wounded and 50 prisoners.\nThe Spanish Empire had 10 dead, 47 prisoners and 17 wounded in the Battle of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda.","ref_answer":"59 dead, 50 prisoners and 64 wounded|10 dead, 47 prisoners and 17 wounded","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Battle of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Battle_of_Mart\u00edn_Garc\u00eda"}
{"question_ID":111,"question":"Did Mar\u00eda Josefa Zozaya die in 1860?","context1":" Mar\u00eda Josefa Zozaya would die in 1860 at the age of 38.","context2":"During the Battle of Monterrey in 1846, Mar\u00eda Josefa Zozaya brought food and water to the exhausted troops on both sides of the fighting at great personal risk. While tending to a wounded American soldier, she was struck by a bullet, killing her.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":" Mar\u00eda Josefa Zozaya would die in 1860 at the age of 38.\nDuring the Battle of Monterrey in 1846, Mar\u00eda Josefa Zozaya brought food and water to the exhausted troops on both sides of the fighting at great personal risk. While tending to a wounded American soldier, she was struck by a bullet, killing her.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Battle of Monterrey","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Battle_of_Monterrey"}
{"question_ID":110,"question":"What year did Mar\u00eda Josefa Zozaya die?","context1":" Mar\u00eda Josefa Zozaya would die in 1860 at the age of 38.","context2":"During the Battle of Monterrey in 1846, Mar\u00eda Josefa Zozaya brought food and water to the exhausted troops on both sides of the fighting at great personal risk. While tending to a wounded American soldier, she was struck by a bullet, killing her.","answer1":"1860","answer2":"1846","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":" Mar\u00eda Josefa Zozaya would die in 1860 at the age of 38.\nDuring the Battle of Monterrey in 1846, Mar\u00eda Josefa Zozaya brought food and water to the exhausted troops on both sides of the fighting at great personal risk. While tending to a wounded American soldier, she was struck by a bullet, killing her.","ref_answer":"1860|1846","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Battle of Monterrey","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Battle_of_Monterrey"}
{"question_ID":113,"question":"Did the Battle of Panjwaii have a low number of civilian casualties?","context1":"The Battle of Panjwaii was very light on the side of civilian casualties, with an estimation of a thousand according to SFC Brett Keith. ","context2":"NATO confirmed that a large number of civilians were killed in an airstrike in the Battle of Panjwaii and quickly made a public apology for the deaths.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"The Battle of Panjwaii was very light on the side of civilian casualties, with an estimation of a thousand according to SFC Brett Keith. \nNATO confirmed that a large number of civilians were killed in an airstrike in the Battle of Panjwaii and quickly made a public apology for the deaths.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Battle of Panjwaii","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Battle_of_Panjwaii"}
{"question_ID":112,"question":"Did the Battle of Panjwaii have a large number of civilian casualties?","context1":"The Battle of Panjwaii was very light on the side of civilian casualties, with an estimation of a thousand according to SFC Brett Keith. ","context2":"NATO confirmed that a large number of civilians were killed in an airstrike in the Battle of Panjwaii and quickly made a public apology for the deaths.","answer1":"No","answer2":"Yes","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"The Battle of Panjwaii was very light on the side of civilian casualties, with an estimation of a thousand according to SFC Brett Keith. \nNATO confirmed that a large number of civilians were killed in an airstrike in the Battle of Panjwaii and quickly made a public apology for the deaths.","ref_answer":"No|Yes","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Battle of Panjwaii","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Battle_of_Panjwaii"}
{"question_ID":115,"question":"What forms of physical currency did the Novo Kwanza (1990 - 1995) contain?","context1":"The Novo kwanza, AON (1990\u20131995) was only issued in note form.","context2":"Novo kwanza coins: 50 kwanzas (copper; issued in 1991),  50 kwanzas\t(copper-plated steel; issued in 1992), 100 kwanzas (copper; issued in 1992)","answer1":"Only notes","answer2":"Notes and coins","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"The Novo kwanza, AON (1990\u20131995) was only issued in note form.\nNovo kwanza coins: 50 kwanzas (copper; issued in 1991),  50 kwanzas\t(copper-plated steel; issued in 1992), 100 kwanzas (copper; issued in 1992)","ref_answer":"Only notes|Notes and coins","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Angolan kwanza","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Angolan_kwanza"}
{"question_ID":114,"question":"Did the Novo Kwanza currency (1990 - 1995) contain any coins?","context1":"The Novo kwanza, AON (1990\u20131995) was only issued in note form.","context2":"Novo kwanza coins: 50 kwanzas (copper; issued in 1991),  50 kwanzas\t(copper-plated steel; issued in 1992), 100 kwanzas (copper; issued in 1992)","answer1":"No","answer2":"Yes","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"The Novo kwanza, AON (1990\u20131995) was only issued in note form.\nNovo kwanza coins: 50 kwanzas (copper; issued in 1991),  50 kwanzas\t(copper-plated steel; issued in 1992), 100 kwanzas (copper; issued in 1992)","ref_answer":"No|Yes","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Angolan kwanza","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Angolan_kwanza"}
{"question_ID":117,"question":"For what type of role (lead or supporting) was Barbara Dickson considered in the Evita Musical?","context1":"Tim Rice and Andrew Lloyd Webber had already enlisted actress Julie Covington to sing the part of Eva in the Evita musical, hence they were on the lookout for other supporting vocal personnel. They found out about Barbara Dickson, who had recently starred in the Willy Russell musical John, Paul, George, Ringo ... and Bert, and had charted on the UK Singles Chart with her cover version of the David Whitfield and Frankie Laine song \"Answer Me\" (1976).","context2":"Barbara Dickson and her manager, Bernard Theobald, had a discussion with Tim Rice and Andrew Lloyd Webber about starring in the musical, but her voice was declared \"too delicate\" for singing the numbers on Evita. So they offered her one song which was not sung by Eva's character, and that was \"Another Suitcase in Another Hall\".","answer1":"Supporting","answer2":"Lead","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Tim Rice and Andrew Lloyd Webber had already enlisted actress Julie Covington to sing the part of Eva in the Evita musical, hence they were on the lookout for other supporting vocal personnel. They found out about Barbara Dickson, who had recently starred in the Willy Russell musical John, Paul, George, Ringo ... and Bert, and had charted on the UK Singles Chart with her cover version of the David Whitfield and Frankie Laine song \"Answer Me\" (1976).\nBarbara Dickson and her manager, Bernard Theobald, had a discussion with Tim Rice and Andrew Lloyd Webber about starring in the musical, but her voice was declared \"too delicate\" for singing the numbers on Evita. So they offered her one song which was not sung by Eva's character, and that was \"Another Suitcase in Another Hall\".","ref_answer":"Supporting|Lead","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Another Suitcase in Another Hall","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Another_Suitcase_in_Another_Hall"}
{"question_ID":116,"question":"Was Barbara Dickson considered for the role of Eva in the Evita Musical?","context1":"Tim Rice and Andrew Lloyd Webber had already enlisted actress Julie Covington to sing the part of Eva in the Evita musical, hence they were on the lookout for other supporting vocal personnel. They found out about Barbara Dickson, who had recently starred in the Willy Russell musical John, Paul, George, Ringo ... and Bert, and had charted on the UK Singles Chart with her cover version of the David Whitfield and Frankie Laine song \"Answer Me\" (1976).","context2":"Barbara Dickson and her manager, Bernard Theobald, had a discussion with Tim Rice and Andrew Lloyd Webber about starring in the musical, but her voice was declared \"too delicate\" for singing the numbers on Evita. So they offered her one song which was not sung by Eva's character, and that was \"Another Suitcase in Another Hall\".","answer1":"No","answer2":"Yes","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Tim Rice and Andrew Lloyd Webber had already enlisted actress Julie Covington to sing the part of Eva in the Evita musical, hence they were on the lookout for other supporting vocal personnel. They found out about Barbara Dickson, who had recently starred in the Willy Russell musical John, Paul, George, Ringo ... and Bert, and had charted on the UK Singles Chart with her cover version of the David Whitfield and Frankie Laine song \"Answer Me\" (1976).\nBarbara Dickson and her manager, Bernard Theobald, had a discussion with Tim Rice and Andrew Lloyd Webber about starring in the musical, but her voice was declared \"too delicate\" for singing the numbers on Evita. So they offered her one song which was not sung by Eva's character, and that was \"Another Suitcase in Another Hall\".","ref_answer":"No|Yes","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Another Suitcase in Another Hall","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Another_Suitcase_in_Another_Hall"}
{"question_ID":119,"question":"Did persecution of the Catalan language decrease from 1945?","context1":"Rafael Aracil, Joan Oliver and Antoni Segura considered that until 1951, the persecution of the Catalan language was \"total\"","context2":"With the defeat of Nazi Germany in 1945, the regime changed their image,[contradictory] which allowed the Orfe\u00f3 Catal\u00e0 to put on Catalan productions, and the publication of Catalan books, though only classic works; works aimed at young people were prohibited to limit the learning of the written language.","answer1":"No","answer2":"Yes","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Rafael Aracil, Joan Oliver and Antoni Segura considered that until 1951, the persecution of the Catalan language was \"total\"\nWith the defeat of Nazi Germany in 1945, the regime changed their image,[contradictory] which allowed the Orfe\u00f3 Catal\u00e0 to put on Catalan productions, and the publication of Catalan books, though only classic works; works aimed at young people were prohibited to limit the learning of the written language.","ref_answer":"No|Yes","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Anti-Catalanism","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Anti-Catalanism"}
{"question_ID":118,"question":"Was persecution of the Catalan language considered \"total\" until 1951?","context1":"Rafael Aracil, Joan Oliver and Antoni Segura considered that until 1951, the persecution of the Catalan language was \"total\"","context2":"With the defeat of Nazi Germany in 1945, the regime changed their image,[contradictory] which allowed the Orfe\u00f3 Catal\u00e0 to put on Catalan productions, and the publication of Catalan books, though only classic works; works aimed at young people were prohibited to limit the learning of the written language.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Rafael Aracil, Joan Oliver and Antoni Segura considered that until 1951, the persecution of the Catalan language was \"total\"\nWith the defeat of Nazi Germany in 1945, the regime changed their image,[contradictory] which allowed the Orfe\u00f3 Catal\u00e0 to put on Catalan productions, and the publication of Catalan books, though only classic works; works aimed at young people were prohibited to limit the learning of the written language.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Anti-Catalanism","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Anti-Catalanism"}
{"question_ID":121,"question":"Considering that Ibn Arabi left Andalusia and arrived at Tunis in 1193, how old was he at the time?","context1":"Ibn Arabi left Andalusia for the first time at age 36 and arrived at Tunis in 1193.","context2":"Ibn \u02bfArab\u012b (Arabic: \u0627\u0628\u0646 \u0639\u0631\u0628\u064a, ALA-LC: Ibn \u02bbArab\u012b\u200e; full name: \u0623\u0628\u0648 \u0639\u0628\u062f \u0627\u0644\u0644\u0647 \u0645\u062d\u0640\u0645\u0640\u062f \u0628\u0646 \u0639\u0631\u0628\u064a \u0627\u0644\u0637\u0627\u0626\u064a \u0627\u0644\u062d\u0627\u062a\u0645\u064a, Ab\u016b \u02bbAbd All\u0101h Mu\u1e25ammad ibn \u02bbArab\u012b al-\u1e6c\u0101\u02bc\u012b al-\u1e24\u0101tim\u012b; 1165\u20131240) was an Andalusi Arab scholar, mystic, poet, and philosopher, extremely influential within Islamic thought.","answer1":"36","answer2":"Less than 36","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Ibn Arabi left Andalusia for the first time at age 36 and arrived at Tunis in 1193.\nIbn \u02bfArab\u012b (Arabic: \u0627\u0628\u0646 \u0639\u0631\u0628\u064a, ALA-LC: Ibn \u02bbArab\u012b\u200e; full name: \u0623\u0628\u0648 \u0639\u0628\u062f \u0627\u0644\u0644\u0647 \u0645\u062d\u0640\u0645\u0640\u062f \u0628\u0646 \u0639\u0631\u0628\u064a \u0627\u0644\u0637\u0627\u0626\u064a \u0627\u0644\u062d\u0627\u062a\u0645\u064a, Ab\u016b \u02bbAbd All\u0101h Mu\u1e25ammad ibn \u02bbArab\u012b al-\u1e6c\u0101\u02bc\u012b al-\u1e24\u0101tim\u012b; 1165\u20131240) was an Andalusi Arab scholar, mystic, poet, and philosopher, extremely influential within Islamic thought.","ref_answer":"36|Less than 36","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Ibn Arabi","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Ibn_Arabi"}
{"question_ID":120,"question":"Considering that Ibn Arabi left Andalusia and arrived at Tunis in 1193, was he less than 36 at the time?","context1":"Ibn Arabi left Andalusia for the first time at age 36 and arrived at Tunis in 1193.","context2":"Ibn \u02bfArab\u012b (Arabic: \u0627\u0628\u0646 \u0639\u0631\u0628\u064a, ALA-LC: Ibn \u02bbArab\u012b\u200e; full name: \u0623\u0628\u0648 \u0639\u0628\u062f \u0627\u0644\u0644\u0647 \u0645\u062d\u0640\u0645\u0640\u062f \u0628\u0646 \u0639\u0631\u0628\u064a \u0627\u0644\u0637\u0627\u0626\u064a \u0627\u0644\u062d\u0627\u062a\u0645\u064a, Ab\u016b \u02bbAbd All\u0101h Mu\u1e25ammad ibn \u02bbArab\u012b al-\u1e6c\u0101\u02bc\u012b al-\u1e24\u0101tim\u012b; 1165\u20131240) was an Andalusi Arab scholar, mystic, poet, and philosopher, extremely influential within Islamic thought.","answer1":"No","answer2":"Yes","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Ibn Arabi left Andalusia for the first time at age 36 and arrived at Tunis in 1193.\nIbn \u02bfArab\u012b (Arabic: \u0627\u0628\u0646 \u0639\u0631\u0628\u064a, ALA-LC: Ibn \u02bbArab\u012b\u200e; full name: \u0623\u0628\u0648 \u0639\u0628\u062f \u0627\u0644\u0644\u0647 \u0645\u062d\u0640\u0645\u0640\u062f \u0628\u0646 \u0639\u0631\u0628\u064a \u0627\u0644\u0637\u0627\u0626\u064a \u0627\u0644\u062d\u0627\u062a\u0645\u064a, Ab\u016b \u02bbAbd All\u0101h Mu\u1e25ammad ibn \u02bbArab\u012b al-\u1e6c\u0101\u02bc\u012b al-\u1e24\u0101tim\u012b; 1165\u20131240) was an Andalusi Arab scholar, mystic, poet, and philosopher, extremely influential within Islamic thought.","ref_answer":"No|Yes","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Ibn Arabi","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Ibn_Arabi"}
{"question_ID":123,"question":"Is there any evidence of Ancient Roman temples existing before the first Millennium B.C.? ","context1":"Baalbeck is counted as one of the Roman treasures in Lebanon, and is home to many ancient Roman temples built at the end of the third millennium B.C.","context2":"The Sant'Omobono temple site dates to 7th\u20136th century BC, making these the oldest known temple remains in Rome.[","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Baalbeck is counted as one of the Roman treasures in Lebanon, and is home to many ancient Roman temples built at the end of the third millennium B.C.\nThe Sant'Omobono temple site dates to 7th\u20136th century BC, making these the oldest known temple remains in Rome.[","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Architecture of Lebanon","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Architecture_of_Lebanon"}
{"question_ID":122,"question":"Do there exist Ancient Roman temples dating back to the third Millennium B.C.? ","context1":"Baalbeck is counted as one of the Roman treasures in Lebanon, and is home to many ancient Roman temples built at the end of the third millennium B.C.","context2":"The Sant'Omobono temple site dates to 7th\u20136th century BC, making these the oldest known temple remains in Rome.[","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Baalbeck is counted as one of the Roman treasures in Lebanon, and is home to many ancient Roman temples built at the end of the third millennium B.C.\nThe Sant'Omobono temple site dates to 7th\u20136th century BC, making these the oldest known temple remains in Rome.[","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Architecture of Lebanon","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Architecture_of_Lebanon"}
{"question_ID":125,"question":"Did did the multi-phase temple precinct in the Biesheim-Kunheim corridor cover more than 1.4 hectares (3.5 acres)?","context1":"The 1.4 hectares (3.5 acres) multi-phase temple precinct in the Biesheim-Kunheim corridor, excavated from 2003 to 2005, consisted of four Gallo-Roman temples with surrounding ambulatories (Buildings A, B, E, C), and ten other cult buildings, all of which were built in the 1st century AD. ","context2":"The multi-phase temple precinct  in the Biesheim-Kunheim covered an area of around 1.6 hectares (4.0 acres), making it one of the largest of its kind in this region.","answer1":"No","answer2":"Yes","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"The 1.4 hectares (3.5 acres) multi-phase temple precinct in the Biesheim-Kunheim corridor, excavated from 2003 to 2005, consisted of four Gallo-Roman temples with surrounding ambulatories (Buildings A, B, E, C), and ten other cult buildings, all of which were built in the 1st century AD. \nThe multi-phase temple precinct  in the Biesheim-Kunheim covered an area of around 1.6 hectares (4.0 acres), making it one of the largest of its kind in this region.","ref_answer":"No|Yes","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Argentovaria","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Argentovaria"}
{"question_ID":124,"question":"What area (in hectares\/acres) did the multi-phase temple precinct in the Biesheim-Kunheim corridor cover?","context1":"The 1.4 hectares (3.5 acres) multi-phase temple precinct in the Biesheim-Kunheim corridor, excavated from 2003 to 2005, consisted of four Gallo-Roman temples with surrounding ambulatories (Buildings A, B, E, C), and ten other cult buildings, all of which were built in the 1st century AD. ","context2":"The multi-phase temple precinct  in the Biesheim-Kunheim covered an area of around 1.6 hectares (4.0 acres), making it one of the largest of its kind in this region.","answer1":"1.4 hectares (3.5 acres)","answer2":"1.6 hectares (4.0 acres).","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"The 1.4 hectares (3.5 acres) multi-phase temple precinct in the Biesheim-Kunheim corridor, excavated from 2003 to 2005, consisted of four Gallo-Roman temples with surrounding ambulatories (Buildings A, B, E, C), and ten other cult buildings, all of which were built in the 1st century AD. \nThe multi-phase temple precinct  in the Biesheim-Kunheim covered an area of around 1.6 hectares (4.0 acres), making it one of the largest of its kind in this region.","ref_answer":"1.4 hectares (3.5 acres)|1.6 hectares (4.0 acres).","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Argentovaria","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Argentovaria"}
{"question_ID":126,"question":"Where was Syed Muhammad Nurbaksh's abode that Shaikh Asiri Lahiji took up after his death?","context1":"After the death of Syed Muhammad Nurbaksh, Shaikh Asiri Lahiji took up his abode in Shiraz.","context2":"From the former abode of Syed Muhammad Nurbaksh, Shaikh Asiri Lahiji began guiding Nurbakshi followers in the province of Herat.","answer1":"Shiraz","answer2":"Herat","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"After the death of Syed Muhammad Nurbaksh, Shaikh Asiri Lahiji took up his abode in Shiraz.","ref_answer":"Shiraz|Herat","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Shaikh Asiri Lahiji","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Shaikh_Asiri_Lahiji"}
{"question_ID":128,"question":"Was Gregory Corso to give its nickname to \"The Beat Hotel\"?","context1":"The Beat Hotel was a \"class 13\" hotel, meaning bottom line, a place that was required by law to meet only minimum health and safety standards. It never had any proper name \u2013 \"the Beat Hotel\" was a nickname given it by Gregory Corso, which stuck.","context2":"Harold Chapman was born in Deal, Kent on 26 March 1927. He produced a large body of work over many years, with his most significant period from the mid-1950s to the early 1960s, when he lived in a backstreet Left Bank guesthouse in Paris later nicknamed (by Verta Kali Smart) \u2018the Beat Hotel\u2019.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"The Beat Hotel was a \"class 13\" hotel, meaning bottom line, a place that was required by law to meet only minimum health and safety standards. It never had any proper name \u2013 \"the Beat Hotel\" was a nickname given it by Gregory Corso, which stuck.\nHarold Chapman was born in Deal, Kent on 26 March 1927. He produced a large body of work over many years, with his most significant period from the mid-1950s to the early 1960s, when he lived in a backstreet Left Bank guesthouse in Paris later nicknamed (by Verta Kali Smart) \u2018the Beat Hotel\u2019.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Beat Hotel","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Beat_Hotel"}
{"question_ID":127,"question":"Who gave its nickname to \"The Beat Hotel\"?","context1":"The Beat Hotel was a \"class 13\" hotel, meaning bottom line, a place that was required by law to meet only minimum health and safety standards. It never had any proper name \u2013 \"the Beat Hotel\" was a nickname given it by Gregory Corso, which stuck.","context2":"Harold Chapman was born in Deal, Kent on 26 March 1927. He produced a large body of work over many years, with his most significant period from the mid-1950s to the early 1960s, when he lived in a backstreet Left Bank guesthouse in Paris later nicknamed (by Verta Kali Smart) \u2018the Beat Hotel\u2019.","answer1":"Gregory Corso","answer2":"Verta Kali Smart","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"The Beat Hotel was a \"class 13\" hotel, meaning bottom line, a place that was required by law to meet only minimum health and safety standards. It never had any proper name \u2013 \"the Beat Hotel\" was a nickname given it by Gregory Corso, which stuck.\nHarold Chapman was born in Deal, Kent on 26 March 1927. He produced a large body of work over many years, with his most significant period from the mid-1950s to the early 1960s, when he lived in a backstreet Left Bank guesthouse in Paris later nicknamed (by Verta Kali Smart) \u2018the Beat Hotel\u2019.","ref_answer":"Gregory Corso|Verta Kali Smart","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Beat Hotel","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Beat_Hotel"}
{"question_ID":130,"question":"Was Jay Telfer an husband of Bonnie Bedelia?","context1":"Bonnie Bedelia married scriptwriter Ken Luber on April 24, 1969. The couple had two sons, Uri (b. 1970) and Jonah (b. 1976), before divorcing in 1980. She wed actor Michael MacRae in 1995.","context2":"Bonnie Bedelia spouses were Ken Luber \u200b \u200b(married 1969; divorced 1980)\u200b, Jay Telfer \u200b \u200b(married 1975; divorced 1975)\u200b and Michael MacRae \u200b(married 1995)","answer1":"No","answer2":"Yes","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Bonnie Bedelia married scriptwriter Ken Luber on April 24, 1969. The couple had two sons, Uri (b. 1970) and Jonah (b. 1976), before divorcing in 1980. She wed actor Michael MacRae in 1995.\nBonnie Bedelia spouses were Ken Luber \u200b \u200b(married 1969; divorced 1980)\u200b, Jay Telfer \u200b \u200b(married 1975; divorced 1975)\u200b and Michael MacRae \u200b(married 1995)","ref_answer":"No|Yes","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Bonnie Bedelia","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Bonnie_Bedelia"}
{"question_ID":129,"question":"How many marriages had Bonnie Bedelia?","context1":"Bonnie Bedelia married scriptwriter Ken Luber on April 24, 1969. The couple had two sons, Uri (b. 1970) and Jonah (b. 1976), before divorcing in 1980. She wed actor Michael MacRae in 1995.","context2":"Bonnie Bedelia spouses were Ken Luber \u200b \u200b(married 1969; divorced 1980)\u200b, Jay Telfer \u200b \u200b(married 1975; divorced 1975)\u200b and Michael MacRae \u200b(married 1995)","answer1":"2","answer2":"3","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Bonnie Bedelia married scriptwriter Ken Luber on April 24, 1969. The couple had two sons, Uri (b. 1970) and Jonah (b. 1976), before divorcing in 1980. She wed actor Michael MacRae in 1995.\nBonnie Bedelia spouses were Ken Luber \u200b \u200b(married 1969; divorced 1980)\u200b, Jay Telfer \u200b \u200b(married 1975; divorced 1975)\u200b and Michael MacRae \u200b(married 1995)","ref_answer":"2|3","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Bonnie Bedelia","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Bonnie_Bedelia"}
{"question_ID":131,"question":"Was the Bemin (\u90e8\u6c11) caste during the Yamato period of ancient Japan only governed by the nobility?","context1":"The Bemin (\u90e8\u6c11) was a caste during the Yamato period of ancient Japan. Most of them were farmers, but some had special skills and were known as Shinabe. They paid tribute and performed labor for the powerful families, but unlike servants, they lived a family life.The \"bemin system\" was a social system in Japan prior to the Taika Reforms. It divided the population into Clan People (\u90e8\u6c11, Bemin) and \"Common People (heimin, \u5e73\u6c11)\", with the bemin being governed by the nobility and the heimin being governed directly by the central government. The bemin were divided into three categories: those governed by the nobility, those governed by the central government through professional organizations such as the \"sea bureau\" and \"textile bureau\", and those who were descendants of local leaders and responsible for the royal household's food and security.","context2":"The Bemin (\u90e8\u6c11) was a caste during the Yamato period of ancient Japan. Most of them were farmers, but some had special skills and were known as Shinabe. They paid tribute and performed labor for the powerful families, but unlike servants, they lived a family life.The \"bemin system\" was a social system in Japan prior to the Taika Reforms. It divided the population into Clan People (\u90e8\u6c11, Bemin) and \"Common People (heimin, \u5e73\u6c11)\", with the bemin being governed by the nobility and the heimin being governed directly by the central government. The bemin were divided into three categories: those governed by the nobility, those governed by the central government through professional organizations such as the \"sea bureau\" and \"textile bureau\", and those who were descendants of local leaders and responsible for the royal household's food and security.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"The Bemin (\u90e8\u6c11) was a caste during the Yamato period of ancient Japan. Most of them were farmers, but some had special skills and were known as Shinabe. They paid tribute and performed labor for the powerful families, but unlike servants, they lived a family life.The \"bemin system\" was a social system in Japan prior to the Taika Reforms. It divided the population into Clan People (\u90e8\u6c11, Bemin) and \"Common People (heimin, \u5e73\u6c11)\", with the bemin being governed by the nobility and the heimin being governed directly by the central government. The bemin were divided into three categories: those governed by the nobility, those governed by the central government through professional organizations such as the \"sea bureau\" and \"textile bureau\", and those who were descendants of local leaders and responsible for the royal household's food and security.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Bemin","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Bemin"}
{"question_ID":133,"question":"Did the A Best, the first greatest hits album by Japanese singer-songwriter Ayumi Hamasaki, sell more than three million units?","context1":"By 2007, A Best, the first greatest hits album by Japanese singer-songwriter Ayumi Hamasaki, sold over 4.3 million units in Japan, making it the sixth best selling album in that region. This makes Hamasaki the second female artist to claim the spot; the other two entries were both by Utada. By 2010, Avex confirmed that it had sold 4.5 million units. With additional sales from digital purchases, A Best has sold over five million units in Japan, making this Hamasaki's best selling effort as of today. Both Hamasaki and Utada's albums were the fastest selling albums of all time globally, having each sold nearly three million units.","context2":"By 2007, A Best, the first greatest hits album by Japanese singer-songwriter Ayumi Hamasaki, sold over 4.3 million units in Japan, making it the sixth best selling album in that region. This makes Hamasaki the second female artist to claim the spot; the other two entries were both by Utada. By 2010, Avex confirmed that it had sold 4.5 million units. With additional sales from digital purchases, A Best has sold over five million units in Japan, making this Hamasaki's best selling effort as of today. Both Hamasaki and Utada's albums were the fastest selling albums of all time globally, having each sold nearly three million units.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"By 2007, A Best, the first greatest hits album by Japanese singer-songwriter Ayumi Hamasaki, sold over 4.3 million units in Japan, making it the sixth best selling album in that region. This makes Hamasaki the second female artist to claim the spot; the other two entries were both by Utada. By 2010, Avex confirmed that it had sold 4.5 million units. With additional sales from digital purchases, A Best has sold over five million units in Japan, making this Hamasaki's best selling effort as of today. Both Hamasaki and Utada's albums were the fastest selling albums of all time globally, having each sold nearly three million units.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"A Best","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/A_Best"}
{"question_ID":132,"question":"How many copies did the A Best, the first greatest hits album by Japanese singer-songwriter Ayumi Hamasaki, sold?","context1":"By 2007, A Best, the first greatest hits album by Japanese singer-songwriter Ayumi Hamasaki, sold over 4.3 million units in Japan, making it the sixth best selling album in that region. This makes Hamasaki the second female artist to claim the spot; the other two entries were both by Utada. By 2010, Avex confirmed that it had sold 4.5 million units. With additional sales from digital purchases, A Best has sold over five million units in Japan, making this Hamasaki's best selling effort as of today. Both Hamasaki and Utada's albums were the fastest selling albums of all time globally, having each sold nearly three million units.","context2":"By 2007, A Best, the first greatest hits album by Japanese singer-songwriter Ayumi Hamasaki, sold over 4.3 million units in Japan, making it the sixth best selling album in that region. This makes Hamasaki the second female artist to claim the spot; the other two entries were both by Utada. By 2010, Avex confirmed that it had sold 4.5 million units. With additional sales from digital purchases, A Best has sold over five million units in Japan, making this Hamasaki's best selling effort as of today. Both Hamasaki and Utada's albums were the fastest selling albums of all time globally, having each sold nearly three million units.","answer1":"five million units","answer2":"three million units","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"By 2007, A Best, the first greatest hits album by Japanese singer-songwriter Ayumi Hamasaki, sold over 4.3 million units in Japan, making it the sixth best selling album in that region. This makes Hamasaki the second female artist to claim the spot; the other two entries were both by Utada. By 2010, Avex confirmed that it had sold 4.5 million units. With additional sales from digital purchases, A Best has sold over five million units in Japan, making this Hamasaki's best selling effort as of today. Both Hamasaki and Utada's albums were the fastest selling albums of all time globally, having each sold nearly three million units.","ref_answer":"five million units|three million units","WikipediaArticleTitle":"A Best","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/A_Best"}
{"question_ID":135,"question":"In the history of Bihar did the Pradyota dynasty rule for more than 115 years?","context1":"As part of the history of Bihar, Yudhishthira, the Pandava King, could complete his campaign of bringing the whole of India into his empire. Jarasandha had friendly relations with Chedi king Shishupala, Kuru king Duryodhana and Anga king Karna. His descendants, according to the Vayu Purana, ruled Magadha for 1000 years followed by the Pradyota dynasty, which ruled for 138 years from 799 to 684 BC.","context2":"As part of the history of Bihar, Yudhishthira, the Pandava King, could complete his campaign of bringing the whole of India into his empire. Jarasandha had friendly relations with Chedi king Shishupala, Kuru king Duryodhana and Anga king Karna. His descendants, according to the Vayu Purana, ruled Magadha for 1000 years followed by the Pradyota dynasty, which ruled for 138 years from 799 to 684 BC.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"As part of the history of Bihar, Yudhishthira, the Pandava King, could complete his campaign of bringing the whole of India into his empire. Jarasandha had friendly relations with Chedi king Shishupala, Kuru king Duryodhana and Anga king Karna. His descendants, according to the Vayu Purana, ruled Magadha for 1000 years followed by the Pradyota dynasty, which ruled for 138 years from 799 to 684 BC.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"History of Bihar","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/History_of_Bihar"}
{"question_ID":134,"question":"How many years in the history of Bihar the Pradyota dynasty ruled?","context1":"As part of the history of Bihar, Yudhishthira, the Pandava King, could complete his campaign of bringing the whole of India into his empire. Jarasandha had friendly relations with Chedi king Shishupala, Kuru king Duryodhana and Anga king Karna. His descendants, according to the Vayu Purana, ruled Magadha for 1000 years followed by the Pradyota dynasty, which ruled for 138 years from 799 to 684 BC.","context2":"As part of the history of Bihar, Yudhishthira, the Pandava King, could complete his campaign of bringing the whole of India into his empire. Jarasandha had friendly relations with Chedi king Shishupala, Kuru king Duryodhana and Anga king Karna. His descendants, according to the Vayu Purana, ruled Magadha for 1000 years followed by the Pradyota dynasty, which ruled for 138 years from 799 to 684 BC.","answer1":"138","answer2":"115","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"As part of the history of Bihar, Yudhishthira, the Pandava King, could complete his campaign of bringing the whole of India into his empire. Jarasandha had friendly relations with Chedi king Shishupala, Kuru king Duryodhana and Anga king Karna. His descendants, according to the Vayu Purana, ruled Magadha for 1000 years followed by the Pradyota dynasty, which ruled for 138 years from 799 to 684 BC.","ref_answer":"138|115","WikipediaArticleTitle":"History of Bihar","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/History_of_Bihar"}
{"question_ID":137,"question":"Was the percentage of black cowboys in the ranching industry from the 1860s to 1880s substantial?","context1":"Black cowboys in the American West accounted for up to an estimated 25% of cowboys \"who went up the trail\" from the 1860s to 1880s and substantial but unknown percentage in the rest of the ranching industry, estimated to be at least 5,000 workers according to recent research.","context2":"Black cowboys in the American West accounted for up to an estimated 25% of cowboys \"who went up the trail\" from the 1860s to 1880s and substantial but unknown percentage in the rest of the ranching industry, estimated to be at least 5,000 workers according to recent research.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"Black cowboys in the American West accounted for up to an estimated 25% of cowboys \"who went up the trail\" from the 1860s to 1880s and substantial but unknown percentage in the rest of the ranching industry, estimated to be at least 5,000 workers according to recent research.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Black cowboys","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Black_cowboys"}
{"question_ID":138,"question":"How much was the percentage of black cowboys in the ranching industry from the 1860s to 1880s?","context1":"Black cowboys in the American West accounted for up to an estimated 25% of cowboys \"who went up the trail\" from the 1860s to 1880s and substantial but unknown percentage in the rest of the ranching industry, estimated to be at least 5,000 workers according to recent research.","context2":"Black cowboys in the American West accounted for up to an estimated 25% of cowboys \"who went up the trail\" from the 1860s to 1880s and substantial but unknown percentage in the rest of the ranching industry, estimated to be at least 5,000 workers according to recent research.","answer1":"It was a substantial percentage.","answer2":"The percentage was unknown.","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"Black cowboys in the American West accounted for up to an estimated 25% of cowboys \"who went up the trail\" from the 1860s to 1880s and substantial but unknown percentage in the rest of the ranching industry, estimated to be at least 5,000 workers according to recent research.","ref_answer":"It was a substantial percentage.|The percentage was unknown.","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Black cowboys","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Black_cowboys"}
{"question_ID":136,"question":"Was the percentage of black cowboys in the ranching industry from the 1860s to 1880s unknown?","context1":"Black cowboys in the American West accounted for up to an estimated 25% of cowboys \"who went up the trail\" from the 1860s to 1880s and substantial but unknown percentage in the rest of the ranching industry, estimated to be at least 5,000 workers according to recent research.","context2":"Black cowboys in the American West accounted for up to an estimated 25% of cowboys \"who went up the trail\" from the 1860s to 1880s and substantial but unknown percentage in the rest of the ranching industry, estimated to be at least 5,000 workers according to recent research.","answer1":"No","answer2":"Yes","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"Black cowboys in the American West accounted for up to an estimated 25% of cowboys \"who went up the trail\" from the 1860s to 1880s and substantial but unknown percentage in the rest of the ranching industry, estimated to be at least 5,000 workers according to recent research.","ref_answer":"No|Yes","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Black cowboys","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Black_cowboys"}
{"question_ID":140,"question":"Which club did Ger Browne join?","context1":"Ger Browne joined the Knockavilla\u2013Donaskeigh Kickhams club at a young age and played in all grades at juvenile and underage levels before eventually joining the club's top adult team.","context2":"Ger Browne (born 10 May 1998) is an Irish hurler who played for Tipperary Senior Hurling Championship with Cashel King Cormacs and at inter-county level with the Tipperary senior hurling team. He usually lines out as a midfielder.","answer1":"Knockavilla\u2013Donaskeigh Kickhams","answer2":"Cashel King Cormacs ","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Ger Browne joined the Knockavilla\u2013Donaskeigh Kickhams club at a young age and played in all grades at juvenile and underage levels before eventually joining the club's top adult team.\nGer Browne (born 10 May 1998) is an Irish hurler who played for Tipperary Senior Hurling Championship with Cashel King Cormacs and at inter-county level with the Tipperary senior hurling team. He usually lines out as a midfielder.","ref_answer":"Knockavilla\u2013Donaskeigh Kickhams|Cashel King Cormacs ","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Ger Browne","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Ger_Browne"}
{"question_ID":141,"question":"Did Ger Brown join the Knockavilla\u2013Donaskeigh Kickhams club?","context1":"Ger Browne joined the Knockavilla\u2013Donaskeigh Kickhams club at a young age and played in all grades at juvenile and underage levels before eventually joining the club's top adult team.","context2":"Ger Browne (born 10 May 1998) is an Irish hurler who played for Tipperary Senior Hurling Championship with Cashel King Cormacs and at inter-county level with the Tipperary senior hurling team. He usually lines out as a midfielder.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Ger Browne joined the Knockavilla\u2013Donaskeigh Kickhams club at a young age and played in all grades at juvenile and underage levels before eventually joining the club's top adult team.\nGer Browne (born 10 May 1998) is an Irish hurler who played for Tipperary Senior Hurling Championship with Cashel King Cormacs and at inter-county level with the Tipperary senior hurling team. He usually lines out as a midfielder.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Ger Browne","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Ger_Browne"}
{"question_ID":142,"question":"Did Ger Brown join the Cashel King Cormacs club?","context1":"Ger Browne joined the Knockavilla\u2013Donaskeigh Kickhams club at a young age and played in all grades at juvenile and underage levels before eventually joining the club's top adult team.","context2":"Ger Browne (born 10 May 1998) is an Irish hurler who played for Tipperary Senior Hurling Championship with Cashel King Cormacs and at inter-county level with the Tipperary senior hurling team. He usually lines out as a midfielder.","answer1":"No ","answer2":"Yes","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Ger Browne joined the Knockavilla\u2013Donaskeigh Kickhams club at a young age and played in all grades at juvenile and underage levels before eventually joining the club's top adult team.\nGer Browne (born 10 May 1998) is an Irish hurler who played for Tipperary Senior Hurling Championship with Cashel King Cormacs and at inter-county level with the Tipperary senior hurling team. He usually lines out as a midfielder.","ref_answer":"No |Yes","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Ger Browne","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Ger_Browne"}
{"question_ID":139,"question":"Did Ger Browne joined the Knockavilla\u2013Donaskeigh Kickhams club or the Cashel King Cormacs club?","context1":"Ger Browne joined the Knockavilla\u2013Donaskeigh Kickhams club at a young age and played in all grades at juvenile and underage levels before eventually joining the club's top adult team.","context2":"Ger Browne (born 10 May 1998) is an Irish hurler who played for Tipperary Senior Hurling Championship with Cashel King Cormacs and at inter-county level with the Tipperary senior hurling team. He usually lines out as a midfielder.","answer1":"Knockavilla\u2013Donaskeigh Kickhams","answer2":"Cashel King Cormacs ","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Ger Browne joined the Knockavilla\u2013Donaskeigh Kickhams club at a young age and played in all grades at juvenile and underage levels before eventually joining the club's top adult team.\nGer Browne (born 10 May 1998) is an Irish hurler who played for Tipperary Senior Hurling Championship with Cashel King Cormacs and at inter-county level with the Tipperary senior hurling team. He usually lines out as a midfielder.","ref_answer":"Knockavilla\u2013Donaskeigh Kickhams|Cashel King Cormacs ","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Ger Browne","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Ger_Browne"}
{"question_ID":144,"question":"Was Building 98 at Fort D. A. Russell built before 1911?","context1":"Building 98 at Fort D. A. Russell was built in 1920.","context2":"Building 98 at Fort D. A. Russell is the historic US army base bachelor officer quarters, officers club, and grand ballroom near Marfa, Texas; it was active from 1911 to 1946. Building 98 is Located at Fort David A. Russell's central fort complex. It is a project of the International Woman's Foundation and it is the home of the World War II German prisoners of war POW murals.","answer1":"No","answer2":"Yes","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Building 98 at Fort D. A. Russell was built in 1920.\nBuilding 98 at Fort D. A. Russell is the historic US army base bachelor officer quarters, officers club, and grand ballroom near Marfa, Texas; it was active from 1911 to 1946. Building 98 is Located at Fort David A. Russell's central fort complex. It is a project of the International Woman's Foundation and it is the home of the World War II German prisoners of war POW murals.","ref_answer":"No|Yes","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Building 98","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Building_98"}
{"question_ID":145,"question":"Was Building 98 at Fort D. A. Russell active as the historic US army base bachelor officer quarters, officers club, and grand ballroom near Marfa, Texas, before 1920?","context1":"Building 98 at Fort D. A. Russell was built in 1920.","context2":"Building 98 at Fort D. A. Russell is the historic US army base bachelor officer quarters, officers club, and grand ballroom near Marfa, Texas; it was active from 1911 to 1946. Building 98 is Located at Fort David A. Russell's central fort complex. It is a project of the International Woman's Foundation and it is the home of the World War II German prisoners of war POW murals.","answer1":"No","answer2":"Yes","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Building 98 at Fort D. A. Russell was built in 1920.\nBuilding 98 at Fort D. A. Russell is the historic US army base bachelor officer quarters, officers club, and grand ballroom near Marfa, Texas; it was active from 1911 to 1946. Building 98 is Located at Fort David A. Russell's central fort complex. It is a project of the International Woman's Foundation and it is the home of the World War II German prisoners of war POW murals.","ref_answer":"No|Yes","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Building 98","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Building_98"}
{"question_ID":143,"question":"When was Building 98 at Fort D. A. Russell built?","context1":"Building 98 at Fort D. A. Russell was built in 1920.","context2":"Building 98 at Fort D. A. Russell is the historic US army base bachelor officer quarters, officers club, and grand ballroom near Marfa, Texas; it was active from 1911 to 1946. Building 98 is Located at Fort David A. Russell's central fort complex. It is a project of the International Woman's Foundation and it is the home of the World War II German prisoners of war POW murals.","answer1":"1920","answer2":"Before 1911","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Building 98 at Fort D. A. Russell was built in 1920.\nBuilding 98 at Fort D. A. Russell is the historic US army base bachelor officer quarters, officers club, and grand ballroom near Marfa, Texas; it was active from 1911 to 1946. Building 98 is Located at Fort David A. Russell's central fort complex. It is a project of the International Woman's Foundation and it is the home of the World War II German prisoners of war POW murals.","ref_answer":"1920|Before 1911","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Building 98","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Building_98"}
{"question_ID":147,"question":"Was Margery de Burgh's husband, Theobald Butler, 3rd Chief Butler of Ireland, buried in Arklow?","context1":"Margery de Burgh's husband, Theobald Butler, 3rd Chief Butler of Ireland, died 26 December 1248. He was buried before 3 August 1248 at Arklow, County Limerick. On 27 April 1250, she made a fine to remarry.","context2":"Margery de Burgh's husband, Theobald Butler, 3rd Chief Butler of Ireland, died 26 December 1248. He was buried before 3 August 1248 at Arklow, County Limerick. On 27 April 1250, she made a fine to remarry.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"Margery de Burgh's husband, Theobald Butler, 3rd Chief Butler of Ireland, died 26 December 1248. He was buried before 3 August 1248 at Arklow, County Limerick. On 27 April 1250, she made a fine to remarry.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Margery de Burgh","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Margery_de_Burgh"}
{"question_ID":146,"question":"Was Margery de Burgh's husband, Theobald Butler, 3rd Chief Butler of Ireland, buried in County Limerick?","context1":"Margery de Burgh's husband, Theobald Butler, 3rd Chief Butler of Ireland, died 26 December 1248. He was buried before 3 August 1248 at Arklow, County Limerick. On 27 April 1250, she made a fine to remarry.","context2":"Margery de Burgh's husband, Theobald Butler, 3rd Chief Butler of Ireland, died 26 December 1248. He was buried before 3 August 1248 at Arklow, County Limerick. On 27 April 1250, she made a fine to remarry.","answer1":"No","answer2":"Yes","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"Margery de Burgh's husband, Theobald Butler, 3rd Chief Butler of Ireland, died 26 December 1248. He was buried before 3 August 1248 at Arklow, County Limerick. On 27 April 1250, she made a fine to remarry.","ref_answer":"No|Yes","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Margery de Burgh","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Margery_de_Burgh"}
{"question_ID":148,"question":"How common is BMS (Burning mouth syndrome)?","context1":"BMS (Burning mouth syndrome) is fairly uncommon worldwide, affecting up to five individuals per 100,000 general population. People with BMS are more likely to be middle aged or elderly, and females are three to seven times more likely to have BMS than males. Some report a female to male ratio of as much as 33 to 1. BMS is reported in about 10-40% of women seeking medical treatment for menopausal symptoms, and BMS occurs in about 14% of postmenopausal women. Males and younger individuals of both sexes are sometimes affected.","context2":"BMS (Burning mouth syndrome) is fairly uncommon worldwide, affecting up to five individuals per 100,000 general population. People with BMS are more likely to be middle aged or elderly, and females are three to seven times more likely to have BMS than males. Some report a female to male ratio of as much as 33 to 1. BMS is reported in about 10-40% of women seeking medical treatment for menopausal symptoms, and BMS occurs in about 14% of postmenopausal women. Males and younger individuals of both sexes are sometimes affected.","answer1":"BMS (Burning mouth syndrome) is fairly uncommon worldwide, affecting up to five individuals per 100,000 general population.","answer2":"BMS is reported in about 10-40% of women seeking medical treatment for menopausal symptoms, and BMS occurs in about 14% of postmenopausal women.","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"BMS (Burning mouth syndrome) is fairly uncommon worldwide, affecting up to five individuals per 100,000 general population. People with BMS are more likely to be middle aged or elderly, and females are three to seven times more likely to have BMS than males. Some report a female to male ratio of as much as 33 to 1. BMS is reported in about 10-40% of women seeking medical treatment for menopausal symptoms, and BMS occurs in about 14% of postmenopausal women. Males and younger individuals of both sexes are sometimes affected.","ref_answer":"BMS (Burning mouth syndrome) is fairly uncommon worldwide, affecting up to five individuals per 100,000 general population.|BMS is reported in about 10-40% of women seeking medical treatment for menopausal symptoms, and BMS occurs in about 14% of postmenopausal women.","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Burning mouth syndrome","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Burning_mouth_syndrome"}
{"question_ID":150,"question":"Was Charles de Lorraine-Guise the leader of the French party at the April 1555 papal conclave?","context1":"During the April 1555 papal conclave College of Cardinals was divided into three parties:  French party \u2013 the adherents of the king Henry II of France. Their leader was Charles de Lorraine-Guise. Habsburg party \u2013 cardinals aligned with Emperor Charles V. Their leader was Cardinal Juan \u00c1lvarez de Toledo. Italian party \u2013 group of Italian cardinals headed by Alessandro Farnese, Cardinal-nephew of Paul III, with no direct connections with main Catholic powers: Habsburg Empire or France.","context2":"Charles de Lorraine-Guise (July 27, 1547) \u2013 Cardinal-Priest of S. Cecilia; Archbishop of Reims was absent at the April 1555 papal conclave.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"During the April 1555 papal conclave College of Cardinals was divided into three parties:  French party \u2013 the adherents of the king Henry II of France. Their leader was Charles de Lorraine-Guise. Habsburg party \u2013 cardinals aligned with Emperor Charles V. Their leader was Cardinal Juan \u00c1lvarez de Toledo. Italian party \u2013 group of Italian cardinals headed by Alessandro Farnese, Cardinal-nephew of Paul III, with no direct connections with main Catholic powers: Habsburg Empire or France.\nCharles de Lorraine-Guise (July 27, 1547) \u2013 Cardinal-Priest of S. Cecilia; Archbishop of Reims was absent at the April 1555 papal conclave.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"April 1555 papal conclave","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/April_1555_papal_conclave"}
{"question_ID":149,"question":"Was Charles de Lorraine-Guise present at the April 1555 papal conclave?","context1":"During the April 1555 papal conclave College of Cardinals was divided into three parties:  French party \u2013 the adherents of the king Henry II of France. Their leader was Charles de Lorraine-Guise. Habsburg party \u2013 cardinals aligned with Emperor Charles V. Their leader was Cardinal Juan \u00c1lvarez de Toledo. Italian party \u2013 group of Italian cardinals headed by Alessandro Farnese, Cardinal-nephew of Paul III, with no direct connections with main Catholic powers: Habsburg Empire or France.","context2":"Charles de Lorraine-Guise (July 27, 1547) \u2013 Cardinal-Priest of S. Cecilia; Archbishop of Reims was absent at the April 1555 papal conclave.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"During the April 1555 papal conclave College of Cardinals was divided into three parties:  French party \u2013 the adherents of the king Henry II of France. Their leader was Charles de Lorraine-Guise. Habsburg party \u2013 cardinals aligned with Emperor Charles V. Their leader was Cardinal Juan \u00c1lvarez de Toledo. Italian party \u2013 group of Italian cardinals headed by Alessandro Farnese, Cardinal-nephew of Paul III, with no direct connections with main Catholic powers: Habsburg Empire or France.\nCharles de Lorraine-Guise (July 27, 1547) \u2013 Cardinal-Priest of S. Cecilia; Archbishop of Reims was absent at the April 1555 papal conclave.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"April 1555 papal conclave","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/April_1555_papal_conclave"}
{"question_ID":152,"question":"Was the Italian Party at the April 1555 papal conclave headed by Alessandro Farnese?","context1":"During the April 1555 papal conclave College of Cardinals was divided into three parties: French party \u2013 the adherents of the king Henry II of France. Their leader was Charles de Lorraine-Guise. Habsburg party \u2013 cardinals aligned with Emperor Charles V. Their leader was Cardinal Juan \u00c1lvarez de Toledo. Italian party \u2013 group of Italian cardinals headed by Alessandro Farnese, Cardinal-nephew of Paul III, with no direct connections with main Catholic powers: Habsburg Empire or France.","context2":"Alessandro Farnese (December 18, 1534) \u2013 Cardinal-Deacon of S. Lorenzo in Damaso; Vice-Chancellor of the Holy Roman Church; Archpriest of the patriarchal Vatican Basilica; Legate in Avignon; Administrator of Monreale and Cahors; Cardinal-protector of Poland, Portugal, Germany, Kingdom of Sicily, Republic of Genoa and Republic of Ragusa; Cardinal-protector of the Orders of Benedictines and Servites, was absent at the April 1555 papal conclave.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"During the April 1555 papal conclave College of Cardinals was divided into three parties: French party \u2013 the adherents of the king Henry II of France. Their leader was Charles de Lorraine-Guise. Habsburg party \u2013 cardinals aligned with Emperor Charles V. Their leader was Cardinal Juan \u00c1lvarez de Toledo. Italian party \u2013 group of Italian cardinals headed by Alessandro Farnese, Cardinal-nephew of Paul III, with no direct connections with main Catholic powers: Habsburg Empire or France.\nAlessandro Farnese (December 18, 1534) \u2013 Cardinal-Deacon of S. Lorenzo in Damaso; Vice-Chancellor of the Holy Roman Church; Archpriest of the patriarchal Vatican Basilica; Legate in Avignon; Administrator of Monreale and Cahors; Cardinal-protector of Poland, Portugal, Germany, Kingdom of Sicily, Republic of Genoa and Republic of Ragusa; Cardinal-protector of the Orders of Benedictines and Servites, was absent at the April 1555 papal conclave.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"April 1555 papal conclave","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/April_1555_papal_conclave"}
{"question_ID":151,"question":"Was Alessandro Farnese present at the April 1555 papal conclave?","context1":"During the April 1555 papal conclave College of Cardinals was divided into three parties: French party \u2013 the adherents of the king Henry II of France. Their leader was Charles de Lorraine-Guise. Habsburg party \u2013 cardinals aligned with Emperor Charles V. Their leader was Cardinal Juan \u00c1lvarez de Toledo. Italian party \u2013 group of Italian cardinals headed by Alessandro Farnese, Cardinal-nephew of Paul III, with no direct connections with main Catholic powers: Habsburg Empire or France.","context2":"Alessandro Farnese (December 18, 1534) \u2013 Cardinal-Deacon of S. Lorenzo in Damaso; Vice-Chancellor of the Holy Roman Church; Archpriest of the patriarchal Vatican Basilica; Legate in Avignon; Administrator of Monreale and Cahors; Cardinal-protector of Poland, Portugal, Germany, Kingdom of Sicily, Republic of Genoa and Republic of Ragusa; Cardinal-protector of the Orders of Benedictines and Servites, was absent at the April 1555 papal conclave.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"During the April 1555 papal conclave College of Cardinals was divided into three parties: French party \u2013 the adherents of the king Henry II of France. Their leader was Charles de Lorraine-Guise. Habsburg party \u2013 cardinals aligned with Emperor Charles V. Their leader was Cardinal Juan \u00c1lvarez de Toledo. Italian party \u2013 group of Italian cardinals headed by Alessandro Farnese, Cardinal-nephew of Paul III, with no direct connections with main Catholic powers: Habsburg Empire or France.\nAlessandro Farnese (December 18, 1534) \u2013 Cardinal-Deacon of S. Lorenzo in Damaso; Vice-Chancellor of the Holy Roman Church; Archpriest of the patriarchal Vatican Basilica; Legate in Avignon; Administrator of Monreale and Cahors; Cardinal-protector of Poland, Portugal, Germany, Kingdom of Sicily, Republic of Genoa and Republic of Ragusa; Cardinal-protector of the Orders of Benedictines and Servites, was absent at the April 1555 papal conclave.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"April 1555 papal conclave","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/April_1555_papal_conclave"}
{"question_ID":154,"question":"Which teams played the 1961 All-Ireland Senior Camogie Championship final?","context1":"The 1961 All-Ireland Senior Camogie Championship Final was the thirtieth All-Ireland Final and the deciding match of the 1961 All-Ireland Senior Camogie Championship, an inter-county camogie tournament for the top teams in Ireland.  Tipperary's prospects looked strong at half-time: after playing against the wind with the sun in their eyes, they were only a point down. But Dublin won in end, with Kathleen Mills finishing her career with a record fifteenth All-Ireland medal. Judy Doyle (Dublin) scored a hat-trick.","context2":"The All-Ireland Senior Camogie Championship 1961 was played Dublin vs Galway.","answer1":"Tipperary and Dublin.","answer2":"Galway and Dublin.","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"The 1961 All-Ireland Senior Camogie Championship Final was the thirtieth All-Ireland Final and the deciding match of the 1961 All-Ireland Senior Camogie Championship, an inter-county camogie tournament for the top teams in Ireland.  Tipperary's prospects looked strong at half-time: after playing against the wind with the sun in their eyes, they were only a point down. But Dublin won in end, with Kathleen Mills finishing her career with a record fifteenth All-Ireland medal. Judy Doyle (Dublin) scored a hat-trick.\nThe All-Ireland Senior Camogie Championship 1961 was played Dublin vs Galway.","ref_answer":"Tipperary and Dublin.|Galway and Dublin.","WikipediaArticleTitle":"1961 All-Ireland Senior Camogie Championship final","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/1961_All-Ireland_Senior_Camogie_Championship_final"}
{"question_ID":153,"question":"Did Tipperary or Galway played the 1961 All-Ireland Senior Camogie Championship final against Dublin?","context1":"The 1961 All-Ireland Senior Camogie Championship Final was the thirtieth All-Ireland Final and the deciding match of the 1961 All-Ireland Senior Camogie Championship, an inter-county camogie tournament for the top teams in Ireland.  Tipperary's prospects looked strong at half-time: after playing against the wind with the sun in their eyes, they were only a point down. But Dublin won in end, with Kathleen Mills finishing her career with a record fifteenth All-Ireland medal. Judy Doyle (Dublin) scored a hat-trick.","context2":"The All-Ireland Senior Camogie Championship 1961 was played Dublin vs Galway.","answer1":"Tipperary","answer2":"Galway","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"The 1961 All-Ireland Senior Camogie Championship Final was the thirtieth All-Ireland Final and the deciding match of the 1961 All-Ireland Senior Camogie Championship, an inter-county camogie tournament for the top teams in Ireland.  Tipperary's prospects looked strong at half-time: after playing against the wind with the sun in their eyes, they were only a point down. But Dublin won in end, with Kathleen Mills finishing her career with a record fifteenth All-Ireland medal. Judy Doyle (Dublin) scored a hat-trick.\nThe All-Ireland Senior Camogie Championship 1961 was played Dublin vs Galway.","ref_answer":"Tipperary|Galway","WikipediaArticleTitle":"1961 All-Ireland Senior Camogie Championship final","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/1961_All-Ireland_Senior_Camogie_Championship_final"}
{"question_ID":156,"question":"There were more or less than 70 tornadoes confirmed during the October 2010 North American storm complex?","context1":"There were 69 tornadoes confirmed in the October 2010 North American storm complex.","context2":"During the October 2010 North American storm complex the cold front tracked eastward on October 27 as the storm weakened. Additional tornadoes developed across the Mid-Atlantic states as the atmosphere remained unstable. In the end, with 87 tornadoes confirmed, it was the largest October tornado outbreak ever recorded, even though none of the tornadoes were stronger than EF2 and there were no fatalities.","answer1":"Less","answer2":"More","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"There were 69 tornadoes confirmed in the October 2010 North American storm complex.\nDuring the October 2010 North American storm complex the cold front tracked eastward on October 27 as the storm weakened. Additional tornadoes developed across the Mid-Atlantic states as the atmosphere remained unstable. In the end, with 87 tornadoes confirmed, it was the largest October tornado outbreak ever recorded, even though none of the tornadoes were stronger than EF2 and there were no fatalities.","ref_answer":"Less|More","WikipediaArticleTitle":"October 2010 North American storm complex","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/October_2010_North_American_storm_complex"}
{"question_ID":155,"question":"How many tornadoes were confirmed during the October 2010 North American storm complex?","context1":"There were 69 tornadoes confirmed in the October 2010 North American storm complex.","context2":"During the October 2010 North American storm complex the cold front tracked eastward on October 27 as the storm weakened. Additional tornadoes developed across the Mid-Atlantic states as the atmosphere remained unstable. In the end, with 87 tornadoes confirmed, it was the largest October tornado outbreak ever recorded, even though none of the tornadoes were stronger than EF2 and there were no fatalities.","answer1":"69","answer2":"87","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"There were 69 tornadoes confirmed in the October 2010 North American storm complex.\nDuring the October 2010 North American storm complex the cold front tracked eastward on October 27 as the storm weakened. Additional tornadoes developed across the Mid-Atlantic states as the atmosphere remained unstable. In the end, with 87 tornadoes confirmed, it was the largest October tornado outbreak ever recorded, even though none of the tornadoes were stronger than EF2 and there were no fatalities.","ref_answer":"69|87","WikipediaArticleTitle":"October 2010 North American storm complex","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/October_2010_North_American_storm_complex"}
{"question_ID":158,"question":"Is \"All-Russian voting\" provisioned by Article 2 of the draft law on making amendments to the Russian Constitution?","context1":"The renewal of the Russian Constitution requires neither a referendum, nor convening of the Constitutional Assembly, but \"All-Russian voting\" (Russian: \u043e\u0431\u0449\u0435\u0440\u043e\u0441\u0441\u0438\u0439\u0441\u043a\u043e\u0435 \u0433\u043e\u043b\u043e\u0441\u043e\u0432\u0430\u043d\u0438\u0435, romanized: obshcherossiyskoye golosovaniye) is provisioned by Article 2 of the draft law on making amendments to the Russian Constitution. Putin introduced this term for the first time and it is not a legal term with clear definition. All-Russian voting is not provisioned by the constitution or mentioned in any federal laws, regional laws or any other legal documents.","context2":"The renewal of the Russian Constitution requires neither a referendum, nor convening of the Constitutional Assembly, but \"All-Russian voting\" (Russian: \u043e\u0431\u0449\u0435\u0440\u043e\u0441\u0441\u0438\u0439\u0441\u043a\u043e\u0435 \u0433\u043e\u043b\u043e\u0441\u043e\u0432\u0430\u043d\u0438\u0435, romanized: obshcherossiyskoye golosovaniye) is provisioned by Article 2 of the draft law on making amendments to the Russian Constitution. Putin introduced this term for the first time and it is not a legal term with clear definition. All-Russian voting is not provisioned by the constitution or mentioned in any federal laws, regional laws or any other legal documents.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"The renewal of the Russian Constitution requires neither a referendum, nor convening of the Constitutional Assembly, but \"All-Russian voting\" (Russian: \u043e\u0431\u0449\u0435\u0440\u043e\u0441\u0441\u0438\u0439\u0441\u043a\u043e\u0435 \u0433\u043e\u043b\u043e\u0441\u043e\u0432\u0430\u043d\u0438\u0435, romanized: obshcherossiyskoye golosovaniye) is provisioned by Article 2 of the draft law on making amendments to the Russian Constitution. Putin introduced this term for the first time and it is not a legal term with clear definition. All-Russian voting is not provisioned by the constitution or mentioned in any federal laws, regional laws or any other legal documents.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"2020 Russian constitutional referendum","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/2020_Russian_constitutional_referendum"}
{"question_ID":157,"question":"Is the All-Russian voting provisioned by the constitution or mentioned in any federal laws, regional laws or any other legal documents?","context1":"The renewal of the Russian Constitution requires neither a referendum, nor convening of the Constitutional Assembly, but \"All-Russian voting\" (Russian: \u043e\u0431\u0449\u0435\u0440\u043e\u0441\u0441\u0438\u0439\u0441\u043a\u043e\u0435 \u0433\u043e\u043b\u043e\u0441\u043e\u0432\u0430\u043d\u0438\u0435, romanized: obshcherossiyskoye golosovaniye) is provisioned by Article 2 of the draft law on making amendments to the Russian Constitution. Putin introduced this term for the first time and it is not a legal term with clear definition. All-Russian voting is not provisioned by the constitution or mentioned in any federal laws, regional laws or any other legal documents.","context2":"The renewal of the Russian Constitution requires neither a referendum, nor convening of the Constitutional Assembly, but \"All-Russian voting\" (Russian: \u043e\u0431\u0449\u0435\u0440\u043e\u0441\u0441\u0438\u0439\u0441\u043a\u043e\u0435 \u0433\u043e\u043b\u043e\u0441\u043e\u0432\u0430\u043d\u0438\u0435, romanized: obshcherossiyskoye golosovaniye) is provisioned by Article 2 of the draft law on making amendments to the Russian Constitution. Putin introduced this term for the first time and it is not a legal term with clear definition. All-Russian voting is not provisioned by the constitution or mentioned in any federal laws, regional laws or any other legal documents.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"The renewal of the Russian Constitution requires neither a referendum, nor convening of the Constitutional Assembly, but \"All-Russian voting\" (Russian: \u043e\u0431\u0449\u0435\u0440\u043e\u0441\u0441\u0438\u0439\u0441\u043a\u043e\u0435 \u0433\u043e\u043b\u043e\u0441\u043e\u0432\u0430\u043d\u0438\u0435, romanized: obshcherossiyskoye golosovaniye) is provisioned by Article 2 of the draft law on making amendments to the Russian Constitution. Putin introduced this term for the first time and it is not a legal term with clear definition. All-Russian voting is not provisioned by the constitution or mentioned in any federal laws, regional laws or any other legal documents.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"2020 Russian constitutional referendum","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/2020_Russian_constitutional_referendum"}
{"question_ID":160,"question":"Was the Relegation play-off of the 2021 Carlow Senior Football Championship played in 2021?","context1":"The 2021 Carlow Senior Football Championship was the 121st edition of the Carlow GAA's premier club Gaelic football tournament for senior graded clubs in County Carlow, Ireland. ","context2":"The Relegation play-off for the 2021 Carlow Senior Football Championship was played on the 24th of September 2019.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"The 2021 Carlow Senior Football Championship was the 121st edition of the Carlow GAA's premier club Gaelic football tournament for senior graded clubs in County Carlow, Ireland. \nThe Relegation play-off for the 2021 Carlow Senior Football Championship was played on the 24th of September 2019.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"2021 Carlow Senior Football Championship","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/2021_Carlow_Senior_Football_Championship"}
{"question_ID":159,"question":"When was the Relegation play-off of the 2021 Carlow Senior Football Championship played?","context1":"The 2021 Carlow Senior Football Championship was the 121st edition of the Carlow GAA's premier club Gaelic football tournament for senior graded clubs in County Carlow, Ireland. ","context2":"The Relegation play-off for the 2021 Carlow Senior Football Championship was played on the 24th of September 2019.","answer1":"2021","answer2":"24th of September 2019","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"The 2021 Carlow Senior Football Championship was the 121st edition of the Carlow GAA's premier club Gaelic football tournament for senior graded clubs in County Carlow, Ireland. \nThe Relegation play-off for the 2021 Carlow Senior Football Championship was played on the 24th of September 2019.","ref_answer":"2021|24th of September 2019","WikipediaArticleTitle":"2021 Carlow Senior Football Championship","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/2021_Carlow_Senior_Football_Championship"}
{"question_ID":162,"question":"Does the adult human brain weigh 1.5 kg (3.3 lb) on average?","context1":"In humans, the right cerebral hemisphere is typically larger than the left, whereas the cerebellar hemispheres are typically closer in size. The adult human brain weighs on average about 1.5 kg (3.3 lb). In men the average weight is about 1370 g and in women about 1200 g.","context2":"In humans, the right cerebral hemisphere is typically larger than the left, whereas the cerebellar hemispheres are typically closer in size. The adult human brain weighs on average about 1.5 kg (3.3 lb). In men the average weight is about 1370 g and in women about 1200 g.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"In humans, the right cerebral hemisphere is typically larger than the left, whereas the cerebellar hemispheres are typically closer in size. The adult human brain weighs on average about 1.5 kg (3.3 lb). In men the average weight is about 1370 g and in women about 1200 g.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Brain size","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Brain_size"}
{"question_ID":163,"question":"Does the adult human brain weigh 1.285 kg on average?","context1":"In humans, the right cerebral hemisphere is typically larger than the left, whereas the cerebellar hemispheres are typically closer in size. The adult human brain weighs on average about 1.5 kg (3.3 lb). In men the average weight is about 1370 g and in women about 1200 g.","context2":"In humans, the right cerebral hemisphere is typically larger than the left, whereas the cerebellar hemispheres are typically closer in size. The adult human brain weighs on average about 1.5 kg (3.3 lb). In men the average weight is about 1370 g and in women about 1200 g.","answer1":"No","answer2":"Yes","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"In humans, the right cerebral hemisphere is typically larger than the left, whereas the cerebellar hemispheres are typically closer in size. The adult human brain weighs on average about 1.5 kg (3.3 lb). In men the average weight is about 1370 g and in women about 1200 g.","ref_answer":"No|Yes","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Brain size","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Brain_size"}
{"question_ID":161,"question":"How much does the adult human brain weigh on average?","context1":"In humans, the right cerebral hemisphere is typically larger than the left, whereas the cerebellar hemispheres are typically closer in size. The adult human brain weighs on average about 1.5 kg (3.3 lb). In men the average weight is about 1370 g and in women about 1200 g.","context2":"In humans, the right cerebral hemisphere is typically larger than the left, whereas the cerebellar hemispheres are typically closer in size. The adult human brain weighs on average about 1.5 kg (3.3 lb). In men the average weight is about 1370 g and in women about 1200 g.","answer1":"1.5 kg (3.3 lb)","answer2":"1.285 kg","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"In humans, the right cerebral hemisphere is typically larger than the left, whereas the cerebellar hemispheres are typically closer in size. The adult human brain weighs on average about 1.5 kg (3.3 lb). In men the average weight is about 1370 g and in women about 1200 g.","ref_answer":"1.5 kg (3.3 lb)|1.285 kg","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Brain size","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Brain_size"}
{"question_ID":165,"question":"Do the Eastern Orthodox Church reject the incompatibility of Eastern Orthodox and Roman Catholic churches?","context1":"Eastern Orthodox Church reject as incompatible with the Orthodox faith any such use of the \"two lungs\" expression to imply that the Eastern Orthodox and Roman Catholic churches are two parts of a single church and \"that Orthodoxy is only for Easterners, and that Catholicism is only for Westerners\", according to Archpriest Andrew Phillips. Patriarch Bartholomew I of Constantinople (spiritual leader of the Eastern Orthodox Christians worldwide) \"rejects the opinion\" that \"there would be an 'incompatibility between Orthodox tradition and the European cultural way', which would be antinomic\" and points out that idea \"is against the principle of equality and respect of peoples and cultural traditions on our continent.\"","context2":"Eastern Orthodox Church reject as incompatible with the Orthodox faith any such use of the \"two lungs\" expression to imply that the Eastern Orthodox and Roman Catholic churches are two parts of a single church and \"that Orthodoxy is only for Easterners, and that Catholicism is only for Westerners\", according to Archpriest Andrew Phillips. Patriarch Bartholomew I of Constantinople  (spiritual leader of the Eastern Orthodox Christians worldwide) \"rejects the opinion\" that \"there would be an 'incompatibility between Orthodox tradition and the European cultural way', which would be antinomic\" and points out that idea \"is against the principle of equality and respect of peoples and cultural traditions on our continent.\"","answer1":"No","answer2":"Yes","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"Eastern Orthodox Church reject as incompatible with the Orthodox faith any such use of the \"two lungs\" expression to imply that the Eastern Orthodox and Roman Catholic churches are two parts of a single church and \"that Orthodoxy is only for Easterners, and that Catholicism is only for Westerners\", according to Archpriest Andrew Phillips. Patriarch Bartholomew I of Constantinople (spiritual leader of the Eastern Orthodox Christians worldwide) \"rejects the opinion\" that \"there would be an 'incompatibility between Orthodox tradition and the European cultural way', which would be antinomic\" and points out that idea \"is against the principle of equality and respect of peoples and cultural traditions on our continent.\"","ref_answer":"No|Yes","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Branch theory","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Branch_theory"}
{"question_ID":164,"question":"Do the Eastern Orthodox Church reject the metaphor of Christianity compared to one body breathing with two lungs: Eastern Orthodox and Roman Catholic churches?","context1":"Eastern Orthodox Church reject as incompatible with the Orthodox faith any such use of the \"two lungs\" expression to imply that the Eastern Orthodox and Roman Catholic churches are two parts of a single church and \"that Orthodoxy is only for Easterners, and that Catholicism is only for Westerners\", according to Archpriest Andrew Phillips. Patriarch Bartholomew I of Constantinople (spiritual leader of the Eastern Orthodox Christians worldwide) \"rejects the opinion\" that \"there would be an 'incompatibility between Orthodox tradition and the European cultural way', which would be antinomic\" and points out that idea \"is against the principle of equality and respect of peoples and cultural traditions on our continent.\"","context2":"Eastern Orthodox Church reject as incompatible with the Orthodox faith any such use of the \"two lungs\" expression to imply that the Eastern Orthodox and Roman Catholic churches are two parts of a single church and \"that Orthodoxy is only for Easterners, and that Catholicism is only for Westerners\", according to Archpriest Andrew Phillips. Patriarch Bartholomew I of Constantinople  (spiritual leader of the Eastern Orthodox Christians worldwide) \"rejects the opinion\" that \"there would be an 'incompatibility between Orthodox tradition and the European cultural way', which would be antinomic\" and points out that idea \"is against the principle of equality and respect of peoples and cultural traditions on our continent.\"","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"Eastern Orthodox Church reject as incompatible with the Orthodox faith any such use of the \"two lungs\" expression to imply that the Eastern Orthodox and Roman Catholic churches are two parts of a single church and \"that Orthodoxy is only for Easterners, and that Catholicism is only for Westerners\", according to Archpriest Andrew Phillips. Patriarch Bartholomew I of Constantinople (spiritual leader of the Eastern Orthodox Christians worldwide) \"rejects the opinion\" that \"there would be an 'incompatibility between Orthodox tradition and the European cultural way', which would be antinomic\" and points out that idea \"is against the principle of equality and respect of peoples and cultural traditions on our continent.\"","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Branch theory","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Branch_theory"}
{"question_ID":167,"question":"Is the given name Brandon derived from Old English?","context1":"Brandon is a masculine given name that is a transferred use of a surname and place name derived from the Old English br\u014dm, meaning broom or gorse, and d\u016bn, meaning hill. It is also sometimes a variant of the Irish masculine given name, Breand\u00e1n, meaning \"prince\".","context2":"Brandon is a masculine given name that is a transferred use of a surname and place name derived from the Old English br\u014dm, meaning broom or gorse, and d\u016bn, meaning hill. It is also sometimes a variant of the Irish masculine given name, Breand\u00e1n, meaning \"prince\".","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"Brandon is a masculine given name that is a transferred use of a surname and place name derived from the Old English br\u014dm, meaning broom or gorse, and d\u016bn, meaning hill. It is also sometimes a variant of the Irish masculine given name, Breand\u00e1n, meaning \"prince\".","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Brandon (given name)","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Brandon_(given_name)"}
{"question_ID":168,"question":"Is the given name Brandon derived from Irish?","context1":"Brandon is a masculine given name that is a transferred use of a surname and place name derived from the Old English br\u014dm, meaning broom or gorse, and d\u016bn, meaning hill. It is also sometimes a variant of the Irish masculine given name, Breand\u00e1n, meaning \"prince\".","context2":"Brandon is a masculine given name that is a transferred use of a surname and place name derived from the Old English br\u014dm, meaning broom or gorse, and d\u016bn, meaning hill. It is also sometimes a variant of the Irish masculine given name, Breand\u00e1n, meaning \"prince\".","answer1":"No","answer2":"Yes","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"Brandon is a masculine given name that is a transferred use of a surname and place name derived from the Old English br\u014dm, meaning broom or gorse, and d\u016bn, meaning hill. It is also sometimes a variant of the Irish masculine given name, Breand\u00e1n, meaning \"prince\".","ref_answer":"No|Yes","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Brandon (given name)","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Brandon_(given_name)"}
{"question_ID":169,"question":"From which name is the given name Brandon derived?","context1":"Brandon is a masculine given name that is a transferred use of a surname and place name derived from the Old English br\u014dm, meaning broom or gorse, and d\u016bn, meaning hill. It is also sometimes a variant of the Irish masculine given name, Breand\u00e1n, meaning \"prince\".","context2":"Brandon is a masculine given name that is a transferred use of a surname and place name derived from the Old English br\u014dm, meaning broom or gorse, and d\u016bn, meaning hill. It is also sometimes a variant of the Irish masculine given name, Breand\u00e1n, meaning \"prince\".","answer1":"br\u014dm","answer2":"Breand\u00e1n","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"Brandon is a masculine given name that is a transferred use of a surname and place name derived from the Old English br\u014dm, meaning broom or gorse, and d\u016bn, meaning hill. It is also sometimes a variant of the Irish masculine given name, Breand\u00e1n, meaning \"prince\".","ref_answer":"br\u014dm|Breand\u00e1n","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Brandon (given name)","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Brandon_(given_name)"}
{"question_ID":170,"question":"Is the given name Brandon derived from br\u014dm?","context1":"Brandon is a masculine given name that is a transferred use of a surname and place name derived from the Old English br\u014dm, meaning broom or gorse, and d\u016bn, meaning hill. It is also sometimes a variant of the Irish masculine given name, Breand\u00e1n, meaning \"prince\".","context2":"Brandon is a masculine given name that is a transferred use of a surname and place name derived from the Old English br\u014dm, meaning broom or gorse, and d\u016bn, meaning hill. It is also sometimes a variant of the Irish masculine given name, Breand\u00e1n, meaning \"prince\".","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"Brandon is a masculine given name that is a transferred use of a surname and place name derived from the Old English br\u014dm, meaning broom or gorse, and d\u016bn, meaning hill. It is also sometimes a variant of the Irish masculine given name, Breand\u00e1n, meaning \"prince\".","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Brandon (given name)","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Brandon_(given_name)"}
{"question_ID":171,"question":"Is the given name Brandon derived from Breand\u00e1n?","context1":"Brandon is a masculine given name that is a transferred use of a surname and place name derived from the Old English br\u014dm, meaning broom or gorse, and d\u016bn, meaning hill. It is also sometimes a variant of the Irish masculine given name, Breand\u00e1n, meaning \"prince\".","context2":"Brandon is a masculine given name that is a transferred use of a surname and place name derived from the Old English br\u014dm, meaning broom or gorse, and d\u016bn, meaning hill. It is also sometimes a variant of the Irish masculine given name, Breand\u00e1n, meaning \"prince\".","answer1":"No","answer2":"Yes","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"Brandon is a masculine given name that is a transferred use of a surname and place name derived from the Old English br\u014dm, meaning broom or gorse, and d\u016bn, meaning hill. It is also sometimes a variant of the Irish masculine given name, Breand\u00e1n, meaning \"prince\".","ref_answer":"No|Yes","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Brandon (given name)","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Brandon_(given_name)"}
{"question_ID":166,"question":"From which language is the given name Brandon derived?","context1":"Brandon is a masculine given name that is a transferred use of a surname and place name derived from the Old English br\u014dm, meaning broom or gorse, and d\u016bn, meaning hill. It is also sometimes a variant of the Irish masculine given name, Breand\u00e1n, meaning \"prince\".","context2":"Brandon is a masculine given name that is a transferred use of a surname and place name derived from the Old English br\u014dm, meaning broom or gorse, and d\u016bn, meaning hill. It is also sometimes a variant of the Irish masculine given name, Breand\u00e1n, meaning \"prince\".","answer1":"Old English","answer2":"Irish","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"Brandon is a masculine given name that is a transferred use of a surname and place name derived from the Old English br\u014dm, meaning broom or gorse, and d\u016bn, meaning hill. It is also sometimes a variant of the Irish masculine given name, Breand\u00e1n, meaning \"prince\".","ref_answer":"Old English|Irish","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Brandon (given name)","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Brandon_(given_name)"}
{"question_ID":173,"question":"Is Bremen the fifth largest city in Germany by area?","context1":"In terms of area, Bremen is the eleventh largest city in Germany; and in terms of population the second largest city in northwest Germany after Hamburg and the eleventh largest in the whole of Germany.","context2":"Today Bremen has a population of 567,000 and is the 11th largest city in Germany and 5th largest city by area with area of 318.21 km2 (122.86 sq mi), which makes this city area bigger than Munich.","answer1":"No","answer2":"Yes","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"In terms of area, Bremen is the eleventh largest city in Germany; and in terms of population the second largest city in northwest Germany after Hamburg and the eleventh largest in the whole of Germany.\nToday Bremen has a population of 567,000 and is the 11th largest city in Germany and 5th largest city by area with area of 318.21 km2 (122.86 sq mi), which makes this city area bigger than Munich.","ref_answer":"No|Yes","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Bremen","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Bremen"}
{"question_ID":174,"question":"How is Bremen ranked in Germany in terms of largest cities by area?","context1":"In terms of area, Bremen is the eleventh largest city in Germany; and in terms of population the second largest city in northwest Germany after Hamburg and the eleventh largest in the whole of Germany.","context2":"Today Bremen has a population of 567,000 and is the 11th largest city in Germany and 5th largest city by area with area of 318.21 km2 (122.86 sq mi), which makes this city area bigger than Munich.","answer1":"eleventh (11th)","answer2":"fifth (5th)","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"In terms of area, Bremen is the eleventh largest city in Germany; and in terms of population the second largest city in northwest Germany after Hamburg and the eleventh largest in the whole of Germany.\nToday Bremen has a population of 567,000 and is the 11th largest city in Germany and 5th largest city by area with area of 318.21 km2 (122.86 sq mi), which makes this city area bigger than Munich.","ref_answer":"eleventh (11th)|fifth (5th)","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Bremen","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Bremen"}
{"question_ID":172,"question":"Is Bremen the eleventh largest city in Germany by area?","context1":"In terms of area, Bremen is the eleventh largest city in Germany; and in terms of population the second largest city in northwest Germany after Hamburg and the eleventh largest in the whole of Germany.","context2":"Today Bremen has a population of 567,000 and is the 11th largest city in Germany and 5th largest city by area with area of 318.21 km2 (122.86 sq mi), which makes this city area bigger than Munich.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"In terms of area, Bremen is the eleventh largest city in Germany; and in terms of population the second largest city in northwest Germany after Hamburg and the eleventh largest in the whole of Germany.\nToday Bremen has a population of 567,000 and is the 11th largest city in Germany and 5th largest city by area with area of 318.21 km2 (122.86 sq mi), which makes this city area bigger than Munich.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Bremen","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Bremen"}
{"question_ID":176,"question":"How is the bribery of senior Wehrmacht officers considered: legal or illegal?","context1":"From 1933 to the end of the Second World War, high-ranking officers of the Armed Forces of Nazi Germany accepted vast bribes in the form of cash, estates, and tax exemptions in exchange for their loyalty to Nazism. Diego Gambetta argues that this practice can be considered selective incentives rather than bribery, since bribery must involve three agents (the truster, the fiduciary, and the corrupter) rather than two. In this case, Hitler's generals (the fiduciary) were paid to do what they were supposed to do for him (the truster, and not the corrupter) in any case. However, by accepting the gifts, the generals sacrificed the independence and the political influence they had already been losing as the result of the systematic consolidation of Hitler's role as the sole \"genius strategist\", and would remain chained to Hitler's decisions even when their soldiers and the common people suffered during the last phase of the war. Thus, historians consider the practice, although \"not technically illegal\" (since the gifts were granted by Hitler himself), \"smacking of corruption\" and \"having an aura of deliberate corruption from above.\"","context2":"From 1933 to the end of the Second World War, high-ranking officers of the Armed Forces of Nazi Germany accepted vast bribes in the form of cash, estates, and tax exemptions in exchange for their loyalty to Nazism. Before any officer began to receive money, they met with Hans Lammers (chief of Nazi Germany's Chancellery), who informed them that future payments would depend on how much loyalty they were willing to show Hitler. They were advised that what he gave with one hand could just as easily be taken away with the other. The illicit nature of the payments was emphasised by Hans Lammers's warning to them not to speak about the payments to anyone and to keep as few written records as possible.","answer1":"Legal","answer2":"Illegal","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"From 1933 to the end of the Second World War, high-ranking officers of the Armed Forces of Nazi Germany accepted vast bribes in the form of cash, estates, and tax exemptions in exchange for their loyalty to Nazism. Diego Gambetta argues that this practice can be considered selective incentives rather than bribery, since bribery must involve three agents (the truster, the fiduciary, and the corrupter) rather than two. In this case, Hitler's generals (the fiduciary) were paid to do what they were supposed to do for him (the truster, and not the corrupter) in any case. However, by accepting the gifts, the generals sacrificed the independence and the political influence they had already been losing as the result of the systematic consolidation of Hitler's role as the sole \"genius strategist\", and would remain chained to Hitler's decisions even when their soldiers and the common people suffered during the last phase of the war. Thus, historians consider the practice, although \"not technically illegal\" (since the gifts were granted by Hitler himself), \"smacking of corruption\" and \"having an aura of deliberate corruption from above.\"\nFrom 1933 to the end of the Second World War, high-ranking officers of the Armed Forces of Nazi Germany accepted vast bribes in the form of cash, estates, and tax exemptions in exchange for their loyalty to Nazism. Before any officer began to receive money, they met with Hans Lammers (chief of Nazi Germany's Chancellery), who informed them that future payments would depend on how much loyalty they were willing to show Hitler. They were advised that what he gave with one hand could just as easily be taken away with the other. The illicit nature of the payments was emphasised by Hans Lammers's warning to them not to speak about the payments to anyone and to keep as few written records as possible.","ref_answer":"Legal|Illegal","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Bribery of senior Wehrmacht officers","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Bribery_of_senior_Wehrmacht_officers"}
{"question_ID":175,"question":"Is the bribery of senior Wehrmacht officers considered illegal?","context1":"From 1933 to the end of the Second World War, high-ranking officers of the Armed Forces of Nazi Germany accepted vast bribes in the form of cash, estates, and tax exemptions in exchange for their loyalty to Nazism. Diego Gambetta argues that this practice can be considered selective incentives rather than bribery, since bribery must involve three agents (the truster, the fiduciary, and the corrupter) rather than two. In this case, Hitler's generals (the fiduciary) were paid to do what they were supposed to do for him (the truster, and not the corrupter) in any case. However, by accepting the gifts, the generals sacrificed the independence and the political influence they had already been losing as the result of the systematic consolidation of Hitler's role as the sole \"genius strategist\", and would remain chained to Hitler's decisions even when their soldiers and the common people suffered during the last phase of the war. Thus, historians consider the practice, although \"not technically illegal\" (since the gifts were granted by Hitler himself), \"smacking of corruption\" and \"having an aura of deliberate corruption from above.\"","context2":"From 1933 to the end of the Second World War, high-ranking officers of the Armed Forces of Nazi Germany accepted vast bribes in the form of cash, estates, and tax exemptions in exchange for their loyalty to Nazism. Before any officer began to receive money, they met with Hans Lammers (chief of Nazi Germany's Chancellery), who informed them that future payments would depend on how much loyalty they were willing to show Hitler. They were advised that what he gave with one hand could just as easily be taken away with the other. The illicit nature of the payments was emphasised by Hans Lammers's warning to them not to speak about the payments to anyone and to keep as few written records as possible.","answer1":"No","answer2":"Yes","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"From 1933 to the end of the Second World War, high-ranking officers of the Armed Forces of Nazi Germany accepted vast bribes in the form of cash, estates, and tax exemptions in exchange for their loyalty to Nazism. Diego Gambetta argues that this practice can be considered selective incentives rather than bribery, since bribery must involve three agents (the truster, the fiduciary, and the corrupter) rather than two. In this case, Hitler's generals (the fiduciary) were paid to do what they were supposed to do for him (the truster, and not the corrupter) in any case. However, by accepting the gifts, the generals sacrificed the independence and the political influence they had already been losing as the result of the systematic consolidation of Hitler's role as the sole \"genius strategist\", and would remain chained to Hitler's decisions even when their soldiers and the common people suffered during the last phase of the war. Thus, historians consider the practice, although \"not technically illegal\" (since the gifts were granted by Hitler himself), \"smacking of corruption\" and \"having an aura of deliberate corruption from above.\"\nFrom 1933 to the end of the Second World War, high-ranking officers of the Armed Forces of Nazi Germany accepted vast bribes in the form of cash, estates, and tax exemptions in exchange for their loyalty to Nazism. Before any officer began to receive money, they met with Hans Lammers (chief of Nazi Germany's Chancellery), who informed them that future payments would depend on how much loyalty they were willing to show Hitler. They were advised that what he gave with one hand could just as easily be taken away with the other. The illicit nature of the payments was emphasised by Hans Lammers's warning to them not to speak about the payments to anyone and to keep as few written records as possible.","ref_answer":"No|Yes","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Bribery of senior Wehrmacht officers","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Bribery_of_senior_Wehrmacht_officers"}
{"question_ID":178,"question":"Did Brinsley use to be a pit village?","context1":"Brinsley used to be a major farming village. The only remainder of this heritage are the headstocks. They are not only of significance for the area but are also the only headstocks left of this kind.","context2":"Brinsley used to be a major farming village. The only remainder of this heritage are the headstocks. They are not only of significance for the area but are also the only headstocks left of this kind.","answer1":"No","answer2":"Yes","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"Brinsley used to be a major farming village. The only remainder of this heritage are the headstocks. They are not only of significance for the area but are also the only headstocks left of this kind.","ref_answer":"No|Yes","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Brinsley","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Brinsley"}
{"question_ID":179,"question":"Did Brinsley use to be a farming village or a pit village?","context1":"Brinsley used to be a major farming village. The only remainder of this heritage are the headstocks. They are not only of significance for the area but are also the only headstocks left of this kind.","context2":"Brinsley used to be a major farming village. The only remainder of this heritage are the headstocks. They are not only of significance for the area but are also the only headstocks left of this kind.","answer1":"farming village","answer2":"pit village","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"Brinsley used to be a major farming village. The only remainder of this heritage are the headstocks. They are not only of significance for the area but are also the only headstocks left of this kind.","ref_answer":"farming village|pit village","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Brinsley","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Brinsley"}
{"question_ID":177,"question":"Did Brinsley use to be a farming village?","context1":"Brinsley used to be a major farming village. The only remainder of this heritage are the headstocks. They are not only of significance for the area but are also the only headstocks left of this kind.","context2":"Brinsley used to be a major farming village. The only remainder of this heritage are the headstocks. They are not only of significance for the area but are also the only headstocks left of this kind.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"Brinsley used to be a major farming village. The only remainder of this heritage are the headstocks. They are not only of significance for the area but are also the only headstocks left of this kind.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Brinsley","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Brinsley"}
{"question_ID":181,"question":"Did five East Midlands British Rail Class 153 railcars have their leases terminated by July 2020?","context1":"At one point in April 2020, only three East Midlands British Rail Class 153 railcars were in service, following the implementation of an emergency timetable due to the COVID-19 pandemic, with all others being stored out of use as surplus to requirement. Two more returned to services by July 2020, while five others (153302, 153318, 153368, 153372, 153374, and 153382) had their leases terminated.","context2":"At one point in April 2020, only three East Midlands British Rail Class 153 railcars were in service, following the implementation of an emergency timetable due to the COVID-19 pandemic, with all others being stored out of use as surplus to requirement. Two more returned to services by July 2020, while five others (153302, 153318, 153368, 153372, 153374, and 153382) had their leases terminated.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"At one point in April 2020, only three East Midlands British Rail Class 153 railcars were in service, following the implementation of an emergency timetable due to the COVID-19 pandemic, with all others being stored out of use as surplus to requirement. Two more returned to services by July 2020, while five others (153302, 153318, 153368, 153372, 153374, and 153382) had their leases terminated.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"British Rail Class 153","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/British_Rail_Class_153"}
{"question_ID":182,"question":"Did six East Midlands British Rail Class 153 railcars have their leases terminated by July 2020?","context1":"At one point in April 2020, only three East Midlands British Rail Class 153 railcars were in service, following the implementation of an emergency timetable due to the COVID-19 pandemic, with all others being stored out of use as surplus to requirement. Two more returned to services by July 2020, while five others (153302, 153318, 153368, 153372, 153374, and 153382) had their leases terminated.","context2":"At one point in April 2020, only three East Midlands British Rail Class 153 railcars were in service, following the implementation of an emergency timetable due to the COVID-19 pandemic, with all others being stored out of use as surplus to requirement. Two more returned to services by July 2020, while five others (153302, 153318, 153368, 153372, 153374, and 153382) had their leases terminated.","answer1":"No","answer2":"Yes","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"At one point in April 2020, only three East Midlands British Rail Class 153 railcars were in service, following the implementation of an emergency timetable due to the COVID-19 pandemic, with all others being stored out of use as surplus to requirement. Two more returned to services by July 2020, while five others (153302, 153318, 153368, 153372, 153374, and 153382) had their leases terminated.","ref_answer":"No|Yes","WikipediaArticleTitle":"British Rail Class 153","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/British_Rail_Class_153"}
{"question_ID":180,"question":"How many East Midlands British Rail Class 153 railcars had their leases terminated by July 2020?","context1":"At one point in April 2020, only three East Midlands British Rail Class 153 railcars were in service, following the implementation of an emergency timetable due to the COVID-19 pandemic, with all others being stored out of use as surplus to requirement. Two more returned to services by July 2020, while five others (153302, 153318, 153368, 153372, 153374, and 153382) had their leases terminated.","context2":"At one point in April 2020, only three East Midlands British Rail Class 153 railcars were in service, following the implementation of an emergency timetable due to the COVID-19 pandemic, with all others being stored out of use as surplus to requirement. Two more returned to services by July 2020, while five others (153302, 153318, 153368, 153372, 153374, and 153382) had their leases terminated.","answer1":"5","answer2":"6","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"At one point in April 2020, only three East Midlands British Rail Class 153 railcars were in service, following the implementation of an emergency timetable due to the COVID-19 pandemic, with all others being stored out of use as surplus to requirement. Two more returned to services by July 2020, while five others (153302, 153318, 153368, 153372, 153374, and 153382) had their leases terminated.","ref_answer":"5|6","WikipediaArticleTitle":"British Rail Class 153","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/British_Rail_Class_153"}
{"question_ID":184,"question":"Did Ger Browne play for Cashel King Cormacs club?","context1":"Ger Browne (born 10 May 1998) is an Irish hurler who played for Tipperary Senior Hurling Championship with Cashel King Cormacs and at inter-county level with the Tipperary senior hurling team. ","context2":"Ger Browne joined the Knockavilla\u2013Donaskeigh Kickhams club at a young age and played in all grades at juvenile and underage levels before eventually joining the club's top adult team.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Ger Browne (born 10 May 1998) is an Irish hurler who played for Tipperary Senior Hurling Championship with Cashel King Cormacs and at inter-county level with the Tipperary senior hurling team. \nGer Browne joined the Knockavilla\u2013Donaskeigh Kickhams club at a young age and played in all grades at juvenile and underage levels before eventually joining the club's top adult team.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Ger Browne","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Ger_Browne"}
{"question_ID":185,"question":"Did Ger Browne play for Knockavilla\u2013Donaskeigh Kickhams club?","context1":"Ger Browne (born 10 May 1998) is an Irish hurler who played for Tipperary Senior Hurling Championship with Cashel King Cormacs and at inter-county level with the Tipperary senior hurling team. ","context2":"Ger Browne joined the Knockavilla\u2013Donaskeigh Kickhams club at a young age and played in all grades at juvenile and underage levels before eventually joining the club's top adult team.","answer1":"No","answer2":"Yes","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Ger Browne (born 10 May 1998) is an Irish hurler who played for Tipperary Senior Hurling Championship with Cashel King Cormacs and at inter-county level with the Tipperary senior hurling team. \nGer Browne joined the Knockavilla\u2013Donaskeigh Kickhams club at a young age and played in all grades at juvenile and underage levels before eventually joining the club's top adult team.","ref_answer":"No|Yes","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Ger Browne","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Ger_Browne"}
{"question_ID":183,"question":"What club did Ger Browne play for: Cashel King Cormacs club or Knockavilla\u2013Donaskeigh Kickhams club?","context1":"Ger Browne (born 10 May 1998) is an Irish hurler who played for Tipperary Senior Hurling Championship with Cashel King Cormacs and at inter-county level with the Tipperary senior hurling team. ","context2":"Ger Browne joined the Knockavilla\u2013Donaskeigh Kickhams club at a young age and played in all grades at juvenile and underage levels before eventually joining the club's top adult team.","answer1":"Cashel King Cormacs club","answer2":"Knockavilla\u2013Donaskeigh Kickhams club","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Ger Browne (born 10 May 1998) is an Irish hurler who played for Tipperary Senior Hurling Championship with Cashel King Cormacs and at inter-county level with the Tipperary senior hurling team. \nGer Browne joined the Knockavilla\u2013Donaskeigh Kickhams club at a young age and played in all grades at juvenile and underage levels before eventually joining the club's top adult team.","ref_answer":"Cashel King Cormacs club|Knockavilla\u2013Donaskeigh Kickhams club","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Ger Browne","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Ger_Browne"}
{"question_ID":186,"question":"How many Blackburn Blackburn aircraft were built?","context1":"Number of Blackburn Blackburn aircraft built: 44","context2":"Blackburn Prototype: three built; Blackburn I Production version with a 449 hp (335 kW) Napier Lion IIB engines: 33 built; Blackburn II Improved production version with a 464 hp (346 kW) Napier Lion V, and increased gap between wings: 29 built.","answer1":"44","answer2":"65 (62 excluding prototypes)","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Number of Blackburn Blackburn aircraft built: 44\nBlackburn Prototype: three built; Blackburn I Production version with a 449 hp (335 kW) Napier Lion IIB engines: 33 built; Blackburn II Improved production version with a 464 hp (346 kW) Napier Lion V, and increased gap between wings: 29 built.","ref_answer":"44|65 (62 excluding prototypes)","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Blackburn Blackburn","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Blackburn_Blackburn"}
{"question_ID":188,"question":"Who was the last person jailed for blasphemy in the United States?","context1":"The last person to be jailed in the United States for blasphemy was Abner Kneeland in 1838","context2":"The last known U.S. conviction for blasphemy was of atheist activist Charles Lee Smith. In 1928, he rented a storefront in Little Rock, Arkansas, and gave out free atheist literature there. The sign in the window read: \"Evolution Is True. The Bible's a Lie. God's a Ghost.\" For this he was charged with violating the city ordinance against blasphemy. Because he was an atheist and therefore could not swear the court's religious oath to tell the truth, he was not permitted to testify in his own defense. The judge then dismissed the original charge, replacing it with one of distributing obscene, slanderous, or scurrilous literature. Smith was convicted, fined $25, and served most of a twenty-six-day jail sentence.","answer1":"Abner Kneeland","answer2":"Charles Lee Smith","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"The last person to be jailed in the United States for blasphemy was Abner Kneeland in 1838\nThe last known U.S. conviction for blasphemy was of atheist activist Charles Lee Smith. In 1928, he rented a storefront in Little Rock, Arkansas, and gave out free atheist literature there. The sign in the window read: \"Evolution Is True. The Bible's a Lie. God's a Ghost.\" For this he was charged with violating the city ordinance against blasphemy. Because he was an atheist and therefore could not swear the court's religious oath to tell the truth, he was not permitted to testify in his own defense. The judge then dismissed the original charge, replacing it with one of distributing obscene, slanderous, or scurrilous literature. Smith was convicted, fined $25, and served most of a twenty-six-day jail sentence.","ref_answer":"Abner Kneeland|Charles Lee Smith","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Blasphemy law in the United States","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Blasphemy_law_in_the_United_States"}
{"question_ID":189,"question":"Who was the last person jailed for blasphemy in the United States and in what year?","context1":"The last person to be jailed in the United States for blasphemy was Abner Kneeland in 1838","context2":"The last known U.S. conviction for blasphemy was of atheist activist Charles Lee Smith. In 1928, he rented a storefront in Little Rock, Arkansas, and gave out free atheist literature there. The sign in the window read: \"Evolution Is True. The Bible's a Lie. God's a Ghost.\" For this he was charged with violating the city ordinance against blasphemy. Because he was an atheist and therefore could not swear the court's religious oath to tell the truth, he was not permitted to testify in his own defense. The judge then dismissed the original charge, replacing it with one of distributing obscene, slanderous, or scurrilous literature. Smith was convicted, fined $25, and served most of a twenty-six-day jail sentence.","answer1":"Abner Kneeland in 1838","answer2":"Charles Lee Smith in 1928","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"The last person to be jailed in the United States for blasphemy was Abner Kneeland in 1838\nThe last known U.S. conviction for blasphemy was of atheist activist Charles Lee Smith. In 1928, he rented a storefront in Little Rock, Arkansas, and gave out free atheist literature there. The sign in the window read: \"Evolution Is True. The Bible's a Lie. God's a Ghost.\" For this he was charged with violating the city ordinance against blasphemy. Because he was an atheist and therefore could not swear the court's religious oath to tell the truth, he was not permitted to testify in his own defense. The judge then dismissed the original charge, replacing it with one of distributing obscene, slanderous, or scurrilous literature. Smith was convicted, fined $25, and served most of a twenty-six-day jail sentence.","ref_answer":"Abner Kneeland in 1838|Charles Lee Smith in 1928","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Blasphemy law in the United States","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Blasphemy_law_in_the_United_States"}
{"question_ID":187,"question":"In what year was the last person jailed for blasphemy in the United States?","context1":"The last person to be jailed in the United States for blasphemy was Abner Kneeland in 1838","context2":"The last known U.S. conviction for blasphemy was of atheist activist Charles Lee Smith. In 1928, he rented a storefront in Little Rock, Arkansas, and gave out free atheist literature there. The sign in the window read: \"Evolution Is True. The Bible's a Lie. God's a Ghost.\" For this he was charged with violating the city ordinance against blasphemy. Because he was an atheist and therefore could not swear the court's religious oath to tell the truth, he was not permitted to testify in his own defense. The judge then dismissed the original charge, replacing it with one of distributing obscene, slanderous, or scurrilous literature. Smith was convicted, fined $25, and served most of a twenty-six-day jail sentence.","answer1":"1838","answer2":"1928","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"The last person to be jailed in the United States for blasphemy was Abner Kneeland in 1838\nThe last known U.S. conviction for blasphemy was of atheist activist Charles Lee Smith. In 1928, he rented a storefront in Little Rock, Arkansas, and gave out free atheist literature there. The sign in the window read: \"Evolution Is True. The Bible's a Lie. God's a Ghost.\" For this he was charged with violating the city ordinance against blasphemy. Because he was an atheist and therefore could not swear the court's religious oath to tell the truth, he was not permitted to testify in his own defense. The judge then dismissed the original charge, replacing it with one of distributing obscene, slanderous, or scurrilous literature. Smith was convicted, fined $25, and served most of a twenty-six-day jail sentence.","ref_answer":"1838|1928","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Blasphemy law in the United States","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Blasphemy_law_in_the_United_States"}
{"question_ID":191,"question":"Has the Hemoglobin-Based Oxygen Carrier, Polyheme been banned? ","context1":"Other methods of bleeding control in surgery include the use of blood substitutes, which at present do not carry oxygen but expand the volume of the blood to prevent shock. Blood substitutes which do carry oxygen, such as PolyHeme, are also under development.","context2":"Hemoglobin-Based Oxygen Carriers such as Polyheme and Hemepure have been discontinued due to severe adverse reactions including death.","answer1":"No","answer2":"Yes","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Other methods of bleeding control in surgery include the use of blood substitutes, which at present do not carry oxygen but expand the volume of the blood to prevent shock. Blood substitutes which do carry oxygen, such as PolyHeme, are also under development.\nHemoglobin-Based Oxygen Carriers such as Polyheme and Hemepure have been discontinued due to severe adverse reactions including death.","ref_answer":"No|Yes","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Bloodless surgery","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Bloodless_surgery"}
{"question_ID":190,"question":"What is the current status of the Hemoglobin-Based Oxygen Carrier, Polyheme? ","context1":"Other methods of bleeding control in surgery include the use of blood substitutes, which at present do not carry oxygen but expand the volume of the blood to prevent shock. Blood substitutes which do carry oxygen, such as PolyHeme, are also under development.","context2":"Hemoglobin-Based Oxygen Carriers such as Polyheme and Hemepure have been discontinued due to severe adverse reactions including death.","answer1":"Under development","answer2":"Banned","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Other methods of bleeding control in surgery include the use of blood substitutes, which at present do not carry oxygen but expand the volume of the blood to prevent shock. Blood substitutes which do carry oxygen, such as PolyHeme, are also under development.\nHemoglobin-Based Oxygen Carriers such as Polyheme and Hemepure have been discontinued due to severe adverse reactions including death.","ref_answer":"Under development|Banned","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Bloodless surgery","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Bloodless_surgery"}
{"question_ID":193,"question":"Is Bombus Polaris exclusively an alpine species?","context1":"Bombus polaris is part of the subgenus Alpinobombus along with Bombus alpinus, Bombus balteatus, Bombus hyperboreus, and Bombus neoboreus. Alpinobombus bees occur in arctic and high alpine regions.","context2":"Bombus polaris is an alpine species. They exclusively live at the summits of mountains.","answer1":"No","answer2":"Yes","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Bombus polaris is part of the subgenus Alpinobombus along with Bombus alpinus, Bombus balteatus, Bombus hyperboreus, and Bombus neoboreus. Alpinobombus bees occur in arctic and high alpine regions.\nBombus polaris is an alpine species. They exclusively live at the summits of mountains.","ref_answer":"No|Yes","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Bombus polaris","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Bombus_polaris"}
{"question_ID":192,"question":"Does Bombus Polaris live exclusively on mountain summits?","context1":"Bombus polaris is part of the subgenus Alpinobombus along with Bombus alpinus, Bombus balteatus, Bombus hyperboreus, and Bombus neoboreus. Alpinobombus bees occur in arctic and high alpine regions.","context2":"Bombus polaris is an alpine species. They exclusively live at the summits of mountains.","answer1":"No","answer2":"Yes","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Bombus polaris is part of the subgenus Alpinobombus along with Bombus alpinus, Bombus balteatus, Bombus hyperboreus, and Bombus neoboreus. Alpinobombus bees occur in arctic and high alpine regions.\nBombus polaris is an alpine species. They exclusively live at the summits of mountains.","ref_answer":"No|Yes","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Bombus polaris","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Bombus_polaris"}
{"question_ID":195,"question":"Does the B\u014ds\u014dzoku have a significant percentage (<15%) of members over the age of 20?","context1":"In general, the Japanese government sees b\u014ds\u014dzoku as highly organized groups, affiliated under several national federations. They are known to be surprisingly well organized, despite generally only having a handful of members above the age of twenty.","context2":" It is estimated that around 25% of b\u014ds\u014dzoku are above the age of twenty.","answer1":"No","answer2":"Yes","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"In general, the Japanese government sees b\u014ds\u014dzoku as highly organized groups, affiliated under several national federations. They are known to be surprisingly well organized, despite generally only having a handful of members above the age of twenty.\n It is estimated that around 25% of b\u014ds\u014dzoku are above the age of twenty.","ref_answer":"No|Yes","WikipediaArticleTitle":"B\u014ds\u014dzoku","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/B\u014ds\u014dzoku"}
{"question_ID":194,"question":"Roughly how many members above the age of 20 do the B\u014ds\u014dzoku have?","context1":"In general, the Japanese government sees b\u014ds\u014dzoku as highly organized groups, affiliated under several national federations. They are known to be surprisingly well organized, despite generally only having a handful of members above the age of twenty.","context2":" It is estimated that around 25% of b\u014ds\u014dzoku are above the age of twenty.","answer1":"a handful","answer2":"25%","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"In general, the Japanese government sees b\u014ds\u014dzoku as highly organized groups, affiliated under several national federations. They are known to be surprisingly well organized, despite generally only having a handful of members above the age of twenty.\n It is estimated that around 25% of b\u014ds\u014dzoku are above the age of twenty.","ref_answer":"a handful|25%","WikipediaArticleTitle":"B\u014ds\u014dzoku","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/B\u014ds\u014dzoku"}
{"question_ID":197,"question":"Do Jamshedpur FC play their home games in JRD Tata Sports Complex Stadium?","context1":"Jamshedpur FC play their home games at JRD Tata Sports Complex Stadium.","context2":"Jamshedpur FC play their home games at Birsa Munda Football Stadium.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Jamshedpur FC play their home games at JRD Tata Sports Complex Stadium.\nJamshedpur FC play their home games at Birsa Munda Football Stadium.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"List of association football stadiums by country","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/List_of_association_football_stadiums_by_country"}
{"question_ID":198,"question":"Do Jamshedpur FC play their home games in Birsa Munda Football Stadium?","context1":"Jamshedpur FC play their home games at JRD Tata Sports Complex Stadium.","context2":"Jamshedpur FC play their home games at Birsa Munda Football Stadium.","answer1":"No","answer2":"Yes","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Jamshedpur FC play their home games at JRD Tata Sports Complex Stadium.\nJamshedpur FC play their home games at Birsa Munda Football Stadium.","ref_answer":"No|Yes","WikipediaArticleTitle":"List of association football stadiums by country","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/List_of_association_football_stadiums_by_country"}
{"question_ID":196,"question":"In which stadium do Jamshedpur FC play their home games?","context1":"Jamshedpur FC play their home games at JRD Tata Sports Complex Stadium.","context2":"Jamshedpur FC play their home games at Birsa Munda Football Stadium.","answer1":"JRD Tata Sports Complex Stadium","answer2":"Birsa Munda Football Stadium","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Jamshedpur FC play their home games at JRD Tata Sports Complex Stadium.\nJamshedpur FC play their home games at Birsa Munda Football Stadium.","ref_answer":"JRD Tata Sports Complex Stadium|Birsa Munda Football Stadium","WikipediaArticleTitle":"List of association football stadiums by country","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/List_of_association_football_stadiums_by_country"}
{"question_ID":200,"question":"Was A Life on Film (book about Mary Astor's career) published in 1971?","context1":" In 1971, a second book was published, A Life on Film, where Mary Astor discussed her career.","context2":"A Life on Film was published in 1967.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":" In 1971, a second book was published, A Life on Film, where Mary Astor discussed her career.\nA Life on Film was published in 1967.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Mary Astor","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Mary_Astor"}
{"question_ID":201,"question":"Was A Life on Film (book about Mary Astor's career) published in 1967?","context1":" In 1971, a second book was published, A Life on Film, where Mary Astor discussed her career.","context2":"A Life on Film was published in 1967.","answer1":"No","answer2":"Yes","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":" In 1971, a second book was published, A Life on Film, where Mary Astor discussed her career.\nA Life on Film was published in 1967.","ref_answer":"No|Yes","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Mary Astor","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Mary_Astor"}
{"question_ID":199,"question":"When was A Life on Film (book about Mary Astor's career) published?","context1":" In 1971, a second book was published, A Life on Film, where Mary Astor discussed her career.","context2":"A Life on Film was published in 1967.","answer1":"1971","answer2":"1967","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":" In 1971, a second book was published, A Life on Film, where Mary Astor discussed her career.\nA Life on Film was published in 1967.","ref_answer":"1971|1967","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Mary Astor","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Mary_Astor"}
{"question_ID":203,"question":"How many shillings was the ringleader of a violent protest against football games prosecution in 1659-1660 fined?","context1":"A prosecution of football games between 1659-1660 triggered a violent protest and resulted in over 100 armed men breaking into the Mayor's house; the ringleader was later fined 10 pounds or 400 shillings, a very large sum of money at the time.","context2":"A prosecution of football games between 1659-1660 triggered a violent protest and resulted in over 100 armed men breaking into the Mayor's house; the ringleader was later fined 10 pounds or 400 shillings, a very large sum of money at the time.","answer1":"200 shillings","answer2":"400 shillings","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"A prosecution of football games between 1659-1660 triggered a violent protest and resulted in over 100 armed men breaking into the Mayor's house; the ringleader was later fined 10 pounds or 400 shillings, a very large sum of money at the time.","ref_answer":"200 shillings|400 shillings","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Attempts to ban football games","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Attempts_to_ban_football_games"}
{"question_ID":204,"question":"Was the ringleader of a violent protest against football games prosecution in 1659-1660 fined 10 pounds?","context1":"A prosecution of football games between 1659-1660 triggered a violent protest and resulted in over 100 armed men breaking into the Mayor's house; the ringleader was later fined 10 pounds or 400 shillings, a very large sum of money at the time.","context2":"A prosecution of football games between 1659-1660 triggered a violent protest and resulted in over 100 armed men breaking into the Mayor's house; the ringleader was later fined 10 pounds or 400 shillings, a very large sum of money at the time.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"A prosecution of football games between 1659-1660 triggered a violent protest and resulted in over 100 armed men breaking into the Mayor's house; the ringleader was later fined 10 pounds or 400 shillings, a very large sum of money at the time.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Attempts to ban football games","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Attempts_to_ban_football_games"}
{"question_ID":205,"question":"Was the ringleader of a violent protest against football games prosecution in 1659-1660 fined 400 shillings?","context1":"A prosecution of football games between 1659-1660 triggered a violent protest and resulted in over 100 armed men breaking into the Mayor's house; the ringleader was later fined 10 pounds or 400 shillings, a very large sum of money at the time.","context2":"A prosecution of football games between 1659-1660 triggered a violent protest and resulted in over 100 armed men breaking into the Mayor's house; the ringleader was later fined 10 pounds or 400 shillings, a very large sum of money at the time.","answer1":"No","answer2":"Yes","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"A prosecution of football games between 1659-1660 triggered a violent protest and resulted in over 100 armed men breaking into the Mayor's house; the ringleader was later fined 10 pounds or 400 shillings, a very large sum of money at the time.","ref_answer":"No|Yes","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Attempts to ban football games","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Attempts_to_ban_football_games"}
{"question_ID":202,"question":"How many pounds was the ringleader of a violent protest against football games prosecution in 1659-1660 fined?","context1":"A prosecution of football games between 1659-1660 triggered a violent protest and resulted in over 100 armed men breaking into the Mayor's house; the ringleader was later fined 10 pounds or 400 shillings, a very large sum of money at the time.","context2":"A prosecution of football games between 1659-1660 triggered a violent protest and resulted in over 100 armed men breaking into the Mayor's house; the ringleader was later fined 10 pounds or 400 shillings, a very large sum of money at the time.","answer1":"10 pounds","answer2":"20 pounds","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"A prosecution of football games between 1659-1660 triggered a violent protest and resulted in over 100 armed men breaking into the Mayor's house; the ringleader was later fined 10 pounds or 400 shillings, a very large sum of money at the time.","ref_answer":"10 pounds|20 pounds","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Attempts to ban football games","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Attempts_to_ban_football_games"}
{"question_ID":207,"question":"Is the color of the flowers of ayapana triplinervis pale pink?","context1":"The flowers of ayapana triplinervis are pale pink and the thin, hairless stem is reddish in color.","context2":"The flowers of ayapana triplinervis are slaty blue.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"The flowers of ayapana triplinervis are pale pink and the thin, hairless stem is reddish in color.\nThe flowers of ayapana triplinervis are slaty blue.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Ayapana triplinervis","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Ayapana_triplinervis"}
{"question_ID":208,"question":"Is the color of the flowers of ayapana triplinervis slaty blue?","context1":"The flowers of ayapana triplinervis are pale pink and the thin, hairless stem is reddish in color.","context2":"The flowers of ayapana triplinervis are slaty blue.","answer1":"No","answer2":"Yes","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"The flowers of ayapana triplinervis are pale pink and the thin, hairless stem is reddish in color.\nThe flowers of ayapana triplinervis are slaty blue.","ref_answer":"No|Yes","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Ayapana triplinervis","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Ayapana_triplinervis"}
{"question_ID":206,"question":"What is the color of the flowers of ayapana triplinervis?","context1":"The flowers of ayapana triplinervis are pale pink and the thin, hairless stem is reddish in color.","context2":"The flowers of ayapana triplinervis are slaty blue.","answer1":"pale pink","answer2":"slaty blue","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"The flowers of ayapana triplinervis are pale pink and the thin, hairless stem is reddish in color.\nThe flowers of ayapana triplinervis are slaty blue.","ref_answer":"pale pink|slaty blue","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Ayapana triplinervis","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Ayapana_triplinervis"}
{"question_ID":210,"question":"Can the Aztec mastiff bat be found in Nicaragua, Guatemala, or southern Venezuela?","context1":"Aztec mastiff bat is found from Jalisco and Cozumel Island in southern Mexico to Nicaragua and has been reported from Guatemala but not from El Salvador or Honduras. It has also been reported from southern Venezuela. It is endemic to Mexico.","context2":"Aztec mastiff bat is found from Jalisco and Cozumel Island in southern Mexico to Nicaragua and has been reported from Guatemala but not from El Salvador or Honduras. It has also been reported from southern Venezuela. It is endemic to Mexico.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"Aztec mastiff bat is found from Jalisco and Cozumel Island in southern Mexico to Nicaragua and has been reported from Guatemala but not from El Salvador or Honduras. It has also been reported from southern Venezuela. It is endemic to Mexico.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Aztec mastiff bat","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Aztec_mastiff_bat"}
{"question_ID":211,"question":"Can the Aztec mastiff bat be found in Nicaragua?","context1":"Aztec mastiff bat is found from Jalisco and Cozumel Island in southern Mexico to Nicaragua and has been reported from Guatemala but not from El Salvador or Honduras. It has also been reported from southern Venezuela. It is endemic to Mexico.","context2":"Aztec mastiff bat is found from Jalisco and Cozumel Island in southern Mexico to Nicaragua and has been reported from Guatemala but not from El Salvador or Honduras. It has also been reported from southern Venezuela. It is endemic to Mexico.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"Aztec mastiff bat is found from Jalisco and Cozumel Island in southern Mexico to Nicaragua and has been reported from Guatemala but not from El Salvador or Honduras. It has also been reported from southern Venezuela. It is endemic to Mexico.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Aztec mastiff bat","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Aztec_mastiff_bat"}
{"question_ID":212,"question":"Can the Aztec mastiff bat be found Guatemala?","context1":"Aztec mastiff bat is found from Jalisco and Cozumel Island in southern Mexico to Nicaragua and has been reported from Guatemala but not from El Salvador or Honduras. It has also been reported from southern Venezuela. It is endemic to Mexico.","context2":"Aztec mastiff bat is found from Jalisco and Cozumel Island in southern Mexico to Nicaragua and has been reported from Guatemala but not from El Salvador or Honduras. It has also been reported from southern Venezuela. It is endemic to Mexico.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"Aztec mastiff bat is found from Jalisco and Cozumel Island in southern Mexico to Nicaragua and has been reported from Guatemala but not from El Salvador or Honduras. It has also been reported from southern Venezuela. It is endemic to Mexico.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Aztec mastiff bat","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Aztec_mastiff_bat"}
{"question_ID":213,"question":"Can the Aztec mastiff bat be found in southern Venezuela?","context1":"Aztec mastiff bat is found from Jalisco and Cozumel Island in southern Mexico to Nicaragua and has been reported from Guatemala but not from El Salvador or Honduras. It has also been reported from southern Venezuela. It is endemic to Mexico.","context2":"Aztec mastiff bat is found from Jalisco and Cozumel Island in southern Mexico to Nicaragua and has been reported from Guatemala but not from El Salvador or Honduras. It has also been reported from southern Venezuela. It is endemic to Mexico.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"Aztec mastiff bat is found from Jalisco and Cozumel Island in southern Mexico to Nicaragua and has been reported from Guatemala but not from El Salvador or Honduras. It has also been reported from southern Venezuela. It is endemic to Mexico.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Aztec mastiff bat","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Aztec_mastiff_bat"}
{"question_ID":214,"question":"Can the Aztec mastiff bat be found in Nicaragua or Guatemala?","context1":"Aztec mastiff bat is found from Jalisco and Cozumel Island in southern Mexico to Nicaragua and has been reported from Guatemala but not from El Salvador or Honduras. It has also been reported from southern Venezuela. It is endemic to Mexico.","context2":"Aztec mastiff bat is found from Jalisco and Cozumel Island in southern Mexico to Nicaragua and has been reported from Guatemala but not from El Salvador or Honduras. It has also been reported from southern Venezuela. It is endemic to Mexico.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"Aztec mastiff bat is found from Jalisco and Cozumel Island in southern Mexico to Nicaragua and has been reported from Guatemala but not from El Salvador or Honduras. It has also been reported from southern Venezuela. It is endemic to Mexico.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Aztec mastiff bat","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Aztec_mastiff_bat"}
{"question_ID":215,"question":"Can the Aztec mastiff bat be found in Nicaragua or southern Venezuela?","context1":"Aztec mastiff bat is found from Jalisco and Cozumel Island in southern Mexico to Nicaragua and has been reported from Guatemala but not from El Salvador or Honduras. It has also been reported from southern Venezuela. It is endemic to Mexico.","context2":"Aztec mastiff bat is found from Jalisco and Cozumel Island in southern Mexico to Nicaragua and has been reported from Guatemala but not from El Salvador or Honduras. It has also been reported from southern Venezuela. It is endemic to Mexico.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"Aztec mastiff bat is found from Jalisco and Cozumel Island in southern Mexico to Nicaragua and has been reported from Guatemala but not from El Salvador or Honduras. It has also been reported from southern Venezuela. It is endemic to Mexico.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Aztec mastiff bat","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Aztec_mastiff_bat"}
{"question_ID":216,"question":"Can the Aztec mastiff bat be found in Guatemala or southern Venezuela?","context1":"Aztec mastiff bat is found from Jalisco and Cozumel Island in southern Mexico to Nicaragua and has been reported from Guatemala but not from El Salvador or Honduras. It has also been reported from southern Venezuela. It is endemic to Mexico.","context2":"Aztec mastiff bat is found from Jalisco and Cozumel Island in southern Mexico to Nicaragua and has been reported from Guatemala but not from El Salvador or Honduras. It has also been reported from southern Venezuela. It is endemic to Mexico.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"Aztec mastiff bat is found from Jalisco and Cozumel Island in southern Mexico to Nicaragua and has been reported from Guatemala but not from El Salvador or Honduras. It has also been reported from southern Venezuela. It is endemic to Mexico.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Aztec mastiff bat","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Aztec_mastiff_bat"}
{"question_ID":209,"question":"Is the Aztec mastiff bat only found in Mexico?","context1":"Aztec mastiff bat is found from Jalisco and Cozumel Island in southern Mexico to Nicaragua and has been reported from Guatemala but not from El Salvador or Honduras. It has also been reported from southern Venezuela. It is endemic to Mexico.","context2":"Aztec mastiff bat is found from Jalisco and Cozumel Island in southern Mexico to Nicaragua and has been reported from Guatemala but not from El Salvador or Honduras. It has also been reported from southern Venezuela. It is endemic to Mexico.","answer1":"No","answer2":"Yes","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"Aztec mastiff bat is found from Jalisco and Cozumel Island in southern Mexico to Nicaragua and has been reported from Guatemala but not from El Salvador or Honduras. It has also been reported from southern Venezuela. It is endemic to Mexico.","ref_answer":"No|Yes","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Aztec mastiff bat","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Aztec_mastiff_bat"}
{"question_ID":218,"question":"Is the word Elemi of Greek origin?","context1":"The word Elemi, like the older term animi, appears to have been derived from enhaemon (\u1f14\u03bd\u03b1\u03b9\u03bc\u03bf\u03bd): the name of a styptic medicine said by Pliny to contain tears exuded by the olive tree of Arabia.","context2":"The name Elemi is derived from an Arabic phrase meaning 'above and below', an abbreviation of 'As above, so below' and this tells us something about its action on the emotional and spiritual planes.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"The word Elemi, like the older term animi, appears to have been derived from enhaemon (\u1f14\u03bd\u03b1\u03b9\u03bc\u03bf\u03bd): the name of a styptic medicine said by Pliny to contain tears exuded by the olive tree of Arabia.\nThe name Elemi is derived from an Arabic phrase meaning 'above and below', an abbreviation of 'As above, so below' and this tells us something about its action on the emotional and spiritual planes.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Canarium luzonicum","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Canarium_luzonicum"}
{"question_ID":219,"question":"Is the word Elemi of Arabic origin?","context1":"The word Elemi, like the older term animi, appears to have been derived from enhaemon (\u1f14\u03bd\u03b1\u03b9\u03bc\u03bf\u03bd): the name of a styptic medicine said by Pliny to contain tears exuded by the olive tree of Arabia.","context2":"The name Elemi is derived from an Arabic phrase meaning 'above and below', an abbreviation of 'As above, so below' and this tells us something about its action on the emotional and spiritual planes.","answer1":"No","answer2":"Yes","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"The word Elemi, like the older term animi, appears to have been derived from enhaemon (\u1f14\u03bd\u03b1\u03b9\u03bc\u03bf\u03bd): the name of a styptic medicine said by Pliny to contain tears exuded by the olive tree of Arabia.\nThe name Elemi is derived from an Arabic phrase meaning 'above and below', an abbreviation of 'As above, so below' and this tells us something about its action on the emotional and spiritual planes.","ref_answer":"No|Yes","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Canarium luzonicum","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Canarium_luzonicum"}
{"question_ID":220,"question":"Of what linguistic origin is the word Elemi?","context1":"The word Elemi, like the older term animi, appears to have been derived from enhaemon (\u1f14\u03bd\u03b1\u03b9\u03bc\u03bf\u03bd): the name of a styptic medicine said by Pliny to contain tears exuded by the olive tree of Arabia.","context2":"The name Elemi is derived from an Arabic phrase meaning 'above and below', an abbreviation of 'As above, so below' and this tells us something about its action on the emotional and spiritual planes.","answer1":"Greek","answer2":"Arabic","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"The word Elemi, like the older term animi, appears to have been derived from enhaemon (\u1f14\u03bd\u03b1\u03b9\u03bc\u03bf\u03bd): the name of a styptic medicine said by Pliny to contain tears exuded by the olive tree of Arabia.\nThe name Elemi is derived from an Arabic phrase meaning 'above and below', an abbreviation of 'As above, so below' and this tells us something about its action on the emotional and spiritual planes.","ref_answer":"Greek|Arabic","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Canarium luzonicum","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Canarium_luzonicum"}
{"question_ID":217,"question":"What is the etymology of the word Elemi?","context1":"The word Elemi, like the older term animi, appears to have been derived from enhaemon (\u1f14\u03bd\u03b1\u03b9\u03bc\u03bf\u03bd): the name of a styptic medicine said by Pliny to contain tears exuded by the olive tree of Arabia.","context2":"The name Elemi is derived from an Arabic phrase meaning 'above and below', an abbreviation of 'As above, so below' and this tells us something about its action on the emotional and spiritual planes.","answer1":"It is derived from enhaemon (\u1f14\u03bd\u03b1\u03b9\u03bc\u03bf\u03bd)","answer2":" It is derived from an Arabic phrase meaning 'above and below'","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"The word Elemi, like the older term animi, appears to have been derived from enhaemon (\u1f14\u03bd\u03b1\u03b9\u03bc\u03bf\u03bd): the name of a styptic medicine said by Pliny to contain tears exuded by the olive tree of Arabia.\nThe name Elemi is derived from an Arabic phrase meaning 'above and below', an abbreviation of 'As above, so below' and this tells us something about its action on the emotional and spiritual planes.","ref_answer":"It is derived from enhaemon (\u1f14\u03bd\u03b1\u03b9\u03bc\u03bf\u03bd)| It is derived from an Arabic phrase meaning 'above and below'","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Canarium luzonicum","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Canarium_luzonicum"}
{"question_ID":222,"question":"Was the site of the Carandiru massacre an actual penitentiary?","context1":"The Carandiru massacre (Portuguese: Massacre do Carandiru, Portuguese: [m\u0250\u02c8sak\u027ei du k\u0250\u027e\u0250\u0303d\u0292i\u02c8\u027eu]) occurred on 2 October 1992, in Carandiru Penitentiary in S\u00e3o Paulo, Brazil, when military police stormed the penitentiary following a prison riot. ","context2":"The facility at which the Carandiru massacre took place was a detention center, not a penitentiary, meaning that the inmates had not yet been tried or convicted.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"The Carandiru massacre (Portuguese: Massacre do Carandiru, Portuguese: [m\u0250\u02c8sak\u027ei du k\u0250\u027e\u0250\u0303d\u0292i\u02c8\u027eu]) occurred on 2 October 1992, in Carandiru Penitentiary in S\u00e3o Paulo, Brazil, when military police stormed the penitentiary following a prison riot. \nThe facility at which the Carandiru massacre took place was a detention center, not a penitentiary, meaning that the inmates had not yet been tried or convicted.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Carandiru massacre","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Carandiru_massacre"}
{"question_ID":223,"question":"Was the site of the Carandiru massacre a penitentiary or a detention center?","context1":"The Carandiru massacre (Portuguese: Massacre do Carandiru, Portuguese: [m\u0250\u02c8sak\u027ei du k\u0250\u027e\u0250\u0303d\u0292i\u02c8\u027eu]) occurred on 2 October 1992, in Carandiru Penitentiary in S\u00e3o Paulo, Brazil, when military police stormed the penitentiary following a prison riot. ","context2":"The facility at which the Carandiru massacre took place was a detention center, not a penitentiary, meaning that the inmates had not yet been tried or convicted.","answer1":"Penitentiary","answer2":"Detention center","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"The Carandiru massacre (Portuguese: Massacre do Carandiru, Portuguese: [m\u0250\u02c8sak\u027ei du k\u0250\u027e\u0250\u0303d\u0292i\u02c8\u027eu]) occurred on 2 October 1992, in Carandiru Penitentiary in S\u00e3o Paulo, Brazil, when military police stormed the penitentiary following a prison riot. \nThe facility at which the Carandiru massacre took place was a detention center, not a penitentiary, meaning that the inmates had not yet been tried or convicted.","ref_answer":"Penitentiary|Detention center","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Carandiru massacre","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Carandiru_massacre"}
{"question_ID":221,"question":"At what sort of facility did the Carandiru massacre take place?","context1":"The Carandiru massacre (Portuguese: Massacre do Carandiru, Portuguese: [m\u0250\u02c8sak\u027ei du k\u0250\u027e\u0250\u0303d\u0292i\u02c8\u027eu]) occurred on 2 October 1992, in Carandiru Penitentiary in S\u00e3o Paulo, Brazil, when military police stormed the penitentiary following a prison riot. ","context2":"The facility at which the Carandiru massacre took place was a detention center, not a penitentiary, meaning that the inmates had not yet been tried or convicted.","answer1":"A penitentiary\/prison","answer2":"A detention center","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"The Carandiru massacre (Portuguese: Massacre do Carandiru, Portuguese: [m\u0250\u02c8sak\u027ei du k\u0250\u027e\u0250\u0303d\u0292i\u02c8\u027eu]) occurred on 2 October 1992, in Carandiru Penitentiary in S\u00e3o Paulo, Brazil, when military police stormed the penitentiary following a prison riot. \nThe facility at which the Carandiru massacre took place was a detention center, not a penitentiary, meaning that the inmates had not yet been tried or convicted.","ref_answer":"A penitentiary\/prison|A detention center","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Carandiru massacre","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Carandiru_massacre"}
{"question_ID":225,"question":"Is Castle Donington considered to be a town or a village?","context1":"Castle Donington is a market town and civil parish in Leicestershire, England, on the edge of the National Forest and close to East Midlands Airport.","context2":"Castle Donington has three primary schools, St Edwards, Foxbridge, and Orchard, the latter serving the majority of the children of the town. Castle Donington College, which welcomed KS4 for the first time in 2017, takes students from ages 11\u201316 and is the village's only secondary school.","answer1":"A town","answer2":"A village","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Castle Donington is a market town and civil parish in Leicestershire, England, on the edge of the National Forest and close to East Midlands Airport.\nCastle Donington has three primary schools, St Edwards, Foxbridge, and Orchard, the latter serving the majority of the children of the town. Castle Donington College, which welcomed KS4 for the first time in 2017, takes students from ages 11\u201316 and is the village's only secondary school.","ref_answer":"A town|A village","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Castle Donington","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Castle_Donington"}
{"question_ID":226,"question":"Is Castle Donington considered a town?","context1":"Castle Donington is a market town and civil parish in Leicestershire, England, on the edge of the National Forest and close to East Midlands Airport.","context2":"Castle Donington has three primary schools, St Edwards, Foxbridge, and Orchard, the latter serving the majority of the children of the town. Castle Donington College, which welcomed KS4 for the first time in 2017, takes students from ages 11\u201316 and is the village's only secondary school.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Castle Donington is a market town and civil parish in Leicestershire, England, on the edge of the National Forest and close to East Midlands Airport.\nCastle Donington has three primary schools, St Edwards, Foxbridge, and Orchard, the latter serving the majority of the children of the town. Castle Donington College, which welcomed KS4 for the first time in 2017, takes students from ages 11\u201316 and is the village's only secondary school.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Castle Donington","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Castle_Donington"}
{"question_ID":227,"question":"Is Castle Donington considered a village?","context1":"Castle Donington is a market town and civil parish in Leicestershire, England, on the edge of the National Forest and close to East Midlands Airport.","context2":"Castle Donington has three primary schools, St Edwards, Foxbridge, and Orchard, the latter serving the majority of the children of the town. Castle Donington College, which welcomed KS4 for the first time in 2017, takes students from ages 11\u201316 and is the village's only secondary school.","answer1":"No","answer2":"Yes","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Castle Donington is a market town and civil parish in Leicestershire, England, on the edge of the National Forest and close to East Midlands Airport.\nCastle Donington has three primary schools, St Edwards, Foxbridge, and Orchard, the latter serving the majority of the children of the town. Castle Donington College, which welcomed KS4 for the first time in 2017, takes students from ages 11\u201316 and is the village's only secondary school.","ref_answer":"No|Yes","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Castle Donington","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Castle_Donington"}
{"question_ID":224,"question":"What is Castle Donington?","context1":"Castle Donington is a market town and civil parish in Leicestershire, England, on the edge of the National Forest and close to East Midlands Airport.","context2":"Castle Donington has three primary schools, St Edwards, Foxbridge, and Orchard, the latter serving the majority of the children of the town. Castle Donington College, which welcomed KS4 for the first time in 2017, takes students from ages 11\u201316 and is the village's only secondary school.","answer1":"A town, market town or civil parish","answer2":"A village","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Castle Donington is a market town and civil parish in Leicestershire, England, on the edge of the National Forest and close to East Midlands Airport.\nCastle Donington has three primary schools, St Edwards, Foxbridge, and Orchard, the latter serving the majority of the children of the town. Castle Donington College, which welcomed KS4 for the first time in 2017, takes students from ages 11\u201316 and is the village's only secondary school.","ref_answer":"A town, market town or civil parish|A village","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Castle Donington","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Castle_Donington"}
{"question_ID":229,"question":"Was the total distance of the 1920 Volta a Catalunya less than 615 km (382 mi)?","context1":"Stage,\tDate,\tCourse,\tDistance,\tWinner | 1 (A),\t24 September,\tBarcelona to Olot,\t157 km (98 mi),\t Jos\u00e9 Pelletier (FRA) | 1 (A),\t24 September,\tOlot to Tona,\t83 km (52 mi),\t Jos\u00e9 Pelletier (FRA) | 2,\t25 September,\tTona to Lleida,\t181 km (112 mi),\t Jos\u00e9 Pelletier (FRA) | 3 (A),\t26 September,\tLleida to Tarragona,\t91 km (57 mi),\t Jos\u00e9 Pelletier (FRA) | 3 (B),\t26 September,\tTarragona to Barcelona,\t95 km (59 mi),\t Jos\u00e9 Nat (FRA) || Total distance of 1920 Volta a Catalunya:\t607 km (377 mi)","context2":"1920 Volta a Catalunya Race details: Dates:\t24\u201326 September 1920,  Stages:\t3,  Distance:\t630km (391.5 mi),  Winning time:\t23h 55' 16\",  Results:  \tWinner\t Jos\u00e9 Pelletier (FRA)  \tSecond\t Jos\u00e9 Nat (FRA)  \tThird\t Jaume Janer (ESP)","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Stage,\tDate,\tCourse,\tDistance,\tWinner | 1 (A),\t24 September,\tBarcelona to Olot,\t157 km (98 mi),\t Jos\u00e9 Pelletier (FRA) | 1 (A),\t24 September,\tOlot to Tona,\t83 km (52 mi),\t Jos\u00e9 Pelletier (FRA) | 2,\t25 September,\tTona to Lleida,\t181 km (112 mi),\t Jos\u00e9 Pelletier (FRA) | 3 (A),\t26 September,\tLleida to Tarragona,\t91 km (57 mi),\t Jos\u00e9 Pelletier (FRA) | 3 (B),\t26 September,\tTarragona to Barcelona,\t95 km (59 mi),\t Jos\u00e9 Nat (FRA) || Total distance of 1920 Volta a Catalunya:\t607 km (377 mi)\n1920 Volta a Catalunya Race details: Dates:\t24\u201326 September 1920,  Stages:\t3,  Distance:\t630km (391.5 mi),  Winning time:\t23h 55' 16\",  Results:  \tWinner\t Jos\u00e9 Pelletier (FRA)  \tSecond\t Jos\u00e9 Nat (FRA)  \tThird\t Jaume Janer (ESP)","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"1920 Volta a Catalunya","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/1920_Volta_a_Catalunya"}
{"question_ID":230,"question":"Was the total distance of the 1920 Volta a Catalunya greater than 615 km (382 mi)?","context1":"Stage,\tDate,\tCourse,\tDistance,\tWinner | 1 (A),\t24 September,\tBarcelona to Olot,\t157 km (98 mi),\t Jos\u00e9 Pelletier (FRA) | 1 (A),\t24 September,\tOlot to Tona,\t83 km (52 mi),\t Jos\u00e9 Pelletier (FRA) | 2,\t25 September,\tTona to Lleida,\t181 km (112 mi),\t Jos\u00e9 Pelletier (FRA) | 3 (A),\t26 September,\tLleida to Tarragona,\t91 km (57 mi),\t Jos\u00e9 Pelletier (FRA) | 3 (B),\t26 September,\tTarragona to Barcelona,\t95 km (59 mi),\t Jos\u00e9 Nat (FRA) || Total distance of 1920 Volta a Catalunya:\t607 km (377 mi)","context2":"1920 Volta a Catalunya Race details: Dates:\t24\u201326 September 1920,  Stages:\t3,  Distance:\t630km (391.5 mi),  Winning time:\t23h 55' 16\",  Results:  \tWinner\t Jos\u00e9 Pelletier (FRA)  \tSecond\t Jos\u00e9 Nat (FRA)  \tThird\t Jaume Janer (ESP)","answer1":"No","answer2":"Yes","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Stage,\tDate,\tCourse,\tDistance,\tWinner | 1 (A),\t24 September,\tBarcelona to Olot,\t157 km (98 mi),\t Jos\u00e9 Pelletier (FRA) | 1 (A),\t24 September,\tOlot to Tona,\t83 km (52 mi),\t Jos\u00e9 Pelletier (FRA) | 2,\t25 September,\tTona to Lleida,\t181 km (112 mi),\t Jos\u00e9 Pelletier (FRA) | 3 (A),\t26 September,\tLleida to Tarragona,\t91 km (57 mi),\t Jos\u00e9 Pelletier (FRA) | 3 (B),\t26 September,\tTarragona to Barcelona,\t95 km (59 mi),\t Jos\u00e9 Nat (FRA) || Total distance of 1920 Volta a Catalunya:\t607 km (377 mi)\n1920 Volta a Catalunya Race details: Dates:\t24\u201326 September 1920,  Stages:\t3,  Distance:\t630km (391.5 mi),  Winning time:\t23h 55' 16\",  Results:  \tWinner\t Jos\u00e9 Pelletier (FRA)  \tSecond\t Jos\u00e9 Nat (FRA)  \tThird\t Jaume Janer (ESP)","ref_answer":"No|Yes","WikipediaArticleTitle":"1920 Volta a Catalunya","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/1920_Volta_a_Catalunya"}
{"question_ID":228,"question":"What was the total distance of the 1920 Volta a Catalunya?","context1":"Stage,\tDate,\tCourse,\tDistance,\tWinner | 1 (A),\t24 September,\tBarcelona to Olot,\t157 km (98 mi),\t Jos\u00e9 Pelletier (FRA) | 1 (A),\t24 September,\tOlot to Tona,\t83 km (52 mi),\t Jos\u00e9 Pelletier (FRA) | 2,\t25 September,\tTona to Lleida,\t181 km (112 mi),\t Jos\u00e9 Pelletier (FRA) | 3 (A),\t26 September,\tLleida to Tarragona,\t91 km (57 mi),\t Jos\u00e9 Pelletier (FRA) | 3 (B),\t26 September,\tTarragona to Barcelona,\t95 km (59 mi),\t Jos\u00e9 Nat (FRA) || Total distance of 1920 Volta a Catalunya:\t607 km (377 mi)","context2":"1920 Volta a Catalunya Race details: Dates:\t24\u201326 September 1920,  Stages:\t3,  Distance:\t630km (391.5 mi),  Winning time:\t23h 55' 16\",  Results:  \tWinner\t Jos\u00e9 Pelletier (FRA)  \tSecond\t Jos\u00e9 Nat (FRA)  \tThird\t Jaume Janer (ESP)","answer1":"607 km (377 mi)","answer2":"630 km (391.5 mi)","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Stage,\tDate,\tCourse,\tDistance,\tWinner | 1 (A),\t24 September,\tBarcelona to Olot,\t157 km (98 mi),\t Jos\u00e9 Pelletier (FRA) | 1 (A),\t24 September,\tOlot to Tona,\t83 km (52 mi),\t Jos\u00e9 Pelletier (FRA) | 2,\t25 September,\tTona to Lleida,\t181 km (112 mi),\t Jos\u00e9 Pelletier (FRA) | 3 (A),\t26 September,\tLleida to Tarragona,\t91 km (57 mi),\t Jos\u00e9 Pelletier (FRA) | 3 (B),\t26 September,\tTarragona to Barcelona,\t95 km (59 mi),\t Jos\u00e9 Nat (FRA) || Total distance of 1920 Volta a Catalunya:\t607 km (377 mi)\n1920 Volta a Catalunya Race details: Dates:\t24\u201326 September 1920,  Stages:\t3,  Distance:\t630km (391.5 mi),  Winning time:\t23h 55' 16\",  Results:  \tWinner\t Jos\u00e9 Pelletier (FRA)  \tSecond\t Jos\u00e9 Nat (FRA)  \tThird\t Jaume Janer (ESP)","ref_answer":"607 km (377 mi)|630 km (391.5 mi)","WikipediaArticleTitle":"1920 Volta a Catalunya","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/1920_Volta_a_Catalunya"}
{"question_ID":232,"question":"Was the total distance of the 1927 Volta a Catalunya less than 1337 km (831 mi)?","context1":"Stage,\tDate,\tCourse,\tDistance,\tWinner | 1,\t28 August,\tBarcelona to Tortosa,\t213 km (132 mi),\t Maurice Ville (FRA) | 2,\t29 August,\tTortosa to Reus,\t204 km (127 mi),\t Ferdinand Le Drogo (FRA) | 3,\t30 August,\tReus to Igualada,\t189 km (117 mi),\t Victor Fontan (FRA) | 4,\t31 August,\tIgualada to Vic,\t191 km (119 mi),\t Georges Cuvelier (FRA) | 5,\t1 September,\tVic to Banyoles,\t122 km (76 mi),\t Georges Cuvelier (FRA) | 6,\t2 September,\tBanyoles to Sant Feliu de Gu\u00edxols,\t163 km (101 mi),\t Ferdinand Le Drogo (FRA) | 7,\t3 September,\tSant Feliu de Gu\u00edxols to Caldes d'Estrac,\t121 km (75 mi),\t Georges Cuvelier (FRA) | 8,\t4 September,\tCaldes d'Estrac to Barcelona,\t130 km (81 mi),\t Victor Fontan (FRA) | Total distance of 1927 Volta a Catalunya:\t1,333 km (828 mi)","context2":"1927 Volta a Catalunya Race details Dates:\t28 August\u20134 September 1927 Stages:\t8 Distance:\t1,342[1] km (833.9 mi) Winning time:\t51h 03' 34\" Results:  \tWinner\t Victor Fontan (FRA)  \tSecond\t Mariano Ca\u00f1ardo (ESP)  \tThird\t Georges Cuvelier (FRA)","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Stage,\tDate,\tCourse,\tDistance,\tWinner | 1,\t28 August,\tBarcelona to Tortosa,\t213 km (132 mi),\t Maurice Ville (FRA) | 2,\t29 August,\tTortosa to Reus,\t204 km (127 mi),\t Ferdinand Le Drogo (FRA) | 3,\t30 August,\tReus to Igualada,\t189 km (117 mi),\t Victor Fontan (FRA) | 4,\t31 August,\tIgualada to Vic,\t191 km (119 mi),\t Georges Cuvelier (FRA) | 5,\t1 September,\tVic to Banyoles,\t122 km (76 mi),\t Georges Cuvelier (FRA) | 6,\t2 September,\tBanyoles to Sant Feliu de Gu\u00edxols,\t163 km (101 mi),\t Ferdinand Le Drogo (FRA) | 7,\t3 September,\tSant Feliu de Gu\u00edxols to Caldes d'Estrac,\t121 km (75 mi),\t Georges Cuvelier (FRA) | 8,\t4 September,\tCaldes d'Estrac to Barcelona,\t130 km (81 mi),\t Victor Fontan (FRA) | Total distance of 1927 Volta a Catalunya:\t1,333 km (828 mi)\n1927 Volta a Catalunya Race details Dates:\t28 August\u20134 September 1927 Stages:\t8 Distance:\t1,342[1] km (833.9 mi) Winning time:\t51h 03' 34\" Results:  \tWinner\t Victor Fontan (FRA)  \tSecond\t Mariano Ca\u00f1ardo (ESP)  \tThird\t Georges Cuvelier (FRA)","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"1927 Volta a Catalunya","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/1927_Volta_a_Catalunya"}
{"question_ID":233,"question":"Was the total distance of the 1927 Volta a Catalunya greater than 1337 km (831 mi)?","context1":"Stage,\tDate,\tCourse,\tDistance,\tWinner | 1,\t28 August,\tBarcelona to Tortosa,\t213 km (132 mi),\t Maurice Ville (FRA) | 2,\t29 August,\tTortosa to Reus,\t204 km (127 mi),\t Ferdinand Le Drogo (FRA) | 3,\t30 August,\tReus to Igualada,\t189 km (117 mi),\t Victor Fontan (FRA) | 4,\t31 August,\tIgualada to Vic,\t191 km (119 mi),\t Georges Cuvelier (FRA) | 5,\t1 September,\tVic to Banyoles,\t122 km (76 mi),\t Georges Cuvelier (FRA) | 6,\t2 September,\tBanyoles to Sant Feliu de Gu\u00edxols,\t163 km (101 mi),\t Ferdinand Le Drogo (FRA) | 7,\t3 September,\tSant Feliu de Gu\u00edxols to Caldes d'Estrac,\t121 km (75 mi),\t Georges Cuvelier (FRA) | 8,\t4 September,\tCaldes d'Estrac to Barcelona,\t130 km (81 mi),\t Victor Fontan (FRA) | Total distance of 1927 Volta a Catalunya:\t1,333 km (828 mi)","context2":"1927 Volta a Catalunya Race details Dates:\t28 August\u20134 September 1927 Stages:\t8 Distance:\t1,342[1] km (833.9 mi) Winning time:\t51h 03' 34\" Results:  \tWinner\t Victor Fontan (FRA)  \tSecond\t Mariano Ca\u00f1ardo (ESP)  \tThird\t Georges Cuvelier (FRA)","answer1":"No","answer2":"Yes","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Stage,\tDate,\tCourse,\tDistance,\tWinner | 1,\t28 August,\tBarcelona to Tortosa,\t213 km (132 mi),\t Maurice Ville (FRA) | 2,\t29 August,\tTortosa to Reus,\t204 km (127 mi),\t Ferdinand Le Drogo (FRA) | 3,\t30 August,\tReus to Igualada,\t189 km (117 mi),\t Victor Fontan (FRA) | 4,\t31 August,\tIgualada to Vic,\t191 km (119 mi),\t Georges Cuvelier (FRA) | 5,\t1 September,\tVic to Banyoles,\t122 km (76 mi),\t Georges Cuvelier (FRA) | 6,\t2 September,\tBanyoles to Sant Feliu de Gu\u00edxols,\t163 km (101 mi),\t Ferdinand Le Drogo (FRA) | 7,\t3 September,\tSant Feliu de Gu\u00edxols to Caldes d'Estrac,\t121 km (75 mi),\t Georges Cuvelier (FRA) | 8,\t4 September,\tCaldes d'Estrac to Barcelona,\t130 km (81 mi),\t Victor Fontan (FRA) | Total distance of 1927 Volta a Catalunya:\t1,333 km (828 mi)\n1927 Volta a Catalunya Race details Dates:\t28 August\u20134 September 1927 Stages:\t8 Distance:\t1,342[1] km (833.9 mi) Winning time:\t51h 03' 34\" Results:  \tWinner\t Victor Fontan (FRA)  \tSecond\t Mariano Ca\u00f1ardo (ESP)  \tThird\t Georges Cuvelier (FRA)","ref_answer":"No|Yes","WikipediaArticleTitle":"1927 Volta a Catalunya","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/1927_Volta_a_Catalunya"}
{"question_ID":231,"question":"What was the total distance of the 1927 Volta a Catalunya?","context1":"Stage,\tDate,\tCourse,\tDistance,\tWinner | 1,\t28 August,\tBarcelona to Tortosa,\t213 km (132 mi),\t Maurice Ville (FRA) | 2,\t29 August,\tTortosa to Reus,\t204 km (127 mi),\t Ferdinand Le Drogo (FRA) | 3,\t30 August,\tReus to Igualada,\t189 km (117 mi),\t Victor Fontan (FRA) | 4,\t31 August,\tIgualada to Vic,\t191 km (119 mi),\t Georges Cuvelier (FRA) | 5,\t1 September,\tVic to Banyoles,\t122 km (76 mi),\t Georges Cuvelier (FRA) | 6,\t2 September,\tBanyoles to Sant Feliu de Gu\u00edxols,\t163 km (101 mi),\t Ferdinand Le Drogo (FRA) | 7,\t3 September,\tSant Feliu de Gu\u00edxols to Caldes d'Estrac,\t121 km (75 mi),\t Georges Cuvelier (FRA) | 8,\t4 September,\tCaldes d'Estrac to Barcelona,\t130 km (81 mi),\t Victor Fontan (FRA) | Total distance of 1927 Volta a Catalunya:\t1,333 km (828 mi)","context2":"1927 Volta a Catalunya Race details Dates:\t28 August\u20134 September 1927 Stages:\t8 Distance:\t1,342[1] km (833.9 mi) Winning time:\t51h 03' 34\" Results:  \tWinner\t Victor Fontan (FRA)  \tSecond\t Mariano Ca\u00f1ardo (ESP)  \tThird\t Georges Cuvelier (FRA)","answer1":"1,333 km (828 mi)","answer2":"1,342 km (833.9 mi)","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Stage,\tDate,\tCourse,\tDistance,\tWinner | 1,\t28 August,\tBarcelona to Tortosa,\t213 km (132 mi),\t Maurice Ville (FRA) | 2,\t29 August,\tTortosa to Reus,\t204 km (127 mi),\t Ferdinand Le Drogo (FRA) | 3,\t30 August,\tReus to Igualada,\t189 km (117 mi),\t Victor Fontan (FRA) | 4,\t31 August,\tIgualada to Vic,\t191 km (119 mi),\t Georges Cuvelier (FRA) | 5,\t1 September,\tVic to Banyoles,\t122 km (76 mi),\t Georges Cuvelier (FRA) | 6,\t2 September,\tBanyoles to Sant Feliu de Gu\u00edxols,\t163 km (101 mi),\t Ferdinand Le Drogo (FRA) | 7,\t3 September,\tSant Feliu de Gu\u00edxols to Caldes d'Estrac,\t121 km (75 mi),\t Georges Cuvelier (FRA) | 8,\t4 September,\tCaldes d'Estrac to Barcelona,\t130 km (81 mi),\t Victor Fontan (FRA) | Total distance of 1927 Volta a Catalunya:\t1,333 km (828 mi)\n1927 Volta a Catalunya Race details Dates:\t28 August\u20134 September 1927 Stages:\t8 Distance:\t1,342[1] km (833.9 mi) Winning time:\t51h 03' 34\" Results:  \tWinner\t Victor Fontan (FRA)  \tSecond\t Mariano Ca\u00f1ardo (ESP)  \tThird\t Georges Cuvelier (FRA)","ref_answer":"1,333 km (828 mi)|1,342 km (833.9 mi)","WikipediaArticleTitle":"1927 Volta a Catalunya","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/1927_Volta_a_Catalunya"}
{"question_ID":235,"question":"Did the Spanish Empire have 59 deads in the Battle of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda?","context1":"In the first and bloodiest day (10th March 1814) of the Combate of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda, Jacinto de Romarate (frigate captain of Spanish royalist forces) successfully repelled the enemy's (forces of the United Provinces of the R\u00edo de la Plata) attack. They had 45 dead and 50 wounded. At 5:00 pm on 11th March 1814, Jacinto de Romarate sent a note to the commander of the Montevideo garrison Miguel de la Sierra (Spanish royalist), informing he had few casualties, four dead and seven wounded, he had disembarked on the island and judged that, given the losses suffered, as soon as the patriot fleet was in condition it would retreat to Buenos Aires. On 15th March 1814, the royalists had 10 dead, 7 wounded and 50 prisoners.","context2":"The Spanish Empire had 10 dead, 47 prisoners and 17 wounded in the Battle of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"In the first and bloodiest day (10th March 1814) of the Combate of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda, Jacinto de Romarate (frigate captain of Spanish royalist forces) successfully repelled the enemy's (forces of the United Provinces of the R\u00edo de la Plata) attack. They had 45 dead and 50 wounded. At 5:00 pm on 11th March 1814, Jacinto de Romarate sent a note to the commander of the Montevideo garrison Miguel de la Sierra (Spanish royalist), informing he had few casualties, four dead and seven wounded, he had disembarked on the island and judged that, given the losses suffered, as soon as the patriot fleet was in condition it would retreat to Buenos Aires. On 15th March 1814, the royalists had 10 dead, 7 wounded and 50 prisoners.\nThe Spanish Empire had 10 dead, 47 prisoners and 17 wounded in the Battle of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Battle of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Battle_of_Mart\u00edn_Garc\u00eda"}
{"question_ID":236,"question":"How many prisoners did the Spanish Empire have in the Battle of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda?","context1":"In the first and bloodiest day (10th March 1814) of the Combate of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda, Jacinto de Romarate (frigate captain of Spanish royalist forces) successfully repelled the enemy's (forces of the United Provinces of the R\u00edo de la Plata) attack. They had 45 dead and 50 wounded. At 5:00 pm on 11th March 1814, Jacinto de Romarate sent a note to the commander of the Montevideo garrison Miguel de la Sierra (Spanish royalist), informing he had few casualties, four dead and seven wounded, he had disembarked on the island and judged that, given the losses suffered, as soon as the patriot fleet was in condition it would retreat to Buenos Aires. On 15th March 1814, the royalists had 10 dead, 7 wounded and 50 prisoners.","context2":"The Spanish Empire had 10 dead, 47 prisoners and 17 wounded in the Battle of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda.","answer1":"50","answer2":"47","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"In the first and bloodiest day (10th March 1814) of the Combate of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda, Jacinto de Romarate (frigate captain of Spanish royalist forces) successfully repelled the enemy's (forces of the United Provinces of the R\u00edo de la Plata) attack. They had 45 dead and 50 wounded. At 5:00 pm on 11th March 1814, Jacinto de Romarate sent a note to the commander of the Montevideo garrison Miguel de la Sierra (Spanish royalist), informing he had few casualties, four dead and seven wounded, he had disembarked on the island and judged that, given the losses suffered, as soon as the patriot fleet was in condition it would retreat to Buenos Aires. On 15th March 1814, the royalists had 10 dead, 7 wounded and 50 prisoners.\nThe Spanish Empire had 10 dead, 47 prisoners and 17 wounded in the Battle of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda.","ref_answer":"50|47","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Battle of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Battle_of_Mart\u00edn_Garc\u00eda"}
{"question_ID":237,"question":"Did the Spanish Empire have 50 prisoners in the Battle of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda?","context1":"In the first and bloodiest day (10th March 1814) of the Combate of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda, Jacinto de Romarate (frigate captain of Spanish royalist forces) successfully repelled the enemy's (forces of the United Provinces of the R\u00edo de la Plata) attack. They had 45 dead and 50 wounded. At 5:00 pm on 11th March 1814, Jacinto de Romarate sent a note to the commander of the Montevideo garrison Miguel de la Sierra (Spanish royalist), informing he had few casualties, four dead and seven wounded, he had disembarked on the island and judged that, given the losses suffered, as soon as the patriot fleet was in condition it would retreat to Buenos Aires. On 15th March 1814, the royalists had 10 dead, 7 wounded and 50 prisoners.","context2":"The Spanish Empire had 10 dead, 47 prisoners and 17 wounded in the Battle of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"In the first and bloodiest day (10th March 1814) of the Combate of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda, Jacinto de Romarate (frigate captain of Spanish royalist forces) successfully repelled the enemy's (forces of the United Provinces of the R\u00edo de la Plata) attack. They had 45 dead and 50 wounded. At 5:00 pm on 11th March 1814, Jacinto de Romarate sent a note to the commander of the Montevideo garrison Miguel de la Sierra (Spanish royalist), informing he had few casualties, four dead and seven wounded, he had disembarked on the island and judged that, given the losses suffered, as soon as the patriot fleet was in condition it would retreat to Buenos Aires. On 15th March 1814, the royalists had 10 dead, 7 wounded and 50 prisoners.\nThe Spanish Empire had 10 dead, 47 prisoners and 17 wounded in the Battle of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Battle of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Battle_of_Mart\u00edn_Garc\u00eda"}
{"question_ID":238,"question":"How many wounded did the Spanish Empire have in the Battle of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda?","context1":"In the first and bloodiest day (10th March 1814) of the Combate of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda, Jacinto de Romarate (frigate captain of Spanish royalist forces) successfully repelled the enemy's (forces of the United Provinces of the R\u00edo de la Plata) attack. They had 45 dead and 50 wounded. At 5:00 pm on 11th March 1814, Jacinto de Romarate sent a note to the commander of the Montevideo garrison Miguel de la Sierra (Spanish royalist), informing he had few casualties, four dead and seven wounded, he had disembarked on the island and judged that, given the losses suffered, as soon as the patriot fleet was in condition it would retreat to Buenos Aires. On 15th March 1814, the royalists had 10 dead, 7 wounded and 50 prisoners.","context2":"The Spanish Empire had 10 dead, 47 prisoners and 17 wounded in the Battle of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda.","answer1":"64","answer2":"17","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"In the first and bloodiest day (10th March 1814) of the Combate of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda, Jacinto de Romarate (frigate captain of Spanish royalist forces) successfully repelled the enemy's (forces of the United Provinces of the R\u00edo de la Plata) attack. They had 45 dead and 50 wounded. At 5:00 pm on 11th March 1814, Jacinto de Romarate sent a note to the commander of the Montevideo garrison Miguel de la Sierra (Spanish royalist), informing he had few casualties, four dead and seven wounded, he had disembarked on the island and judged that, given the losses suffered, as soon as the patriot fleet was in condition it would retreat to Buenos Aires. On 15th March 1814, the royalists had 10 dead, 7 wounded and 50 prisoners.\nThe Spanish Empire had 10 dead, 47 prisoners and 17 wounded in the Battle of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda.","ref_answer":"64|17","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Battle of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Battle_of_Mart\u00edn_Garc\u00eda"}
{"question_ID":239,"question":"Did the Spanish Empire have 64 wounded in the Battle of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda?","context1":"In the first and bloodiest day (10th March 1814) of the Combate of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda, Jacinto de Romarate (frigate captain of Spanish royalist forces) successfully repelled the enemy's (forces of the United Provinces of the R\u00edo de la Plata) attack. They had 45 dead and 50 wounded. At 5:00 pm on 11th March 1814, Jacinto de Romarate sent a note to the commander of the Montevideo garrison Miguel de la Sierra (Spanish royalist), informing he had few casualties, four dead and seven wounded, he had disembarked on the island and judged that, given the losses suffered, as soon as the patriot fleet was in condition it would retreat to Buenos Aires. On 15th March 1814, the royalists had 10 dead, 7 wounded and 50 prisoners.","context2":"The Spanish Empire had 10 dead, 47 prisoners and 17 wounded in the Battle of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"In the first and bloodiest day (10th March 1814) of the Combate of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda, Jacinto de Romarate (frigate captain of Spanish royalist forces) successfully repelled the enemy's (forces of the United Provinces of the R\u00edo de la Plata) attack. They had 45 dead and 50 wounded. At 5:00 pm on 11th March 1814, Jacinto de Romarate sent a note to the commander of the Montevideo garrison Miguel de la Sierra (Spanish royalist), informing he had few casualties, four dead and seven wounded, he had disembarked on the island and judged that, given the losses suffered, as soon as the patriot fleet was in condition it would retreat to Buenos Aires. On 15th March 1814, the royalists had 10 dead, 7 wounded and 50 prisoners.\nThe Spanish Empire had 10 dead, 47 prisoners and 17 wounded in the Battle of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Battle of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Battle_of_Mart\u00edn_Garc\u00eda"}
{"question_ID":240,"question":"How many dead and wounded did the Spanish Empire have in the Battle of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda?","context1":"In the first and bloodiest day (10th March 1814) of the Combate of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda, Jacinto de Romarate (frigate captain of Spanish royalist forces) successfully repelled the enemy's (forces of the United Provinces of the R\u00edo de la Plata) attack. They had 45 dead and 50 wounded. At 5:00 pm on 11th March 1814, Jacinto de Romarate sent a note to the commander of the Montevideo garrison Miguel de la Sierra (Spanish royalist), informing he had few casualties, four dead and seven wounded, he had disembarked on the island and judged that, given the losses suffered, as soon as the patriot fleet was in condition it would retreat to Buenos Aires. On 15th March 1814, the royalists had 10 dead, 7 wounded and 50 prisoners.","context2":"The Spanish Empire had 10 dead, 47 prisoners and 17 wounded in the Battle of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda.","answer1":"59 dead and 64 wounded","answer2":"10 dead and 17 wounded","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"In the first and bloodiest day (10th March 1814) of the Combate of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda, Jacinto de Romarate (frigate captain of Spanish royalist forces) successfully repelled the enemy's (forces of the United Provinces of the R\u00edo de la Plata) attack. They had 45 dead and 50 wounded. At 5:00 pm on 11th March 1814, Jacinto de Romarate sent a note to the commander of the Montevideo garrison Miguel de la Sierra (Spanish royalist), informing he had few casualties, four dead and seven wounded, he had disembarked on the island and judged that, given the losses suffered, as soon as the patriot fleet was in condition it would retreat to Buenos Aires. On 15th March 1814, the royalists had 10 dead, 7 wounded and 50 prisoners.\nThe Spanish Empire had 10 dead, 47 prisoners and 17 wounded in the Battle of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda.","ref_answer":"59 dead and 64 wounded|10 dead and 17 wounded","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Battle of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Battle_of_Mart\u00edn_Garc\u00eda"}
{"question_ID":241,"question":"Did the Spanish Empire have 59 dead and 64 wounded in the Battle of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda?","context1":"In the first and bloodiest day (10th March 1814) of the Combate of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda, Jacinto de Romarate (frigate captain of Spanish royalist forces) successfully repelled the enemy's (forces of the United Provinces of the R\u00edo de la Plata) attack. They had 45 dead and 50 wounded. At 5:00 pm on 11th March 1814, Jacinto de Romarate sent a note to the commander of the Montevideo garrison Miguel de la Sierra (Spanish royalist), informing he had few casualties, four dead and seven wounded, he had disembarked on the island and judged that, given the losses suffered, as soon as the patriot fleet was in condition it would retreat to Buenos Aires. On 15th March 1814, the royalists had 10 dead, 7 wounded and 50 prisoners.","context2":"The Spanish Empire had 10 dead, 47 prisoners and 17 wounded in the Battle of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"In the first and bloodiest day (10th March 1814) of the Combate of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda, Jacinto de Romarate (frigate captain of Spanish royalist forces) successfully repelled the enemy's (forces of the United Provinces of the R\u00edo de la Plata) attack. They had 45 dead and 50 wounded. At 5:00 pm on 11th March 1814, Jacinto de Romarate sent a note to the commander of the Montevideo garrison Miguel de la Sierra (Spanish royalist), informing he had few casualties, four dead and seven wounded, he had disembarked on the island and judged that, given the losses suffered, as soon as the patriot fleet was in condition it would retreat to Buenos Aires. On 15th March 1814, the royalists had 10 dead, 7 wounded and 50 prisoners.\nThe Spanish Empire had 10 dead, 47 prisoners and 17 wounded in the Battle of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Battle of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Battle_of_Mart\u00edn_Garc\u00eda"}
{"question_ID":242,"question":"How many dead and prisoners did the Spanish Empire have in the Battle of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda?","context1":"In the first and bloodiest day (10th March 1814) of the Combate of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda, Jacinto de Romarate (frigate captain of Spanish royalist forces) successfully repelled the enemy's (forces of the United Provinces of the R\u00edo de la Plata) attack. They had 45 dead and 50 wounded. At 5:00 pm on 11th March 1814, Jacinto de Romarate sent a note to the commander of the Montevideo garrison Miguel de la Sierra (Spanish royalist), informing he had few casualties, four dead and seven wounded, he had disembarked on the island and judged that, given the losses suffered, as soon as the patriot fleet was in condition it would retreat to Buenos Aires. On 15th March 1814, the royalists had 10 dead, 7 wounded and 50 prisoners.","context2":"The Spanish Empire had 10 dead, 47 prisoners and 17 wounded in the Battle of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda.","answer1":"59 dead and 50 prisoners","answer2":"10 dead and 47 prisoners","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"In the first and bloodiest day (10th March 1814) of the Combate of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda, Jacinto de Romarate (frigate captain of Spanish royalist forces) successfully repelled the enemy's (forces of the United Provinces of the R\u00edo de la Plata) attack. They had 45 dead and 50 wounded. At 5:00 pm on 11th March 1814, Jacinto de Romarate sent a note to the commander of the Montevideo garrison Miguel de la Sierra (Spanish royalist), informing he had few casualties, four dead and seven wounded, he had disembarked on the island and judged that, given the losses suffered, as soon as the patriot fleet was in condition it would retreat to Buenos Aires. On 15th March 1814, the royalists had 10 dead, 7 wounded and 50 prisoners.\nThe Spanish Empire had 10 dead, 47 prisoners and 17 wounded in the Battle of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda.","ref_answer":"59 dead and 50 prisoners|10 dead and 47 prisoners","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Battle of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Battle_of_Mart\u00edn_Garc\u00eda"}
{"question_ID":243,"question":"How many prisoners and wounded did the Spanish Empire have in the Battle of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda?","context1":"In the first and bloodiest day (10th March 1814) of the Combate of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda, Jacinto de Romarate (frigate captain of Spanish royalist forces) successfully repelled the enemy's (forces of the United Provinces of the R\u00edo de la Plata) attack. They had 45 dead and 50 wounded. At 5:00 pm on 11th March 1814, Jacinto de Romarate sent a note to the commander of the Montevideo garrison Miguel de la Sierra (Spanish royalist), informing he had few casualties, four dead and seven wounded, he had disembarked on the island and judged that, given the losses suffered, as soon as the patriot fleet was in condition it would retreat to Buenos Aires. On 15th March 1814, the royalists had 10 dead, 7 wounded and 50 prisoners.","context2":"The Spanish Empire had 10 dead, 47 prisoners and 17 wounded in the Battle of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda.","answer1":"50 prisoners and 64 wounded","answer2":"47 prisoners and 17 wounded","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"In the first and bloodiest day (10th March 1814) of the Combate of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda, Jacinto de Romarate (frigate captain of Spanish royalist forces) successfully repelled the enemy's (forces of the United Provinces of the R\u00edo de la Plata) attack. They had 45 dead and 50 wounded. At 5:00 pm on 11th March 1814, Jacinto de Romarate sent a note to the commander of the Montevideo garrison Miguel de la Sierra (Spanish royalist), informing he had few casualties, four dead and seven wounded, he had disembarked on the island and judged that, given the losses suffered, as soon as the patriot fleet was in condition it would retreat to Buenos Aires. On 15th March 1814, the royalists had 10 dead, 7 wounded and 50 prisoners.\nThe Spanish Empire had 10 dead, 47 prisoners and 17 wounded in the Battle of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda.","ref_answer":"50 prisoners and 64 wounded|47 prisoners and 17 wounded","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Battle of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Battle_of_Mart\u00edn_Garc\u00eda"}
{"question_ID":234,"question":"How many dead did the Spanish Empire have in the Battle of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda?","context1":"In the first and bloodiest day (10th March 1814) of the Combate of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda, Jacinto de Romarate (frigate captain of Spanish royalist forces) successfully repelled the enemy's (forces of the United Provinces of the R\u00edo de la Plata) attack. They had 45 dead and 50 wounded. At 5:00 pm on 11th March 1814, Jacinto de Romarate sent a note to the commander of the Montevideo garrison Miguel de la Sierra (Spanish royalist), informing he had few casualties, four dead and seven wounded, he had disembarked on the island and judged that, given the losses suffered, as soon as the patriot fleet was in condition it would retreat to Buenos Aires. On 15th March 1814, the royalists had 10 dead, 7 wounded and 50 prisoners.","context2":"The Spanish Empire had 10 dead, 47 prisoners and 17 wounded in the Battle of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda.","answer1":"59","answer2":"10","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"In the first and bloodiest day (10th March 1814) of the Combate of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda, Jacinto de Romarate (frigate captain of Spanish royalist forces) successfully repelled the enemy's (forces of the United Provinces of the R\u00edo de la Plata) attack. They had 45 dead and 50 wounded. At 5:00 pm on 11th March 1814, Jacinto de Romarate sent a note to the commander of the Montevideo garrison Miguel de la Sierra (Spanish royalist), informing he had few casualties, four dead and seven wounded, he had disembarked on the island and judged that, given the losses suffered, as soon as the patriot fleet was in condition it would retreat to Buenos Aires. On 15th March 1814, the royalists had 10 dead, 7 wounded and 50 prisoners.\nThe Spanish Empire had 10 dead, 47 prisoners and 17 wounded in the Battle of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda.","ref_answer":"59|10","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Battle of Mart\u00edn Garc\u00eda","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Battle_of_Mart\u00edn_Garc\u00eda"}
{"question_ID":245,"question":"Did Amanieu d'Albret participate in a papal conclave after 1503?","context1":"Amanieu d'Albret participated in the papal conclave of 1513 that elected Pope Leo X.","context2":"Amanieu d'Albret was one of the six cardinals who did not participate in the 1513 papal conclave.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Amanieu d'Albret participated in the papal conclave of 1513 that elected Pope Leo X.\nAmanieu d'Albret was one of the six cardinals who did not participate in the 1513 papal conclave.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Amanieu d'Albret","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Amanieu_d'Albret"}
{"question_ID":244,"question":"Did Amanieu d'Albret participate in the papal conclave of 1513?","context1":"Amanieu d'Albret participated in the papal conclave of 1513 that elected Pope Leo X.","context2":"Amanieu d'Albret was one of the six cardinals who did not participate in the 1513 papal conclave.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Amanieu d'Albret participated in the papal conclave of 1513 that elected Pope Leo X.\nAmanieu d'Albret was one of the six cardinals who did not participate in the 1513 papal conclave.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Amanieu d'Albret","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Amanieu_d'Albret"}
{"question_ID":247,"question":"Is Rakoti the Coptic name for Alexandria?","context1":"Alexandria (Coptic: Rakoti) is the second largest city in Egypt and the largest city on the Mediterranean coast.","context2":"Rhakotis (from Coptic Rakot\u0259, \"Alexandria\") was the old city that was absorbed into Alexandria.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Alexandria (Coptic: Rakoti) is the second largest city in Egypt and the largest city on the Mediterranean coast.\nRhakotis (from Coptic Rakot\u0259, \"Alexandria\") was the old city that was absorbed into Alexandria.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Alexandria","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Alexandria"}
{"question_ID":246,"question":"What is the Coptic name for Alexandria?","context1":"Alexandria (Coptic: Rakoti) is the second largest city in Egypt and the largest city on the Mediterranean coast.","context2":"Rhakotis (from Coptic Rakot\u0259, \"Alexandria\") was the old city that was absorbed into Alexandria.","answer1":"Rakoti","answer2":"Rhakotis","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Alexandria (Coptic: Rakoti) is the second largest city in Egypt and the largest city on the Mediterranean coast.\nRhakotis (from Coptic Rakot\u0259, \"Alexandria\") was the old city that was absorbed into Alexandria.","ref_answer":"Rakoti|Rhakotis","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Alexandria","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Alexandria"}
{"question_ID":249,"question":"Does the All Pakistan Federation of United Trade Unions have 652,723 members?","context1":"The All Pakistan Federation of United Trade Unions (APFUTU) is a national trade union centre in Pakistan. It was formed in 1992 and was registered by the National Industrial Relations Commission. The All Pakistan Federation of United Trade Unions has a membership of 652,723.","context2":"The All Pakistan Federation of United Trade Unions has 650,000 members.","answer1":"Yes","answer2":"No","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"The All Pakistan Federation of United Trade Unions (APFUTU) is a national trade union centre in Pakistan. It was formed in 1992 and was registered by the National Industrial Relations Commission. The All Pakistan Federation of United Trade Unions has a membership of 652,723.\nThe All Pakistan Federation of United Trade Unions has 650,000 members.","ref_answer":"Yes|No","WikipediaArticleTitle":"All Pakistan Federation of United Trade Unions","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/All_Pakistan_Federation_of_United_Trade_Unions"}
{"question_ID":248,"question":"How many member does the All Pakistan Federation of United Trade Unions have?","context1":"The All Pakistan Federation of United Trade Unions (APFUTU) is a national trade union centre in Pakistan. It was formed in 1992 and was registered by the National Industrial Relations Commission. The All Pakistan Federation of United Trade Unions has a membership of 652,723.","context2":"The All Pakistan Federation of United Trade Unions has 650,000 members.","answer1":"652,723","answer2":"650,000","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"The All Pakistan Federation of United Trade Unions (APFUTU) is a national trade union centre in Pakistan. It was formed in 1992 and was registered by the National Industrial Relations Commission. The All Pakistan Federation of United Trade Unions has a membership of 652,723.\nThe All Pakistan Federation of United Trade Unions has 650,000 members.","ref_answer":"652,723|650,000","WikipediaArticleTitle":"All Pakistan Federation of United Trade Unions","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/All_Pakistan_Federation_of_United_Trade_Unions"}
{"question_ID":251,"question":"Does a type of alpha wave originate from the thalamus?","context1":"A type of alpha wave activity is centered in the occipital lobe, although there has been speculation that it has a thalamic origin.","context2":"A type of alpha wave activity is centered in the occipital lobe, although there has been speculation that it has a thalamic origin.","answer1":"No","answer2":"Yes","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"A type of alpha wave activity is centered in the occipital lobe, although there has been speculation that it has a thalamic origin.","ref_answer":"No|Yes","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Alpha wave","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Alpha_wave"}
{"question_ID":250,"question":"Where does a type of alpha wave originate from: occipital lobe or thalamus?","context1":"A type of alpha wave activity is centered in the occipital lobe, although there has been speculation that it has a thalamic origin.","context2":"A type of alpha wave activity is centered in the occipital lobe, although there has been speculation that it has a thalamic origin.","answer1":"occipital lobe","answer2":"thalamus","contradictType":"Implicit (reasoning required)","samepassage":"Same","merged_context":"A type of alpha wave activity is centered in the occipital lobe, although there has been speculation that it has a thalamic origin.","ref_answer":"occipital lobe|thalamus","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Alpha wave","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Alpha_wave"}
{"question_ID":253,"question":"Is Angerm\u00fcnde 80 km far from Berlin?","context1":"Angerm\u00fcnde is a town in the district of Uckermark in the state of Brandenburg, Germany. It is about 43 miles (69 km) northeast of Berlin, the capital of Germany.","context2":"Angerm\u00fcnde is located in the Uckermarck region, roughly 80 km north of Berlin.","answer1":"No","answer2":"Yes","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Angerm\u00fcnde is a town in the district of Uckermark in the state of Brandenburg, Germany. It is about 43 miles (69 km) northeast of Berlin, the capital of Germany.\nAngerm\u00fcnde is located in the Uckermarck region, roughly 80 km north of Berlin.","ref_answer":"No|Yes","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Angerm\u00fcnde","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Angerm\u00fcnde"}
{"question_ID":252,"question":"How far is Angerm\u00fcnde from Berlin?","context1":"Angerm\u00fcnde is a town in the district of Uckermark in the state of Brandenburg, Germany. It is about 43 miles (69 km) northeast of Berlin, the capital of Germany.","context2":"Angerm\u00fcnde is located in the Uckermarck region, roughly 80 km north of Berlin.","answer1":"43 miles (69 km)","answer2":"80 km","contradictType":"Explicit","samepassage":"Different","merged_context":"Angerm\u00fcnde is a town in the district of Uckermark in the state of Brandenburg, Germany. It is about 43 miles (69 km) northeast of Berlin, the capital of Germany.\nAngerm\u00fcnde is located in the Uckermarck region, roughly 80 km north of Berlin.","ref_answer":"43 miles (69 km)|80 km","WikipediaArticleTitle":"Angerm\u00fcnde","url":"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Angerm\u00fcnde"}
